<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: New York | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/new-york/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:33:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brooklyn Brewery - Brooklyn, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first I&rsquo;d heard about Brooklyn Brewery was from an article in a BYO issue. To be honest, I don&rsquo;t remember much from the article besides the fact they were an older brewery which I wanted to visit. I should probably go back and read that article. Anyway, since I was already in New York City it was a perfect opportunity for a visit. Let me tell you, I&rsquo;m glad that I did.</p>

<p>Brooklyn has a distinctly different feel than Manhattan island. When you emerge from the subway, you&rsquo;re immediately surrounded with by jobs, homes, and real people (not tourists). While I only experienced a few blocks of Brooklyn, it was enough to make an impression.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" alt="Factory Roots">
            <div class="caption"><small>The brewery's former life as a factory shows on the outside but the inside is 100% brewery.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" alt="Building">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/entrance.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Brewery Entrance">
        <div class="caption"><small>Standing guard just inside the main doors are four large fermentation vessels.</small></div>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Standing in the brewery entrance, to your right you&rsquo;ll catch a glimpse of the inner workings of the brewery. To your left is the tempting hubbub of the tap room. We went left.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Brooklyn Brewery</strong><br>
79 N 11th Street<br>
Brooklyn, New York 11249<br>
<a href="http://brooklynbrewery.com/">www.brooklynbrewery.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>10% off Merchandise &amp; Cases</li>
<li>1 Free Beer during Happy Hour &amp; Tours (Friday &amp; Saturday)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tap Room</h2>

<p>The tap room was the large generic room you would expect to see from a warehouse. While the room was filled with wooden tables and benches, finding an open seat was a challenge; the demand for this brewery has definitely outgrown its supply. Whenever a your ends, the line to the tokens to purchase tokens becomes a ten minute wait and the line for the beer becomes a fifteen to twenty minute wait. I would recommend grabbing two beers per person when you finally reach the bartenders. Speaking of bartenders, they all wear the Brooklyn Brewery shirts available for sale which is an excellent way to sneak a preview before you buy. Of course, I could not resist picking up another <a href="http://store.brooklynbrewery.com/brewhouse-t-shirt-180">shirt</a> for my collection.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/tap-room.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tap Room">
Even though the wait was long the beer was worth it. The ones we tried were a bit hoppy for The Wife which means they were right up my alley. The price of beer (five tokens for $20) is worth mentioning. One token will get you most beers with a few speciality beer costing two tokens. This is a killer price for any bar, let alone one in New York City which explains why the place was <em>packed</em> even on a Sunday.</p>

<h2>Tour</h2>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <p>The free tour starts in the main entryway with nowhere near enough seats for the large crowd gathered; no sign-up or reservations is required. We non-intentionally placed ourselves at the front of the tour, but unfortunately the tour consisted of a single room so it didn't make much of a difference. While the information given by the presenter was interesting and well delivered, I felt a bit disappointed at not seeing more of the brewery. Granted the room was quite large and packed with enough equipment to glimpse all aspects of the brewing process, it still felt like just a glimpse. That said, I do not regret going on the tour one bit or even a byte (hahaha, computer pun!) and I definitely recommend you do it at least once. Be sure to bring a beer with you on the tour though, as you'll be standing in one place for a while.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/presenter-bartender.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tour Guide">
    </div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The drink prices alone make the Brooklyn Brewery difficult to pass up; throw in the fact that the beer is <em>good</em> and it becomes a required stop. While there was music always playing it was not overly loud or obnoxious as you would find in most bars or clubs. I envy the group who snagged a large table early and brought a board game (Settlers of Catan I believe) for the evening. Others brought in pizza which is the encouraged food of choice for the tap room. Unfortunately I did not have a chance to try all the beers which means the I will definitely be returning to visit the Brooklyn Brewery the next time I&rsquo;m in New York City. Maybe I&rsquo;ll see you there next time.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" alt="Wall Logo">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" alt="Terminator">
            <div class="caption"><small>Under no circumstances should you visit this brewery if you are the future savior of mankind from intelligent killer robots.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" alt="Random Sword">
            <div class="caption"><small>Unfortunately, I did not witness any sword-fighting. Maybe next time?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" alt="Scorcher 1363">
            <div class="caption"><small>One of the beers on tap during our visit.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" alt="Log">
            <div class="caption"><small>Bonus points if you can figure out what they were brewing.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" alt="Grain Tubes">
            <div class="caption"><small>Those tubes carry grain, not liquids.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" alt="Chandelier">
            <div class="caption"><small>Did I mention this brewery was quite the classy establishment?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" alt="Casks">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" alt="Bottler">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SAVOR: An American Craft Beer & Food Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/savor-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/savor-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Held in Washington D.C. for the last five years, <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/">SAVOR</a> took place this year at the Altman Building and adjoining Metropolitan Pavilion in Manhattan, New York. Attendees enjoy a reception-style sampling of sweet and savoury appetizers and craft beers from over seventy small and independent craft breweries.</p>

<p>If I had to describe my SAVOR experience in one word it would be <em>overwhelming</em>. I say this in the best possible way but I was entirely unprepared for the event. Not that I did not plan ahead (I remembered to wear pants and everything!) and this wasn&rsquo;t the first beer/wine tasting events I had attended. Maybe it was just the product of a Midwesterner&rsquo;s first time in the Big Apple but this event was broad in a scope to a degree I had not imagined.</p>

<p>SAVOR offers the opportunity to participate in directed tasting salons featuring stars from the craft beer and food scene. Very few events offer the opportunity to have a one-on-one conversation with the rock stars of the craft beer world. My frantic Ticketmaster antics during the pre-sale managed to secure myself tickets to one of the salon&rsquo;s:</p>

<p><strong>Apocalypse Now and Again (and Again)</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>If the world were coming to end, what beer would you brew? In 2012, <a href="http://www.elysianbrewing.com">Elysian Brewing Company</a> answered that question with their 12 Beers of the Apocalypse series. While the world may not have come to an end, the Apocalypse series did, leaving behind a dozen unique beers, each brewed with unusual ingredients. Join Elysian founder Dick Cantwell as he shares samples of four beers from the series and talks about the trials and tribulations of the project.</p></blockquote>

<p>Only a small increase in the ticket price, the private tasting was money well spent. If the ticket price weren&rsquo;t so steep I would probably go both days just to have the opportunity to attend two salons. Read on for a look into our SAVOR experience.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>By the time we arrived to the event, the line had wrapped around the Altman Building twice. Some store owners were not pleased about us being there as we were so they erected a &ldquo;sturdy barricade&rdquo; to keep the unruly beer enthusiasts in check. During our wait I almost got a picture of Sam Calagione walking by but wasn&rsquo;t fast enough on the draw with the camera.</p>

<p>Each brewery had two beers for tasting, each paired with a small food dish. These dishes were not quite unique to each brewery so we started having repeats near the end of the night. However, the beers kept changing so we we&rsquo;re too concerned (that&rsquo;s why we were there after all) and any food was appreciated after missing dinner.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-1.jpg" alt="Line Outside">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-2.jpg" alt="Line Outside">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/barricade.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/barricade.jpg" alt="Sturdy Barricade">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/inside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/inside.jpg" alt="Just Inside the Entrance">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/floor-maps.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/floor-maps.jpg" alt="Floor Maps">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/linden-street.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/linden-street.jpg" alt="Linden Street Brewer">
            <div class="caption"><small>Linden Street Brewer</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Not all beer servers at the event were on the same playing field. Some were just hired help, there to serve the beer with no real knowledge of the beer or the brewery employing them. On the other hand, some servers intimately knew the beers they were serving and, more importantly, were passionate about them. There people were a real joy to talk to about the beers we were tasting and made the encounter with that brewery extra special.</p>

<p>If I had to choose one beer which stood out about the rest it was Biere de Tartine by Linden Street Brewery. Fermented with a trained sourdough yeast, this beer had a definitive bread taste and the result was amazing.</p>

<p>The highlight of the event for me was the tasting salon <em>Apocalypse Now and Again (and Again)</em>. The experience was a wonderfully intimate telling of Dick Cantwell&rsquo;s journey through Elysian Brewing&rsquo;s Twelve Beers of the Apocalypse project and what it means to use speciality ingredients on a commercial level. We were able to taste a few of the beer from that project with added commentary from the brewer. I can still taste the chocolate chili beer as I write this. Rather than attempt to summarize the experience in a watered-down paragraph, I recommend you instead listen to the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.ApocalypseNowAgainAgain.mp3">actual thing</a>. Bonus: At the 48 minute 13 second mark, I&rsquo;m the one who &ldquo;stumps&rdquo; Dick Cantwell with a question.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/dick-cantwell.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/dick-cantwell.jpg" alt="Dick Cantwell">
            <div class="caption"><small>Elysian's Dick Cantwell</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-1.jpg" alt="Elysian Front">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-2.jpg" alt="Elysian Back">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/salon.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/salon.jpg" alt="Salon">
            <div class="caption"><small>Salon</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Three hours had gone by before we knew it and sadly it was time to leave. On the way each person received a bottle of the New York Limited collaboration beer from Brooklyn, Ommegang and Saranac. I&rsquo;ll post tasting notes after I get back and settled in.</p>

<p>Things to be aware of at future events:</p>

<ul>
<li>Make Time for Dinner &ndash; There was construction on our direct subway line so we didn&rsquo;t have time to eat dinner. Even though the beer had food pairings, not eating was rough, especially toward the end of the night.</li>
<li>Have a Game Plan &ndash; Even if you do not attend a Salon, there is no way to taste all of the beers available in only three hours. Look over the list of attending breweries beforehand and prioritize which ones you would like to see. Be aware there can be a line at some of the sponsoring breweries.</li>
</ul>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle-devil-horns.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle-devil-horns.jpg" alt="Devil Horns">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle.jpg" alt="Supporters Circle">
            <div class="caption"><small>Supporter's Circle</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/boulevard.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/boulevard.jpg" alt="Boulevard Booth">
            <div class="caption"><small>Boulevard's Booth</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
