<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hops | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/hops/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-19T17:34:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glacier Hops]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/12/22/glacier-hops/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/12/22/glacier-hops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I purchased Glacier hop pellets in bulk for the significant cost difference. I vacuum-sealed them into 1.0/1.5/2.0 oz portions, which I&rsquo;ve done before with Centennial and Cascade hops with good results. Not being familiar with the Glacier variety and wanting to clear up some freezer space, I used them in my IPA test recipe:</p>

<ul>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>7.0 lb Pale LME</li>
<li>1.0 lb Maris Otter Malt</li>
<li>1.0 lb Crystal 20</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>90 min: 0.5 oz (enough to hit 35 IBU)</li>
<li>30 min: 1.5 oz</li>
<li>00 min: 2.0 oz</li>
<li>Dry: 2.0 oz</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: US-05 @ 67F</li>
</ul>


<p>While the bitterness was as expected, the hop flavor and aroma were anything but; the reaction from everyone, myself included, when tasting the beer was &ldquo;That&rsquo;s not what I expected.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Aroma tingles the nose, almost like mint, and is not as potent as expected with the amount of dry hopping. Flavor is a cool, clean citrus but subdued to the point you would not know it was dry hopped and far less than the aroma implies. A very clean bitterness; right on the money.</p>

<p>The beer does not taste bad (The Wife rather likes subdued hop flavors), just unexpected from this level of hopping. The aroma is almost entirely disconnected from the amount of hop flavors present. The end result is an IPA unlike anything I&rsquo;ve tasted prior. Definitely something to keep in mind the next time I use Glacier hops.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
