<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: California Cider Company | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/california-cider-company/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:40:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r3/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After visiting four cities and eleven liquor stores, the area appears to be tapped out of pumpkin beers. I even had to cheat a little just to find enough to fill out this round so you&rsquo;ll have to forgive me for taking some liberties with the definition of &ldquo;pumpkin beer.&rdquo;
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/10/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-3.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 3 Beers">
The final four contenders see if they have what it takes to make it into the coveted Final Round. Which brewery&rsquo;s Fall creation will emerge from Round 3 victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.shipyard.com/images/pspumpkinlyte.jpg">Shipyard &ndash; Smashed Pumpkin</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Smashed Pumpkin is a big-bodied beer with a light coppery orange color and pleasing aromas of pumpkin and nutmeg. The Pale Ale, Wheat and Light Munich malts combine with the natural tannin in pumpkin and the delicate spiciness of hops to balance the sweetness of fruit.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 1.088 Plato</li>
<li>Malts: Pale Ale, Wheat, Light Munich</li>
<li>Hops: Willamette, Hallertau</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-Fermenting English</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild cinnamon and sweet malt nose. Dominant cinnamon and floral flavors. Sweetness of alcohol balances with the vegetal pumpkin flavors. Pleasant bitterness compliments the sweetness without being overwhelming. This double version of their Pumpkinhead tastes far better than the regular version but doesn&rsquo;t grow on me as I drink it which knocked it down to a six.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Pumpkin allspice nose. Slight bitter front-end and dry finish without a lingering flavor in the mouth. Allspice spice for bittering and cinnamon vegetal flavor.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/fat-jack">Samuel Adams &ndash; Fat Jack</a></h3>

<p><em><small>This rich and luscious brew indulges in flavor with over 28 lbs. of pumpkin per barrel, for a full bodied sweetness and deep russet color.  Classic pumpkin pie spices like cinnamon, nutmeg, and allspice ignite a warmth and spark that&rsquo;s deepened by an undercurrent of roasty smoked malts.  The result is a delectable brew full of enveloping layers of flavor and spice.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 8.5% ABV</li>
<li>SRM: 25 (Rich copper)</li>
<li>IBU: 25</li>
<li>Hops: East Kent Goldings, Fuggles</li>
<li>Malts: Samuel Adams two-row pale malt blend, rye, Special B, smoked malt</li>
<li>Yeast: Samuel Adams ale yeast</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Real pumpkin, cinnamon, ginger, nutmeg, allspice</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Medium malt nose with a touch of roasty notes. Pumpkin and malt flavors dominant; not spice heavy at all. Basically a double version of their standard pumpkin ale. Bitter front-end vegetal pumpkin which lingers but pleasantly fades away; a bit more sweetness may have balanced this out. Very complex and grew on me as I drank it until it became my favorite beer of the round.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft nose with a slight spiced smell of nutmeg. Good pumpkin flavor. Smooth maltiness with a bitter aftertaste. Vegetal flavors with smooth, complex spice taste.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.bridgeportbrew.com/drink/witch-hunt">BridgePort &ndash; Witch Hunt</a></h3>

<p><em><small>A spiced harvest ale with a rich caramel color, unique dry hop character and subtle hints of cinnamon and nutmeg.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 15.8 Plato</li>
<li>ABV: 5.8%</li>
<li>IBU: 40</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 1 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild malt and nutmeg nose. Overbearing nutmeg front and lingering bitterness which coats the tongue like a sawdust film. The harsh spices are like sawing logs in the Siberia wilderness. I did not drink any more of this beer than I had to.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 1 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft nutmeg and allspice nose. Too much spice flavor. Bitter front-end and dry bitter finish.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.acecider.com/about/ace-ciders/ace-pumpkin-cider/">California Cider Company &ndash; Ace Pumpkin Cider</a></h3>

<p><em><small>We first made this cider three years ago in 2010. We add cinnamon, cloves and allspice to fermented apple juice to produce a 5% cider which tastes like pumpkin pie. It is orange in color with a full rich taste that makes you want more. We carbonate the cider, cold-filter it four times before we bottle and keg it. This cider is released after Labor Day and is ideal for Halloween through Thanksgiving; although some customers think we should make it year round. It is the first Pumpkin cider to be made out West.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet apple cider nose which reminds me of cinnamon apples. Dominant cinnamon taste with apple sweetness and maybe a touch of nutmeg. This beer is like drinking a dessert. Simple flavor with little complexity. The balance is heavy on the sweet side; a dry version would be amazing.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet cider nose with apple allspice aroma. Smooth allspice flavor but minimal pumpkin flavor. Sweet up front with a lingering sweet mouthfeel. Yummy! Dessert in my mouth!</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">7</div> California Cider Company &ndash; Ace Pumpkin Cider</li>
<li><div class="badge">6.5</div> Samuel Adams &ndash; Fat Jack</li>
<li><div class="badge">6</div> Shipyard &ndash; Smashed Pumpkin</li>
<li><div class="badge">1</div> BridgePort &ndash; Witch Hunt</li>
</ol>


<p>In Case you Missed it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/">Round 1</a></li>
<li><a href="/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2/">Round 2</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
