<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:33:55-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confluence Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/good-things.jpg" width="300" title="Where Good Things Come Together" alt="Local Art">
My schedule was terrible for my trip through Des Moines this year and the decision to visit Confluence was based more off their late tap room hours than anything else. Spoiler: It wasn&rsquo;t a bad decision.</p>

<p>Late in the evening we were driving through what appeared to be an industrial district filled with dark warehouses and wondering if our GPS was purposefully leading us to our doom. Just as we had given up hope, we round the bend and were greeted with the warm and bright Confluence store front. It was cold, late and being desperately in need of a beer we hustled inside.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Confluence Brewing Company</strong><br>
1235 Thomas Beck Rd., Suite A<br>
Des Moines, IA 50315<br>
<a href="http://confluencebrewing.com/">www.confluencebrewing.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Member Deals</h3>

<ul>
<li>$0.50 Off on Regular Pints</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> I am loath to post such a short write-up on this brewery&rsquo;s beers because they deserve better but I enjoyed the brewery so much I had the share the experience regardless. You&rsquo;ve been warned: these tasting notes are sub-standard.</p>

<h3>Des Moines IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>Mix of medium body, lighter color and plenty of malt flavor to balance the massive hop impact. Citrusy and piney hops from the Pacific Northwest offset the robust malt flavor of the two-row barley and medium crystal malts.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>75 IBU</li>
<li>7.1% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>High bitterness which does not linger and tastes of Centennial. The Wife: more hop smell than flavor; do not like.</p>

<h3>Capital Gold Golden Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Brewed with time-honored German brewing methods, its slightly sweet, bready, malty flavor is balanced perfectly by traditional German noble hops with medium-low hop bitterness. Domestic and imported German two-row barley malt and noble German hops as well as traditional lager yeast. Undergoes a lagering period of three to four weeks after initial fermentation.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>4.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Grainy nose but standard lager taste. The Wife: clean, light flavor reminiscent of most light beers.</p>

<h3>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>A refreshing, blonde ale, it features a base of two row American barley malt along with a large portion of wheat malt, a small dose of rye malt and un-malted oats, corn and wheat. Lightly hopped with English East Kent Goldings hops chosen for their subtle, earthy qualities and finished with Czech Saaz hops for their sweet, floral essence to create a beer that&rsquo;s light in body and color, with a velvety texture and an aroma as sweet as a freshly cut field of hay.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>21 IBU</li>
<li>5.6%</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite the complex grain flavor; there is a lot going on in this beer. The Wife: very interesting, complex light flavor.</p>

<h3>Thomas Beck Black IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>The dark color comes from black wheat, which is combined with two-row base malt and a good portion of caramel malt and some flaked rye to add a subtle dry, spiciness. We used a special blend of hops, including Nelson Sauvin from Australia, to give it a unique flavor and aroma profile completely distinct from its India Pale Ale cousin, Des Moines IPA.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>58 IBU</li>
<li>6.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Lots of citrus on top of roasted malt flavors. The Wife: burned, bitter flavor.</p>

<h3>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Features a massive bill of English Golden Promise, a little Special B and roasted barley for color to condense and create caramelized sugars that will survive the fermentation process. Adding English East Kent Golding balances the sweetness and cool fermenting with Scottish ale yeast.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>6.6% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>One of the more subtle Scotch Ales I&rsquo;ve tasted. A The Wife: smooth malty finish; very good.</p>

<h3>ChewBocka Winter Bock</h3>

<p><em><small>Made with plenty of Munich malt for a rich, chewy, full-body flavor as well as German Spalter Select, German Tettnanger and American Mt. Hood hops to balance out the malty sweetness. There are also some toasty notes as well as a slight hint of chocolate.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>28 IBU</li>
<li>6.2%</li>
</ul>


<p>Some fruity esters liven up this Bock. The Wife: &ldquo;oaty&rdquo; (I think she made this word up) flavor with a dry finish.</p>

<h3>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Lighter, crisper beer that still has some hop bite to it. Pilsen, Vienna and Caramel 10L malts create a lightly sweet malt profile that is beautifully balanced with Amarillo and Crystal hops.  The light citrus and subtle grass flavors from the hops remind us of the eagerly awaited spring.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>31 IBU</li>
<li>4.86% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Light, clean, and hoppy. I could drink gallons of this beer in the summer. The Wife: hoppy light beer; do not like.</p>

<h3>Wee Lassie Scottish Session Ale</h3>

<ul>
<li>25 IBU</li>
<li>4.8%</li>
</ul>


<p>Very light bodied. The Wife: smooth light ale flavor with a nice finish.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<p>While I quite enjoyed both IPAs offered, the ChewBocka Winter Bock and Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale beat them out but only because they were a bit more unique and stood out among the crowd.</p>

<ol>
<li>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</li>
<li>ChewBocka Winter Bock</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
<li>Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Luke: Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
<li>The Wife: Thomas Beck Black IPA</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>This will be short and sweet, just like our visit to Confluence. Because we arrived so late, I didn&rsquo;t have the time I would have wanted to spend. Hell, my notes were whatever I could fit on the back of a flier for local music. The only conclusion I can make is we enjoyed what little time we had and 100% plan on stopping there again the next time we&rsquo;re in Des Moines.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" alt="Tap Room">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" alt="Tap Board">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" alt="Beer">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" alt="Art">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" alt="casks">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard - Chocolate Ale]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/07/boulevard-chocolate-ale/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/07/boulevard-chocolate-ale</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/chocolate-ale/table-inside.jpg" width="200" title="On the Bier Garden" alt="Picture of beer in glass inside with terribly lighting"> A collaboration between <a href="http://www.elbowchocolates.com/">Christopher Elbow</a> and Boulevard brewmaster Steven Pauwels, Chocolate Ale harmonizes the chocolate and malt, each supporting and enhancing, but not overwhelming, the other. Elbow recommended a rare variety of chocolate from the Dominican Republic, prized for its robust flavor and aroma. More than a mere flavoring, the crushed, roasted beans were incorporated into the brewing process itself.</p>

<p>Chocolate Ale is full of surprises, beginning with a glowing amber hue. The aroma is given over to earthy, fruity cocoa, with just a hint of hops. Smooth layers of dark chocolate intertwine with threads of caramel, vanilla, and nutty malt as the flavor warms and rounds to a bitter-sweet finish.</p>

<ul>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>Perle</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Pale Malt</li>
<li>Caracrystal Wheat</li>
<li>Simpsons Honey Naked Oats</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adjuncts:

<ul>
<li>Dextrose</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Cacao Nibs</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Color &ndash; 41 EBC / 21 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 24 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 20 Plato / 1.083 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 4 Plato / 1.016 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 9.1%</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.bjcp.org/2008styles/style23.php">Speciality Beer (23)</a>, base style unknown but my guess is a <a href="http://www.bjcp.org/2008styles/style10.php#1c">American Brown Ale (10C)</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Clear, dark amber color. Moderate, light tan head with decent retention from the wheat.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Fruit notes mixed with a rich cocoa, with just a hint of green/minty hop aroma. The character of the cacao nibs should be evident.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; High caramel, vanilla, and nutty malt flavors. Medium bitter finish from the chocolate. Slightly sweet from the caramel malts. Medium body finishing with some alcohol warmth. The distinctive flavor character associated from the cacao nibs should be noticeable.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Copper color with medium-high clarity. The head is an ivory with low retention, possibly from being on draft. The CO2 bubbles rising from the sides of the glass from the higher level makes the beer quite the looker.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Exactly how a chocolate ale should smell. The cocoa is the dominant aroma with sweet caramel malt coming in a distant second. Possibly some fruit mixed in there but the cocoa has beaten the other aromas into submission.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Heavy malt, with grainy, caramel, and cocoa dominating. Reminds me of the flavors of a Tootsie Roll but with a rich vanilla backbone. The cacao gives the beer a different sort of bitterness which doesn&rsquo;t linger.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; Dry finish which evaporates off the tongue. Light bodied and effervescent with lingering alcohol warmth.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Excellent (43 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (47 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 2 / 3</h4>

<p>The practically non-existent head cost the beer one point.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 2 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Low Size and Retention, Cream Color</li>
<li>Medium Clarity</li>
<li>Amber/Brown Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 8 / 12</h4>

<p>I did not experience any earthy or hop aromas which were not overpowered by the cacao. There was perhaps a touch of fruitiness, but I could have been making that up in my head it was so slight. While I quite enjoyed the aroma, I had to dock the beer for not being as described.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 11 / 12

<ul>
<li>High Sweetness</li>
<li>Caramel malt</li>
<li>Chocolate Cherries</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>I was sceptical of how the dominating cocoa would work out, but the taste is almost exactly what I expected.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 19 / 20

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Caramel Malt</li>
<li>Medium-High Sweetness, Medium-Low Bitterness</li>
<li>Medium Earthy Hops</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Berry and Chocolate flavors (chocolate covered cherries)</li>
<li>Just enough bitterness to cut the sweetness at the end</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 5 / 5</h4>

<p>The light body prevents the beer from feeling too heavy from the sweetness and chocolate flavors.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Low-Medium Warmth and Creaminess</li>
<li>Dry Finish</li>
<li>Smooth with slight tingle on the back end with the hop flavor</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>Chocolate is usually associated with sweet, which this beer is not. As someone who likes drier beers, this beer makes for the perfect dessert pour. I really want to try making ice cream with this beer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
<li>Yes please, chocolate dessert.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard - Rye-On-Rye]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/boulevard-rye-on-rye/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/boulevard-rye-on-rye</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/01/rye-on-rye/outside.jpg" width="300" title="Outside Facing North" alt="Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light"> Rye is an assertively flavorful grain more often associated with whiskey than with ales but has largely been eclipsed by corn and barley, the sources of bourbon and scotch. When Boulevard procured seasoned barrels from <a href="http://www.templetonrye.com">Templeton Rye</a>, they chose to brew a rich, tawny rye ale, then mellowed it in the warmth of charred oak rye whiskey casks. Two kinds of malted rye provide spicy sweetness, giving way to notes of caramelized wood and the citrusy tang of Citra and Ahtanum hops before easing into a dry, lingering finish.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info"><strong>Heads up!</strong> Despite what your bottle label may say, Boulevard Brewer Jeremy Danner has confirmed the hop schedule listed here is correct.</div>


<ul>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>Magnum &ndash; Bittering</li>
<li>Citra &ndash; Bittering/Flavor</li>
<li>Styrian Golding &ndash; Flavor/Aroma (in kettle)</li>
<li>Ahtanum &ndash; Flavor/Aroma (in whirlpool)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Pale Malt</li>
<li>Malted Rye</li>
<li>Munich</li>
<li>Cara 50</li>
<li>Crystal Rye</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adjuncts:

<ul>
<li>Dextrose</li>
<li>Brown Sugar</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Color &ndash; 44 EBC / 22 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 47 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 22.5 Plato / 1.094 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 2.8 Plato / 1.011 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 12%</li>
<li>CO2 &ndash; Bottles &ndash; 6.8 g/L</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>What first springs to mind for me is an imperial version of an <a href="http://www.bjcp.org/2008styles/style06.php#1d">American Rye Beer (6D)</a> but the color is far too dark to be true to the style, not to mention the oak aging. The extra bitterness should balance out the rich malts as long as the spice of the rye is not overpowering.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Dark amber more in line with a porter or stout and a nice solid head from the rye.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Oak, caramels, and maybe a touch of citrus or spicy notes.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Sweet caramels from the crystal malts and spiciness from the rye on the front. Warmth from the alcohol. Rich sweetness from the high OG balanced with the bitterness of the hops and rye. I&rsquo;m not sure how the citrus flavors of the hops will fit in but I&rsquo;m hoping they compliment the spiciness of the rye. Oak flavors always take me by surprise in their individual character so while I&rsquo;m expecting the oak flavors to be noticeable, I&rsquo;m not sure exactly how it will come through.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Beautiful amber, mostly clear with just a touch of turbidity. Average dark beige head which dissipates quickly.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Caramel and dark fruit notes with some rye spiciness pulling everything together. Brett sourness comes to mind, possibly from the combination of hops and barrel character.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Simple elegant flavors of rich caramel and a sourness/citrus of hops which I found extremely similar to Brett. Rye was mellow but in a good way. Pleasant warmth of alcohol complements the sweet bourbon twang from the barrels.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Excellent (44 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Excellent (44 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 2 / 3</h4>

<p>The low head retention cost the beer one point, but was otherwise spot on.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Smooth Texture, Medium Size, Medium-Low Retention, Cream Color</li>
<li>Low Clarity</li>
<li>Amber/Brown Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 10 / 12</h4>

<p>The caramels and rye spiciness were present, but the sour notes while pleasant, were definitely unexpected.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>High levels of Rich, Caramel, Roasty malt</li>
<li>Medium-Low Hops</li>
<li>Medium-High Sweetness</li>
<li>Slight Brett Smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>The complimentary flavors from the malts and the oak tie everything together. Even the citrus sourness which I was so sceptical about fit perfectly into the overall experience.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 18 / 20

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Hops</li>
<li>Citrusy Hops similar to the tang of Brett</li>
<li>Medium-High Rich, Caramel Malt</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Twang of brett or citrus hops</li>
<li>Sweet tingle at the front which mellows with a slight bittering of oak flavor at the end</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>A bit more carbonation than I would prefer in this style; rough on the mouth. However, I let mine breathe for a few minutes and by then it was perfect.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 4 / 5

<ul>
<li>Sweet Finish</li>
<li>Nice elevated amount of carbonation</li>
<li>Sweet beginning with smooth finish leaves mouth clean</li>
<li>Citrus tingling flavor once the drink is done</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>For a &ldquo;harsher&rdquo; rye beer, this is quite drinkable. The balance is spot on for what I enjoy drinking. The oak flavors, especially the bourbon, are great as the beer gets closer to 50F. However, I do not recommend drinking the beer about 55F because the balance goes totally off the wall.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 9 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Glacier Hops]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/12/22/glacier-hops/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/12/22/glacier-hops</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last year I purchased Glacier hop pellets in bulk for the significant cost difference. I vacuum-sealed them into 1.0/1.5/2.0 oz portions, which I&rsquo;ve done before with Centennial and Cascade hops with good results. Not being familiar with the Glacier variety and wanting to clear up some freezer space, I used them in my IPA test recipe:</p>

<ul>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>7.0 lb Pale LME</li>
<li>1.0 lb Maris Otter Malt</li>
<li>1.0 lb Crystal 20</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>90 min: 0.5 oz (enough to hit 35 IBU)</li>
<li>30 min: 1.5 oz</li>
<li>00 min: 2.0 oz</li>
<li>Dry: 2.0 oz</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: US-05 @ 67F</li>
</ul>


<p>While the bitterness was as expected, the hop flavor and aroma were anything but; the reaction from everyone, myself included, when tasting the beer was &ldquo;That&rsquo;s not what I expected.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Aroma tingles the nose, almost like mint, and is not as potent as expected with the amount of dry hopping. Flavor is a cool, clean citrus but subdued to the point you would not know it was dry hopped and far less than the aroma implies. A very clean bitterness; right on the money.</p>

<p>The beer does not taste bad (The Wife rather likes subdued hop flavors), just unexpected from this level of hopping. The aroma is almost entirely disconnected from the amount of hop flavors present. The end result is an IPA unlike anything I&rsquo;ve tasted prior. Definitely something to keep in mind the next time I use Glacier hops.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned Tasting 17 Different Pumpkin Beers]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/11/07/what-i-learned-tasting-17-different-pumpkin-beers/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/11/07/what-i-learned-tasting-17-different-pumpkin-beers</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/11/what-i-learned-tasting-pumpkin-beers/carnage.jpg" width="300"> I initially embarked on this journey in a effort to finally know, instead of guessing from year to year, which pumpkin beer I enjoyed the most. All I would need to do is taste a bunch of different pumpkin beers and see which I liked best. Easy, right? I was woefully unprepared for what lay ahead.</p>

<p>While conducting a beer tasting of this scale is not difficult, it is not entirely straightforward either. However, there are some things you can do to ensure a smooth, easy experience. Below are the five things I know now that I wish I had known at the start. Hopefully this will help someone learn from my mistakes and inspire you to conduct your own tasting experiments.</p>

<ol>
<li>Plan Ahead</li>
<li>Beware Palate Fatigue</li>
<li>Invite Everyone!</li>
<li>Define Ranking Criteria</li>
<li>Negative Feedback is Guaranteed</li>
</ol>


<p><span class="label label-primary">Bonus</span> 7 Pumpkin Beers You Should Try Next Year</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>1. Plan Ahead</h3>

<p>First, make a wish list of the beers you would like to try and then find out which ones you can purchase locally. Due to federal regulations, stores are at the mercy of their distributor when it comes to what they can stock. Just because a store orders a certain beer does not mean it will be delivered (I ran into this several times). Different distributors carry different beers so find a few favorite stores in as many different distribution areas as possible.</p>

<p>Second, buy your beers as soon as possible and have enough for all your tastings (perhaps some extras as well). Seasonal beers can be difficult to find and are often short-lived. I was unable to taste Lakefront&rsquo;s pumpkin beer in Round 4 because I did not buy it when I had the chance. Do not make the same mistake.</p>

<h3>2. Beware Palate Fatigue</h3>

<p>While especially important with strong spiced beers, how fatiguing the style you are tasting should affect how many beers you taste at a time. Five pumpkin beers in one sitting was a bit much while attempting to be objective. I would have reduced the number we tasted in a round to three, at most four, per tasting to achieve cleaner results. Now that you know how many beers you will have available and how many you can taste at a time, you can start planning your tastings accordingly. Putting it all together at the last minute week after week is exhausting.</p>

<h3>3. <a href="http://youtu.be/MrTsuvykUZk">Invite Everyone!</a></h3>

<p>From a statistical standpoint, the larger the sample size the more closer your results will reflect the population. While this is great, for me the true value of doing tastings with other people comes from the experience itself. I quite enjoy my food and beer and I am always excited to share it with others. A wider range of values also provides a better analysis of the beer and others can help identify flavors/smells you may have difficulty describing. I continue to be amazed at the differing experiences people have when tasting the same beer. I do not regret spending the time with The Wife, but I do wish I could have shared the experience with others. In the future, I will be inviting people to participate in all rounds of the showdown.</p>

<h3>4. Define Ranking Criteria</h3>

<p>To be perfectly honest, our rankings were terribly subjective. I did not fully realize this until I was called out on my rating of Blue Moon being higher than Schlafly. This was a surprise to me as Schlafly&rsquo;s Pumpkin Ale is in the top ten pumpkin beers on <a href="http://beeradvocate.com/beer/style/72">Beer Advocate</a>. So why had we rated Blue Moon higher? These beers were tasted at different times against different sets of beers. At first, I did not have an answer because we had never defined a rating criteria. After thinking about it a while, it turns out we had been rating beers based on how drinkable a beer was. In Schlafly&rsquo;s case, the richness of the pumpkin flavors lowered the rating.</p>

<p>Was this a good call? Probably not. Not having a defined tasting criteria leads to inconsistent rankings when tasting beers in sets at different times. Having a defined criteria will help explain why you ranked a beer as you did. This situation could have been avoided by having a consistent criteria which should lead to less subjective results. The injustice stuck with me so much that I chose Schlafly as our wild card beer for the finals. I am glad I did because Schlafly placed a solid second place in the showdown finals. Next time I will create a grading sheet ahead of time, most likely based off of the BJCP guidelines. <a href="http://obedientingredients.wordpress.com/2013/09/26/blind-pumpkin-beer-tasting/">Here is an example of a well-defined tasting.</a></p>

<h3>5. Negative Feedback is Guaranteed</h3>

<p>While I had lots of great feedback and recommendations from people who followed the showdown, I was surprised at the amount of negativity generated by the list of beers chosen. The torches and pitchforks came out over not including certain beers and the validity of the entire experiment questioned. For this reason I have created the following disclaimer which I will be adding to future showdown finals to help clear things up:</p>

<div class="alert alert-warning">
    <h4>Disclaimer</h4>
    <p>This list is not meant to be exhaustive or comprehensive. Limited by our distributor, these were all the beers available to me at the time of the tasting. If you do not see your favorite on the list, be assured I did not leave it off intentionally.</p>
    <p>Nor should this list be considered the definitive rating of these beers. Instead, my purpose is to inspire you to try something new or perhaps help you avoid beers you may not enjoy. If you do not agree with our opinions, great! Tell me <em>why</em> and what you prefer instead.  Or better yet, organize your own tasting and send me the results. I would love to have your perspective and I am always looking for new beers to try.</p>
</div>


<p>I don&rsquo;t expect all feedback to be sunshine and rainbows, but hopefully this will prevent any future misunderstandings in my process of selecting beers for the showdown.</p>

<h3>7 Pumpkin Beers You Should Try Next Year</h3>

<p>Along the way I had quite a few people recommend me their favorite pumpkin beers. Below I have compiled those recommendations in rough order of popularity (number of times mentioned).</p>

<ol>
<li>Southern Tier &ndash; Pumpking</li>
<li>Southern Tier &ndash; Warlock</li>
<li>Dogfish Head &ndash; Punkin Ale</li>
<li>Elysian &ndash; Great Pumpkin</li>
<li>Elysian &ndash; Night Owl</li>
<li>Stevens Point Brewery &ndash; Point Whole Hog Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>Crown Valley &ndash; Imperial Pumpkin Smash</li>
</ol>


<p>Honorable Mentions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Cigar City &ndash; Good Gourd Imperial Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>Elysian &ndash; Dark O&#8217; The Moon</li>
<li>Fat Heads &ndash; Spooky Tooth Imperial Pumpkin</li>
<li>Heavy Seas &ndash; The Greater Pumpkin</li>
<li>Horseheads &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>Ichabod &ndash; New Holland Brewery</li>
<li>Karbach &ndash; Krunkin Pumpkin</li>
<li>Long Trail &ndash; Imperial Pumpkin</li>
<li>St. Arnold &ndash; Pumpkinator</li>
<li>Traveler &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</li>
<li>Two Roads &ndash; Roadmary&rsquo;s Baby</li>
<li>Weyerbacher &ndash; Imperial Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>Williamsburg Alewerks &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: A Winner is Chosen]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/31/pumpkin-beer-showdown-finals/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/31/pumpkin-beer-showdown-finals</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/10/pumpkin-beer-showdown/finals-1.jpg" width="300"> At long last, the time to choose a winner is upon us. I gathered up our favorite beers from the last four rounds and took them to a Halloween party to perform a final tasting experiment: eight people, five beers, one winner.</p>

<p>The finalists were chosen from the top four ranked beers plus one wildcard we wanted to taste again compared to the others. Which pumpkin beer will I be drinking exclusively next Fall? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<table class="table table-striped">
    <tr>
        <th>Beer</th>
        <th>Rank</th>
        <th>Rating</th>
    </tr>
    <tr class="success">
        <td>O&#8217;Fallon - Pumpkin Beer</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>8.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr class="success">
        <td>Buffalo Bill&#8217;s - Pumpkin Ale</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>8.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr class="success">
        <td>Samuel Adams - Harvest Pumpkin Ale</td>
        <td>2</td>
        <td>7.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr class="success">
        <td>Blue Moon - Harvest Pumpkin Ale</td>
        <td>2</td>
        <td>7.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>California Cider Company - Ace Pumpkin Cider</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>7</td>
    </tr>
    <tr class="warning">
        <td>Schlafly - Pumpkin Ale</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>6.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Shock Top - Pumpkin Wheat</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>6.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Samuel Adams - Fat Jack</td>
        <td>2</td>
        <td>6.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Shipyard - Smashed Pumpkin</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>6</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Mother&#8217;s - Mr. Pumpkin</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>6</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Rogue Farms - Pumpkin Patch Ale</td>
        <td>1</td>
        <td>6</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Horny Goat - HornyCopia</td>
        <td>4</td>
        <td>5.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>New Belgium - Pumpkick</td>
        <td>5</td>
        <td>5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Woodchuck - Pumpkin Cider</td>
        <td>3</td>
        <td>4</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Shipyard - Pumpkinhead</td>
        <td>4</td>
        <td>3.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>Mendocino - Pumpkin Ale</td>
        <td>5</td>
        <td>2.5</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
        <td>BridgePort - Witch Hunt</td>
        <td>4</td>
        <td>1</td>
    </tr>

</table>




<!-- More -->


<h2>The Tasting</h2>

<p>Each participant was asked to rate each beer&rsquo;s Appearance, Smell, and Taste being either a Positive (<span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span>), Neutral, or Negative (<span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span>) experience. An option to describe the beer in ten words or less was also given. Some people (me!) had difficulty keeping within the ten word limit. After tasting all five beers, the participants were then asked to rank the beers from Best (1) to Worst (5).</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/harvest-pumpkin-ale">Samuel Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Taster</th>
<th align="center">Appearance</th>
<th align="center">Smell</th>
<th align="center">Taste</th>
<th align="center">Rank</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Catwoman</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mama Jen</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Miss Scarlet</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Colonel Mustard </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Host</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Librarian</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pirate</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bank Robber</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<h4>Comments</h4>

<ul>
<li>Catwoman

<ul>
<li>Good</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Mama Jen

<ul>
<li>Mellow but smooth</li>
<li>Good drinkable beer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Miss Scarlet

<ul>
<li>Sharp taste</li>
<li>Acetone/Vodka notes at end</li>
<li>Skunky smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Colonel Mustard

<ul>
<li>Heavy spice but smooth</li>
<li>Minimal beer flavor</li>
<li>Biscuity</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Librarian

<ul>
<li>Spicy</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pirate

<ul>
<li>Dark amber color</li>
<li>Soft spiced nose</li>
<li>Up front bitter quickly resolves to a burned taste</li>
<li>Pumpkin patch on fire</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bank Robber

<ul>
<li>Pumpkin theme stands out in the nose</li>
<li>Dry, complex, improves the more you drink</li>
<li>Deep amber not what I would expect from a pumpkin ale</li>
<li>Crisp fall day out at the pumpkin patch</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.ofallonbrewery.com/products/">O&#8217;Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</a></h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Taster</th>
<th align="center">Appearance</th>
<th align="center">Smell</th>
<th align="center">Taste</th>
<th align="center">Rank</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Catwoman</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mama Jen</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Miss Scarlet</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Colonel Mustard </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Host</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Librarian</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pirate</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bank Robber</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<h4>Comments</h4>

<ul>
<li>Catwoman

<ul>
<li>Just OK</li>
<li>Not chuggable</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Mama Jen

<ul>
<li>No spice</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Miss Scarlet

<ul>
<li>Savory pumpkin taste without spice</li>
<li>More &ldquo;Beer&rdquo; taste</li>
<li>Good but plain</li>
<li>Doesn&rsquo;t taste very pumpkiny</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Colonel Mustard

<ul>
<li>Biscuit, Roasty, Coffee</li>
<li>Mild pumpkin with caramel</li>
<li>Malt accent</li>
<li>Mild spice</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Librarian

<ul>
<li>Watery</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pirate

<ul>
<li>Light brown, cloudy</li>
<li>Soft sweet nose</li>
<li>Sweet pumpkin love</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bank Robber

<ul>
<li>Beautiful orange</li>
<li>Light body falls a bit flat</li>
<li>One-dimensional spices (cinnamon)</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.buffalobillsbrewery.com/">Buffalo Bill&rsquo;s &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Taster</th>
<th align="center">Appearance</th>
<th align="center">Smell</th>
<th align="center">Taste</th>
<th align="center">Rank</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Catwoman</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mama Jen</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Miss Scarlet </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"> ? </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Colonel Mustard </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Host</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Librarian</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pirate</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bank Robber</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<h4>Comments</h4>

<ul>
<li>Catwoman

<ul>
<li>Chuggable</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Miss Scarlet

<ul>
<li>Lager? Watery taste</li>
<li>Crisp finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Colonel Mustard

<ul>
<li>Skunky smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Librarian

<ul>
<li>Not impressive</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pirate

<ul>
<li>Light brown (cloudy)</li>
<li>Soft nose of spice and sweet</li>
<li>Light, watered down flavor</li>
<li>Tastes like a spiced pumpkin tea</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bank Robber

<ul>
<li>Unique taste</li>
<li>Sweet floral nose but not spice oriented</li>
<li>Too much floral/cinnamon to correctly balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://www.bluemoonbrewingcompany.com/ourbeers/product/harvest-pumpkin-ale">Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Taster</th>
<th align="center">Appearance</th>
<th align="center">Smell</th>
<th align="center">Taste</th>
<th align="center">Rank</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Catwoman</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mama Jen</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Miss Scarlet </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Colonel Mustard </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Host</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Librarian</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pirate</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bank Robber</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<h4>Comments</h4>

<ul>
<li>Catwoman

<ul>
<li>Good but wouldn&rsquo;t drink more than two</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Mama Jen

<ul>
<li>Nutmeg</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Miss Scarlet

<ul>
<li>Pumpkin mid palate</li>
<li>Bitter aftertase does not balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Colonel Mustard

<ul>
<li>Spicy pumpkin smell</li>
<li>Balance of spice and beer flavors</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pirate

<ul>
<li>Clear light brown</li>
<li>Sharp spice nose</li>
<li>Slight bitterness, good pumpkin flavor with light spice</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bank Robber

<ul>
<li>Crystal clear orange</li>
<li>Generic aroma</li>
<li>Technical ability shows in the taste balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3><a href="http://schlafly.com/beers/styles/pumpkin-ale/">Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>Taster</th>
<th align="center">Appearance</th>
<th align="center">Smell</th>
<th align="center">Taste</th>
<th align="center">Rank</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td>Catwoman</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">5</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Mama Jen</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Miss Scarlet </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Colonel Mustard </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Host</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">4</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Librarian</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">3</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Pirate</td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-down text-danger"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">2</span></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Bank Robber</td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"> </td>
<td align="center"><span class="glyphicon glyphicon-thumbs-up text-success"></span></td>
<td align="center"><span class="badge">1</span></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>


<h4>Comments</h4>

<ul>
<li>Catwoman

<ul>
<li>Eh</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Mama Jen

<ul>
<li>Tastes like pumpkin pie</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Miss Scarlet

<ul>
<li>Good spice taste</li>
<li>Semi-sweet wine taste</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Colonel Mustard

<ul>
<li>Yeasty, metallic smell</li>
<li>Heavy spice</li>
<li>More pumpkin flavor; no beer</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Librarian:

<ul>
<li>Very spicey</li>
<li>Too pumpkiny</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Pirate

<ul>
<li>Strong cinnamon nose</li>
<li>Pumpkin Pie</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Bank Robber

<ul>
<li>Deep amber loses out to some of the more vibrant oranges</li>
<li>Beautiful spice nose</li>
<li>Touch of bitter aftertaste lingers</li>
<li>Rich and sweet goodness</li>
<li>It&rsquo;s a freaking pie!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h2>Results</h2>

<p>Sam Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale proved to be the clear winner of the Pumpkin Beer Showdown. Determining the final ranking of the other beers proved to be a bit more difficult. First, for each beer the participants&#8217; rank (1-5) were added together and sorted in descending order to determine the Total Rank.</p>

<p><strong>Total Rank</strong></p>

<ol>
<li><span class="badge">19</span> Sam Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><span class="badge">22</span> Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><span class="badge">24</span> Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><span class="badge">25</span> O&#8217;Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</li>
<li><span class="badge">30</span> Buffalo Bill &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
</ol>


<p>Next, for each positive experience a beer would earn 1 points, for each negative experience a beer would earn -1, and for neutral each neutral experience a beer earned 0 points. The points were added together and sorted in ascending order to determine the Overall Experience.</p>

<p><strong>Overall Experience</strong></p>

<ol>
<li><span class="badge">9</span> Sam Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><span class="badge">8</span> Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><span class="badge">5</span> O&#8217;Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</li>
<li><span class="badge">4</span> Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><span class="badge">-2</span> Buffalo Bill &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
</ol>


<p>Only by averaging the placement of both the Total Rank and the Overall Experience was I able to determine the Final Ranking.</p>

<p><strong>Final Ranking</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Sam Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li>O&#8217;Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</li>
<li>Buffalo Bill &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r4/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s an Autumn miracle! Just when I had given up hope, these latecomers had shown up to join the showdown. Even after tasting over a dozen different pumpkin beers I&rsquo;m still excited to see how this batch turns out.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/10/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-4.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 4 Beers">
Which brewery&rsquo;s late-to-the-party beverage will emerge from Round 4 victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://rogue.com/beers/chatoe-pumpkin.php">Rogue Farms &ndash; Pumpkin Patch Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>The newest addition to the Chatoe Rogue series is Pumpkin Patch Ale, a beer made using fresh pumpkins grown in a patch that borders Rogue&rsquo;s 42 acre hop yard. The pumpkins are picked, loaded into Rogue&rsquo;s farm truck, driven immediately 77 miles to our brewery in Newport, quickly roasted, and pitched into the brew kettle to create a batch of Pumpkin Patch Ale.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>14 PLATO</li>
<li>25 Lovibond</li>
<li>75 AA</li>
<li>IBU: 25</li>
<li>Hops: Rogue Micro Hopyard Rebel Hops</li>
<li>Malts: Great Western 2-Row, Carawheat, Weyermann Carafe Malts</li>
<li>Yeast: Pacman Yeast</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Rogue Farms Pumpkins, Ginger, Cloves, Vanilla bean, Cinnamon, Cardamom, Nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild nutmeg aroma. Complex flavors of allspice and clove make this beer difficult to decipher but in a good way. However, there is a bit too much astringency on the back-end (maybe the orange peel?) which overstays its welcome. Unfortunately, the extra bitterness at the end kept this from being one of my favorites.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet pumpkin nose and a soft spice smell. Smooth malt front flowing easily into spice bitterness. Slight lingering flavor of cinnamon and cloves.</p>

<h3><a href="http://mothersbrewing.com/craft-beers/our-beers/mr-pumpkin/">Mother&rsquo;s &ndash; Mr. Pumpkin</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Our first release from Mother&rsquo;s Cupboard, Mr. Pumpkin is a medium bodied, copper color ale. With just the right blend of 2 Row, Caramel, and Crystal malts, pumpkin and spices, Mother&rsquo;s has created one yummy pint of love. Perfect after dinner in lieu of dessert, or for a night out on the town. Enjoy out doors on cool fall nights, or when slaving over the stove making that holiday dinner for the in-laws. If pie can be for breakfast, well it certainly should work as beer.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 5.0%</li>
<li>IBU: 10</li>
<li>Color: Copper colored medium to medium-light bodied</li>
<li>Malts: Pale ale, Crystal 35</li>
<li>Hops: Very little hops</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: touch of Roast pumpkin before addition for some carmelization and pie spice in kettle and post fermentation</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Good spice nose of ginger and allspice. Dry finish and pleasant amount of allspice/cinnamon/nutmeg which balances with the malts. Not quite enough body in this beer which lost it points for me.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Cinnamon and allspice nose. Lingering cinnamon front-end flavor with mild to modest front-end bitterness and only a small malt flavor.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.woodchuck.com/cider/private-reserves.html">Woodchuck &ndash; Pumpkin Cider</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Every once in a while you know you stumble upon something glorious. That something just so happens to be our Private Reserve Pumpkin. We have combined our signature taste with a refreshing pumpkin finish. Limited to just two and half hours on the production line this is a true connoisseur&rsquo;s cider.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 2 / 10</h4>

<p>Aroma is an icepick of sweetness straight into the sinuses. The combination of cider and spices tastes like cheap flavoured gum. Couldn&rsquo;t bring myself to take more than one drink so that&rsquo;s all the analysis I&rsquo;ll be providing.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Strong apple cider nose. Beautiful dark color. Bubble gum sweet, candy apple flavor with no bitterness. Not sure where the pumpkin flavor fits in.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">6</div> Rogue Farms &ndash; Pumpkin Patch Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">6</div> Mother&rsquo;s &ndash; Mr. Pumpkin</li>
<li><div class="badge">4</div> Woodchuck &ndash; Pumpkin Cider</li>
</ol>


<p>In Case you Missed it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/">Round 1</a></li>
<li><a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2/">Round 2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r3/">Round 3</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 3]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r3/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/07/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After visiting four cities and eleven liquor stores, the area appears to be tapped out of pumpkin beers. I even had to cheat a little just to find enough to fill out this round so you&rsquo;ll have to forgive me for taking some liberties with the definition of &ldquo;pumpkin beer.&rdquo;
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/10/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-3.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 3 Beers">
The final four contenders see if they have what it takes to make it into the coveted Final Round. Which brewery&rsquo;s Fall creation will emerge from Round 3 victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.shipyard.com/images/pspumpkinlyte.jpg">Shipyard &ndash; Smashed Pumpkin</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Smashed Pumpkin is a big-bodied beer with a light coppery orange color and pleasing aromas of pumpkin and nutmeg. The Pale Ale, Wheat and Light Munich malts combine with the natural tannin in pumpkin and the delicate spiciness of hops to balance the sweetness of fruit.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 1.088 Plato</li>
<li>Malts: Pale Ale, Wheat, Light Munich</li>
<li>Hops: Willamette, Hallertau</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-Fermenting English</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild cinnamon and sweet malt nose. Dominant cinnamon and floral flavors. Sweetness of alcohol balances with the vegetal pumpkin flavors. Pleasant bitterness compliments the sweetness without being overwhelming. This double version of their Pumpkinhead tastes far better than the regular version but doesn&rsquo;t grow on me as I drink it which knocked it down to a six.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Pumpkin allspice nose. Slight bitter front-end and dry finish without a lingering flavor in the mouth. Allspice spice for bittering and cinnamon vegetal flavor.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/fat-jack">Samuel Adams &ndash; Fat Jack</a></h3>

<p><em><small>This rich and luscious brew indulges in flavor with over 28 lbs. of pumpkin per barrel, for a full bodied sweetness and deep russet color.  Classic pumpkin pie spices like cinnamon, nutmeg, and allspice ignite a warmth and spark that&rsquo;s deepened by an undercurrent of roasty smoked malts.  The result is a delectable brew full of enveloping layers of flavor and spice.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 8.5% ABV</li>
<li>SRM: 25 (Rich copper)</li>
<li>IBU: 25</li>
<li>Hops: East Kent Goldings, Fuggles</li>
<li>Malts: Samuel Adams two-row pale malt blend, rye, Special B, smoked malt</li>
<li>Yeast: Samuel Adams ale yeast</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Real pumpkin, cinnamon, ginger, nutmeg, allspice</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Medium malt nose with a touch of roasty notes. Pumpkin and malt flavors dominant; not spice heavy at all. Basically a double version of their standard pumpkin ale. Bitter front-end vegetal pumpkin which lingers but pleasantly fades away; a bit more sweetness may have balanced this out. Very complex and grew on me as I drank it until it became my favorite beer of the round.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft nose with a slight spiced smell of nutmeg. Good pumpkin flavor. Smooth maltiness with a bitter aftertaste. Vegetal flavors with smooth, complex spice taste.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.bridgeportbrew.com/drink/witch-hunt">BridgePort &ndash; Witch Hunt</a></h3>

<p><em><small>A spiced harvest ale with a rich caramel color, unique dry hop character and subtle hints of cinnamon and nutmeg.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 15.8 Plato</li>
<li>ABV: 5.8%</li>
<li>IBU: 40</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 1 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild malt and nutmeg nose. Overbearing nutmeg front and lingering bitterness which coats the tongue like a sawdust film. The harsh spices are like sawing logs in the Siberia wilderness. I did not drink any more of this beer than I had to.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 1 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft nutmeg and allspice nose. Too much spice flavor. Bitter front-end and dry bitter finish.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.acecider.com/about/ace-ciders/ace-pumpkin-cider/">California Cider Company &ndash; Ace Pumpkin Cider</a></h3>

<p><em><small>We first made this cider three years ago in 2010. We add cinnamon, cloves and allspice to fermented apple juice to produce a 5% cider which tastes like pumpkin pie. It is orange in color with a full rich taste that makes you want more. We carbonate the cider, cold-filter it four times before we bottle and keg it. This cider is released after Labor Day and is ideal for Halloween through Thanksgiving; although some customers think we should make it year round. It is the first Pumpkin cider to be made out West.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet apple cider nose which reminds me of cinnamon apples. Dominant cinnamon taste with apple sweetness and maybe a touch of nutmeg. This beer is like drinking a dessert. Simple flavor with little complexity. The balance is heavy on the sweet side; a dry version would be amazing.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet cider nose with apple allspice aroma. Smooth allspice flavor but minimal pumpkin flavor. Sweet up front with a lingering sweet mouthfeel. Yummy! Dessert in my mouth!</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">7</div> California Cider Company &ndash; Ace Pumpkin Cider</li>
<li><div class="badge">6.5</div> Samuel Adams &ndash; Fat Jack</li>
<li><div class="badge">6</div> Shipyard &ndash; Smashed Pumpkin</li>
<li><div class="badge">1</div> BridgePort &ndash; Witch Hunt</li>
</ol>


<p>In Case you Missed it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/">Round 1</a></li>
<li><a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2/">Round 2</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My favorite season of the year is upon us. Cool weather, changing colors, allergies, festivals, and of course, seasonal beer. Perhaps the the most iconic Autumn style is the pumpkin beer. While pumpkin beers were produced in the early days of the American colonies, they were different from the pumpkin beers we know today. Colonists used pumpkin and squash as the fermenting medium, since malted barley was scarce. Once malt became more readily available, it replaced these alternatives to grain.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/09/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-2.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 2 Beers">
Five more pumpkin beers face off in this head-to-head challenge of seasonal carnage. Which brewery&rsquo;s Fall creation will from Round 2 emerge victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.shocktopbeer.com/s/index.php/our-beers/pumpkin-wheat/">Shock Top &ndash; Pumpkin Wheat</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Our Pumpkin Wheat seasonal offering combines the smooth taste of Shock Top with the flavors of Fall. We start with a traditional Belgian-style wheat ale and then brew with ripe pumpkins and a variety of autumnal spices, including nutmeg, cinnamon and cloves, for a refreshingly smooth beer that fully captures all the flavors of fall.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Dominant allspice nose and flavor. The use of wheat makes a nice complement to the spices at the expense of smoothness but still resulting in a balanced beer. Wheat replaces any pumpkin characteristics which I am not a big fan of so this beer loses a few points for going off-style.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft spiced nose. Bitter front-end taste with a clean finish which doesn&rsquo;t linger. Allspice but no pumpkin taste. Tastes more like a wheat beer than a pumpkin beer.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.shipyard.com/images/pumpkinlyte.jpg">Shipyard &ndash; Pumpkinhead</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Shipyard Pumpkinhead Ale is a crisp and refreshing wheat ale with delightful aromatics and subtle spiced flavor.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 1048</li>
<li>Color: Golden</li>
<li>Malts: 2-Row British Pale Ale, Malted Wheat, Light Munich</li>
<li>Hops: Hallertau, Willamette</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-Fermenting English</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: pumpkin, cinnamon, nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 5 / 10</h4>

<p>Floral allspice aroma. Pale and straw-colored, this beer is the lightest in color we&rsquo;ve tasted so far. Floral front-end, light body, but not much spice flavor. Perhaps a touch of cinnamon and honey contributeS to the floral nature of the beer. While good, it is not much of a pumpkin beer so it loses some points for going off-style.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 2 / 10</h4>

<p>Cinnamon spice sweet nose with maybe some brown sugar as well. Huge cinnamon flavor with a slight bit of cloves on the front-end. Slight pumpkin flavor in mouth at the end. Really just tastes like cinnamon water to me.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.mendobrew.com/collections/seasonal.html">Mendocino &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>To honor Fall we offer our deep mahogany hued Pumpkin Ale, bursting with a robust roasted malt flavor. To this melange we add copious amounts of pumpkin and embellish that further with nutmeg, cinnamon and ginger. This would have been ideal, but perfection is our preference and so we diligently add cocoa nibs as the beer conditions and intensifies the depth of flavor. This melds magnificently with the pumpkin and spice. And as a fitting finale we gently introduce hops to compliment this complex potion and the result is a finish that is clean and brilliant. At 5% alc./vol., this is a Pumpkin perfect session ale &ndash; Perfect for Fall and the approaching holiday season.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 3 / 10</h4>

<p>Dark amber in color with a very mild spice aroma. Mild nutmeg and allspice flavors are ruined by the unexpected harsh bitterness from the cocoa nibs. I have no idea what would posses someone to add these flavors to a pumpkin beer but the gamble did not pay off.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 2 / 10</h4>

<p>Bitter and burned nutmeg flavor lingers in the mouth. Dry finish with maybe some cinnamon flavors.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.bluemoonbrewingcompany.com/ourbeers/product/harvest-pumpkin-ale">Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>In 1995, we crafted our first autumn seasonal-Pumpkin Ale. At the time, Oktoberfest beers were in high demand. For our version, we wanted to create a beer that was a little different than what was already out there and complemented the season by highlighting the flavors we&rsquo;ve all grown to love during this time. It was so popular that it became the first nationally available pumpkin ale. Harvest Pumpkin Ale, as it&rsquo;s called now, is crafted with pumpkin and spices of cinnamon, nutmeg, cloves, and allspice for a taste you&rsquo;ll want to fall right into.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 15 Plato</li>
<li>ABV: 5.7%</li>
<li>IBU: 16</li>
<li>Malts: Munich, Caramel</li>
<li>Hops: Hallertau</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Pumpkin, Cinnamon, Nutmeg, Clove, Allspice</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild spice aroma. Dominant nutmeg flavors are balanced out with some allspice and vegetable flavors. Dry finish with some bitterness from the nutmeg. While the spices have a strong presence they are not overpowering creating a nice balance.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet nose with a nutmeg/allspice flavor and a nice pumpkin bitterness.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.buffalobillsbrewery.com/">Buffalo Bill&rsquo;s &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet pumpkin flesh nose and medium spice aroma. The spice takes a back seat and complements the good malt flavors. Light body with a dry finish, this beer is wonderfully balanced and easy to drink.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft pumpkin nose and a smooth allspice flavor. Has a nice subtle pumpkin flavor.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">8.5</div> Buffalo Bill&rsquo;s &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">7.5</div> Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">6.5</div> Shock Top &ndash; Pumpkin Wheat</li>
<li><div class="badge">3.5</div> Shipyard &ndash; Pumpkinhead</li>
<li><div class="badge">2.5</div> Mendocino &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
</ol>


<p>In Case you Missed it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/">Round 1</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My favorite season of the year is almost upon us. Cooler weather, changing colors, all the best holidays, and of course, seasonal beer. One of the most iconic Autumn styles is the pumpkin beer. While pumpkin beers were produced in the early days of the American colonies, they were different from the pumpkin beers we know today.  Colonists used pumpkin and squash as the fermenting medium, since malted barley was scarce.  Once malt became more readily available, it replaced these alternatives to grain. In the 1990&rsquo;s, American craft brewers reintroduced the style to the delight of pumpkin beer drinkers.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/09/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-1.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 1 Beers">
Five pumpkin beers face off in a head-to-head challenge of seasonal carnage. Which brewery&rsquo;s Fall creation will emerge victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.newbelgium.com/beer/detail.aspx?id=4a0076ef-aa43-44bb-a1ff-1a20d33245b6">New Belgium &ndash; Pumpkick</a></h3>

<p><em><small>What&rsquo;s that bite of tartness doing in a pumpkin beer? Adding the unexpected kick of cranberry juice to brighten this traditionally spiced seasonal ale. Pumpkick is brewed with plenty of pumpkin juice, cinnamon, nutmeg, and allspice, but it&rsquo;s the cranberries and touch of lemongrass that send your taste buds sailing.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 6.0%</li>
<li>Hops: Target</li>
<li>Malts: Pale, Munich, Caramel</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Pumpkin juice, Cinnamon, Nutmeg, Allspice, Cranberries, Lemongrass</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 5 / 10</h4>

<p>Bold spice nose of nutmeg, allspice, and clove which comes through with a medium intensity in the flavor. There is a touch of fruity esters in the background which I would except from New Belgium. The vegetable/fruit flavor of the pumpkin and the dry finish leaves a gritty coating of spices on my tongue. The blend of spices is great but the finish leaves a residue which ruins the balance of the beer.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 5 / 10</h4>

<p>Spiced nose, strong of allspice and nutmeg. Weak flavor, pumpkin lacking. Lots of spices in the flavor.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.hornygoatbrewing.com/wordpress/meet-the-craft-beers/">Horny Goat &ndash; HornyCopia</a></h3>

<p><em><small>We mash in pumpkins with two-row, Vienna and Caramel malts for a hearty ale with just the right amount of body. Spices added to the boil create a complex yet deliciously harmonious flavor. We used pumpkin and spice to yield a brew we proudly describe as &ldquo;Pumpkin Pie in a Bottle&rdquo;.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 6.3%</li>
<li>IBU: 23</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 4 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet malty nose and good nutmeg aroma which comes through mild yet dominant in the flavor on top of a solid malt base. Finish is light and airy, but the nutmeg bitterness lingers, compounding with each drink and ruining the beer for me after only a few drinks.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft, sweet nose with little spice smell. Smooth malt flavor, dry finish. Good pumpkin up front.</p>

<h3><a href="http://schlafly.com/beers/styles/pumpkin-ale/">Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Our Pumpkin Ale blends the spices of the harvest with full-bodied sweetness for a beer that tastes like pumpkin pie. Pounds of pumpkin form a malty foundation that supports the fall flavors of cinnamon, nutmeg and clove.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 18.5 Plato</li>
<li>ABV: 8.0%</li>
<li>IBU: 16</li>
<li>SRM: 27 (Copper-colored, bright)</li>
<li>Malts: Pale, Crystal, Munich, Wheat, Chocolate</li>
<li>Hops: Marynka (PL)</li>
<li>Yeast: American Ale</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: pumpkin squash and a blend of spices</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Allspice comes through in the nose and is the dominant spice in the flavor with a medium intensity. Darker malts, possibly crystal, sweeten this beer up and ends with a pleasant, medium dry finish. While the sweetness sets this beer apart from the others, the extra flavors makes this beer a bit heavier and not as easy to drink.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft nose of nutmeg and allspice. Too much nutmeg and not enough malt flavor. Bitter back-end. Too much spice, not enough everything else.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.ofallonbrewery.com/products/">O&#8217;Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Like pumpkin pie in a bottle&hellip;we add 136 pounds of real pumpkin to the three-barley mash and then season the finished beer with cinnamon, nutmeg and cloves.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 5.6%</li>
<li>IBU: 11</li>
<li>SRM 8.7</li>
<li>Malts: Pale, White Wheat, Caramel 90L</li>
<li>Hops: Cluster</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>A sweet cinnamon nose with a good balance between the spices and hop bitterness. The spice flavors did not dominate but instead complimented the malts well; very well balanced.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet nose of cinnamon and nutmeg. Sweet pumpkin flavor with very little pumpkin back-end or bitterness. Slight malt flavor. Good body.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/harvest-pumpkin-ale">Samuel Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Smooth, rich, and roasty with over 17 lbs. of real pumpkin &amp; warming spices like ginger, cinnamon &amp; nutmeg give this brew a smooth inviting character.  This style, first brewed by American colonists, is hearty and spicy making it perfect for the crisper days of fall.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 5.7%</li>
<li>IBU: 14</li>
<li>SRM: 33 (Dark reddish amber)</li>
<li>Malts: Samuel Adams two-row pale malt blend, Caramel 60, Special B, smoked malt</li>
<li>Hops: East Kent Goldings, Fuggles</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-fermenting Ale</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Real pumpkin, cinnamon, ginger, nutmeg, allspice</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>The aroma is nutty with a hint of nutmeg. Vegetal pumpkin taste come through with a nice spice seasoning. Smooth, clean finish indicative of a lager beer. This beer is how I imagine the original pumpkin beers may have tasted.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Spiced nose of allspice and nutmeg. Sweet spice and malty flavor. No real hop bitterness noted; any bitterness is from pumpkin flavors. Tastes like it smells.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">8.5</div> O&#8217;Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</li>
<li><div class="badge">7.5</div> Samuel Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">6.5</div> Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">5.5</div> Horny Goat &ndash; HornyCopia</li>
<li><div class="badge">5</div> New Belgium &ndash; Pumpkick</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard / Sierra Nevada - Terra Incognita]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/boulevard-sierra-nevada-terra-incognita/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/boulevard-sierra-nevada-terra-incognita</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/09/terra-incognita/outside.jpg" width="300" title="Outside Facing North" alt="Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light"> First brewed in 2012 for SAVOR attendees, <a href="http://terraincognitabeer.com/">Terra Incognita</a> is a collaboration between the Sierra Nevada and Boulevard breweries which was released commercially in 2013. Terra Incognita is a blend of three different aging processes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Terra Incognita aged in Templeton Rye barrels (30%)</li>
<li>Terra Incognita aged in a 2,000-gallon foudre (45%)</li>
<li>Fresh Terra Incognita dry-hopped with East Kent Golding (25%)</li>
</ul>


<p>This blending creates a beer aimed at showcasing some predominant oak characteristics with a subtle hint of earthy hops and which celebrates the unique terroir of the two brewery locations. Then just prior to bottling a dose of the wild yeast Brettanomyces is added and the beer is aged for over three months.</p>

<ul>
<li>Color &ndash; 92.5 EBC / 47 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 38.5 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 16.9 Plato / 1.069 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 2.10 (after BC) Plato / 1.008 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 8.5%</li>
<li>CO2 &ndash; Bottles &ndash; 6 g/L</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>I did not have much to work with so this is nothing but guesswork. The vital statistics match that of a stout (category 13) with the ABV making my best approximation as an imperial stout.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Dark in color, almost black with a rich head to match.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Mild earthy hop flavors mixed with some oak notes from the barrel aging.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Earthy and spicy flavors from the hops with an rich oak back-end balanced by the warmth of the alcohol. Because the Brettanomyces is added late in the process I don&rsquo;t expect it to be a dominant flavor but rather something subtle in the background.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Huge tan colored head which was rock-solid and seemed to last <em>forever</em>. Beer was deep copper with good clarity.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Strong earthy hop aroma with a touch of rye spiciness and lactic sourness.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The rye and oak flavors blend well on the front of the taste. Some sweetness balanced with a dry bittering on the finish.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; Medium carbonation despite the huge head (which annoying kept getting on my nose). Dry finish.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Very Good (33 / 50)</h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/09/terra-incognita/outside-closeup.jpg" width="350" title="Outside Facing North" alt="Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light"></p>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Excellent (37 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 2 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: High Size, High Retention, Frothy Texture, Tan Color</li>
<li>Brown/Black color</li>
<li>Lace</li>
<li>Too much head</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 10 / 12</h4>

<p>While the hops flavors were present in the aroma I was missing the oak notes.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Caramel, Roasty, Medium-High Malt</li>
<li>Earthy, Medium Hops</li>
<li>Low-Medium Sweetness</li>
<li>Bittersweet oak background smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 10 / 20</h4>

<p>Why is the hop gone? Strangely, despite the bold hop aroma little to none of the earthy hop flavors which dominated the aroma remain.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 17 / 20

<ul>
<li>Rich, Toasty, Roasty, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Earthy, Spicy, Medium Hops</li>
<li>Low Sweetness</li>
<li>Low Acidic Back-end</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>Unfortunately, the Hulk Hogan head got in the way of drinking this beer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Medium Warmth</li>
<li>Low Creaminess</li>
<li>Medium, Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>This beer would be nice to have once in a while but not on a regular basis. I would be more willing to drink one on a crisp Autumn day as opposed to a hot Summer afternoon. Even then I would probably only drink one glass.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 3 / 10

<ul>
<li>High Stylistic Accuracy</li>
<li>High Technical Merit</li>
<li>Low Intangibles</li>
<li>I would finish this sample</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of New York Limited - Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, Saranac Brewery]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/outside.jpg" width="300" title="Outside Facing North" alt="Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light"> Brewed and bottled at Brooklyn Brewery, Brookly, NY for SAVOR 2013 NYC this beer is a one-of-a-kind collaboration of Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, and Saranac Brewery. With a focus on local New York ingredients, these brewers combined matled barley, raw wheat, yeast, hops, spices, and ideas grown in New York State to bring you a unique take on wheat beer. This white lager, 100% re-fermented in this bottle, is a collaborative nod to the glorious past and brilliant future of New York State brewing. This special release was presented as an exit gift to SAVOR attendees in a 750 ml corked and caged bottle.</p>

<ul>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Coriander</li>
<li>Orange Peel</li>
<li>Lemon Verbena</li>
<li>Wildflower Honey</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Lager</li>
<li>ABV: 8.5%</li>
<li>IBU: 16.5 IBU</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Because this beer is unique, some research was involved in order to have any idea what to expect. My primary sources of information were the label on the bottle, the <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/news/savor-2013-collaboration-beer/">Media Spot</a>, and the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.SAVORCollaborationBeer.mp3">SAVOR 2013 Salon recording: SAVOR Collaboration Beer</a>. I also took into consideration the stylistic inspiration for this beer, the Witbier(16A).</p>

<ul>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Moderate sweetness with light, grainy, spicy wheat aromatics, often with a bit of tartness. Dominate coriander with a mix of complex herbal and floral aromas in the background. Moderate zesty, citrusy orangey fruitiness.</li>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Pale straw to light gold in color. Thick light-colored head with good retention from the wheat.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Pleasant sweetness with a honey character and a zesty, orange-citrusy fruitiness. The orange peel and lemon verbena should give this beer a different sort of bitterness alongside the low IBU value to help balance. The honey, coriander, and other herbs should give the beer a somewhat complex floral taste in the absence of a Belgian yeast strain. Coriander levels were higher than expected due to either 1) no masking esters or 2) less vigorous lager fermentation left more particulates to contribute to the flavor. Dry, with a low-amount of residual sugars and clean malt taste makes this beer smooth with the high alcohol levels going largely unnoticed. The use of a lager yeast puts the ingredients used to the main stage when it comes to flavor.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Golden straw colored with a touch of haze but otherwise clear. White, bubbly head can be quite tall and the retention is excellent considering its low density.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Coriander and orange dominates the aroma with a touch of floral notes. Spicy wheat characteristics are there if you&rsquo;re really looking for them. The CO2 tickles my nose.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; High carbonation levels makes for a bubbly but unexpectedly creamy texture. I had to pour this beer quickly because after opening the gas release caused the beer to escape the bottle much like a champagne.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Smooth and creamy while still light and refreshing. The orange bitterness lingers a bit on the tongue. Clean lager profile with a solid wheat backdrop for the spices. I think I was picking up on the honey flavors but without knowing the taste profiles of New York honey it is difficult to be certain.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Outstanding (45 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (46 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Smooth Texture, Medium-High Size, High Retention, White Color</li>
<li>Low Clarity</li>
<li>Yellow Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 9 / 12</h4>

<p>Any traces of sweetness or spicy wheat aromatics were masked by the coriander and other spices. Hopefully these will come through more once the beer has had some time to age.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Grainy, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Citrusy, Earthy, Spicy</li>
<li>Fruity</li>
<li>Soft nose with slight coriander smell</li>
<li>Smooth malt/wheat flavor balances with tingling spice aftertaste which lingers on tongue</li>
<li>Missing: Grainy, Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>The floral flavors were the only missing component here. I suspect the overly dominate coriander covered them up.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 19 / 20

<ul>
<li>Low Sweetness, Low Bitterness</li>
<li>Medium Hops, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Slight Toasty, Creamy Malt Flavors</li>
<li>Spicy, Citrusy, Herbal</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Missing: Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>The high level of carbonation was a bit much but the beer improved after several minutes of degassing.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Low Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 10 / 10</h4>

<p>A wonderful beer for drinking on a hot summer day (which we did), this easy to drink beer left me wishing I could have a keg of it every summer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 9 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/inside.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Picture of unopened bottle and SAVOR glasses"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Samuel Adams - Merry Mischief]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/07/07/samuel-adams-merry-mischief/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/07/07/samuel-adams-merry-mischief</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/07/merry-mischief/outside.jpg" width="300" title="Outside Facing North" alt="Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light"> This rich dark gingerbread stout entices with the aromas of the holidays.  The flavor of gingerbread comes alive, beginning with the smooth sweetness and heartiness of dark roasted malts and a touch of wheat.  But it&rsquo;s the intensity and spices of cinnamon, clove, nutmeg, &amp; ginger that add a wicked kick for a jolly playful brew full of merry mischief.</p>

<ul>
<li>Batch Number: 1</li>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>East Kent Goldings</li>
<li>Fuggles</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Samuel Adams two row pale malt blend</li>
<li>Wheat</li>
<li>Special B</li>
<li>Paul&rsquo;s Roasted Barley</li>
<li>Flaked Oats</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Cinnamon</li>
<li>Clove</li>
<li>Nutmeg</li>
<li>Ginger</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Samuel Adams ale yeast</li>
<li>Color: 200 SRM</li>
<li>ABV: 9.0%</li>
<li>IBUs: 25</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/merry-mischief">Brewer&rsquo;s Tasting Notes</a></h3>

<p>While no gingerbread went into this beer, the sweet roastiness with hints of cocoa and a slight nuttiness from the dark malts provide a similar comparison to gingerbread. A blend of nutmeg, cinnamon, cloves, and ginger were used to create a layer of complexity and lingering heat.</p>

<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Everything about this beer from description, the ingredients, the name, even the label screams Christmas/Winter Specialty Spiced Beer (21B) so I will use this style as a benchmark for my tasting. The inclusion of flaked oats and low IBUs has me guessing the base style is an Oatmeal Stout (13C).</p>

<ul>
<li>Aroma &ndash; A bold spice nose which will hopefully remind me of gingerbread cookies with the help of roasted grain aromas. I would guess the hops were used primarily for bittering and any hop aroma will be absent.</li>
<li>Appearance &ndash; If the reported IBU is correct, I would expect quite a dark, black beer impossible to see through with a thick, creamy, tan/brown-colored head.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The spices and higher alcohol content should contribute a warm, complex flavor set on top of a solid oats and roasted dark grain base balanced by a moderate bitterness from the hops.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Very black with a dark, tan head which was quite thick on the first poor. Opaque to the point of no visible light through the glass.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Clove and spices dominate the aroma, whether you&rsquo;re trying to smell the beer or not; no hop aroma.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The spices of the aroma come through first, followed by roasted grains and an alcohol warmth. Carbonation was a bit higher than I expected from a stout but works wells with the warmth of the alcohol.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Outstanding (41 / 45)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (42 / 45)</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): Excellent (34 / 45)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected it which deserves a perfect score. The reported SRM is more believable after you&rsquo;ve seen this beer first hand.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Dark Brown</li>
<li>Creamy Head</li>
<li>Defined Legs</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Black</li>
<li>Tan, Medium Head Size, Medium-Low Head Retention</li>
<li>Opaque</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 11 / 12</h4>

<p>Spices, particularly cloves, dominate the aroma and in my opinion overpower any grains that may have been present. Besides the lack of roasted grain notes this what I expected.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 11 / 12

<ul>
<li>Spiced Smell with Cookie Bread</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 9 / 12

<ul>
<li>Bready, Medium-High Malt</li>
<li>Piney</li>
<li>Spice</li>
<li>Smells Similar to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wassail">Wassail</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 18 / 20</h4>

<p>Spices, check. Alcohol warmth, check. Roasted grains, um&hellip;maybe. Just short of perfect, the overpowering spices have masked any significant grain flavors I hoped to find but not in a bad way, hence the high but not perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 18 / 20

<ul>
<li>Smooth</li>
<li>Creamy</li>
<li>Spiced</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 15 / 20

<ul>
<li>Toasty</li>
<li>Piney, Spicy</li>
<li>Banana</li>
<li>Spice</li>
<li>Malty Balance</li>
<li>Tastes Similar to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wassail">Wassail</a></li>
<li>For something with this much flavor, it should have been heavier</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>I would probably only drink one (large) glass of this beer in a night but oh man would I enjoy that one beer. It is important to note that there is a small window of opportunity in which this beer can be fully appreciated and July is not one of those times. However, this beer sets the bar for all Christmas beers to follow.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 10

<ul>
<li>Front-end acidic but balances with spices</li>
<li>I really like it; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 7 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would drink a pint of this beer, however I wouldn&rsquo;t fathom drinking this beer in a non-holiday context</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Unexpected Encounter]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/17/an-unexpected-encounter/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/17/an-unexpected-encounter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While this actually happened during our Brooklyn Brewery visit, the experience was so incredible it deserved its own post.</p>

<p>I had been wearing my Boulevard Brewery hat all over NYC without a second thought. The Wife and I were sitting at a table in the Brooklyn Brewery tap room enjoying our beer when I noticed the woman across from us looking at me oddly. Full disclosure, I often deserve being looked at oddly but this was not one of those times. Then to my surprise, this happened:</p>

<blockquote><p>Woman: &#8220;Boulevard Brewing, as in Kansas City?&#8221;<br/>Me: &#8220;Yes. We&#8217;re actually here visiting from Kansas City.&#8221;<br/>Woman: &#8220;My husband and I live in Lawrence, Kansas and are in New York to visit breweries.&#8221;<br/>Me: <em>Jaw Drops</em></p></blockquote>


<p>In one of the largest cities in the world, two couples who live within 50 miles of one another just happen to sit across from each other at the same table. Now that&rsquo;s the power of beer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brooklyn Brewery - Brooklyn, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first I&rsquo;d heard about Brooklyn Brewery was from an article in a BYO issue. To be honest, I don&rsquo;t remember much from the article besides the fact they were an older brewery which I wanted to visit. I should probably go back and read that article. Anyway, since I was already in New York City it was a perfect opportunity for a visit. Let me tell you, I&rsquo;m glad that I did.</p>

<p>Brooklyn has a distinctly different feel than Manhattan island. When you emerge from the subway, you&rsquo;re immediately surrounded with by jobs, homes, and real people (not tourists). While I only experienced a few blocks of Brooklyn, it was enough to make an impression.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" alt="Factory Roots">
            <div class="caption"><small>The brewery&#8217;s former life as a factory shows on the outside but the inside is 100% brewery.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" alt="Building">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/entrance.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Brewery Entrance">
        <div class="caption"><small>Standing guard just inside the main doors are four large fermentation vessels.</small></div>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Standing in the brewery entrance, to your right you&rsquo;ll catch a glimpse of the inner workings of the brewery. To your left is the tempting hubbub of the tap room. We went left.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Brooklyn Brewery</strong><br>
79 N 11th Street<br>
Brooklyn, New York 11249<br>
<a href="http://brooklynbrewery.com/">www.brooklynbrewery.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>10% off Merchandise &amp; Cases</li>
<li>1 Free Beer during Happy Hour &amp; Tours (Friday &amp; Saturday)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tap Room</h2>

<p>The tap room was the large generic room you would expect to see from a warehouse. While the room was filled with wooden tables and benches, finding an open seat was a challenge; the demand for this brewery has definitely outgrown its supply. Whenever a your ends, the line to the tokens to purchase tokens becomes a ten minute wait and the line for the beer becomes a fifteen to twenty minute wait. I would recommend grabbing two beers per person when you finally reach the bartenders. Speaking of bartenders, they all wear the Brooklyn Brewery shirts available for sale which is an excellent way to sneak a preview before you buy. Of course, I could not resist picking up another <a href="http://store.brooklynbrewery.com/brewhouse-t-shirt-180">shirt</a> for my collection.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/tap-room.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tap Room">
Even though the wait was long the beer was worth it. The ones we tried were a bit hoppy for The Wife which means they were right up my alley. The price of beer (five tokens for $20) is worth mentioning. One token will get you most beers with a few speciality beer costing two tokens. This is a killer price for any bar, let alone one in New York City which explains why the place was <em>packed</em> even on a Sunday.</p>

<h2>Tour</h2>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <p>The free tour starts in the main entryway with nowhere near enough seats for the large crowd gathered; no sign-up or reservations is required. We non-intentionally placed ourselves at the front of the tour, but unfortunately the tour consisted of a single room so it didn&#8217;t make much of a difference. While the information given by the presenter was interesting and well delivered, I felt a bit disappointed at not seeing more of the brewery. Granted the room was quite large and packed with enough equipment to glimpse all aspects of the brewing process, it still felt like just a glimpse. That said, I do not regret going on the tour one bit or even a byte (hahaha, computer pun!) and I definitely recommend you do it at least once. Be sure to bring a beer with you on the tour though, as you&#8217;ll be standing in one place for a while.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/presenter-bartender.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tour Guide">
    </div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The drink prices alone make the Brooklyn Brewery difficult to pass up; throw in the fact that the beer is <em>good</em> and it becomes a required stop. While there was music always playing it was not overly loud or obnoxious as you would find in most bars or clubs. I envy the group who snagged a large table early and brought a board game (Settlers of Catan I believe) for the evening. Others brought in pizza which is the encouraged food of choice for the tap room. Unfortunately I did not have a chance to try all the beers which means the I will definitely be returning to visit the Brooklyn Brewery the next time I&rsquo;m in New York City. Maybe I&rsquo;ll see you there next time.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" alt="Wall Logo">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" alt="Terminator">
            <div class="caption"><small>Under no circumstances should you visit this brewery if you are the future savior of mankind from intelligent killer robots.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" alt="Random Sword">
            <div class="caption"><small>Unfortunately, I did not witness any sword-fighting. Maybe next time?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" alt="Scorcher 1363">
            <div class="caption"><small>One of the beers on tap during our visit.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" alt="Log">
            <div class="caption"><small>Bonus points if you can figure out what they were brewing.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" alt="Grain Tubes">
            <div class="caption"><small>Those tubes carry grain, not liquids.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" alt="Chandelier">
            <div class="caption"><small>Did I mention this brewery was quite the classy establishment?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" alt="Casks">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" alt="Bottler">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SAVOR: An American Craft Beer & Food Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/savor-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/savor-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Held in Washington D.C. for the last five years, <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/">SAVOR</a> took place this year at the Altman Building and adjoining Metropolitan Pavilion in Manhattan, New York. Attendees enjoy a reception-style sampling of sweet and savoury appetizers and craft beers from over seventy small and independent craft breweries.</p>

<p>If I had to describe my SAVOR experience in one word it would be <em>overwhelming</em>. I say this in the best possible way but I was entirely unprepared for the event. Not that I did not plan ahead (I remembered to wear pants and everything!) and this wasn&rsquo;t the first beer/wine tasting events I had attended. Maybe it was just the product of a Midwesterner&rsquo;s first time in the Big Apple but this event was broad in a scope to a degree I had not imagined.</p>

<p>SAVOR offers the opportunity to participate in directed tasting salons featuring stars from the craft beer and food scene. Very few events offer the opportunity to have a one-on-one conversation with the rock stars of the craft beer world. My frantic Ticketmaster antics during the pre-sale managed to secure myself tickets to one of the salon&rsquo;s:</p>

<p><strong>Apocalypse Now and Again (and Again)</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>If the world were coming to end, what beer would you brew? In 2012, <a href="http://www.elysianbrewing.com">Elysian Brewing Company</a> answered that question with their 12 Beers of the Apocalypse series. While the world may not have come to an end, the Apocalypse series did, leaving behind a dozen unique beers, each brewed with unusual ingredients. Join Elysian founder Dick Cantwell as he shares samples of four beers from the series and talks about the trials and tribulations of the project.</p></blockquote>

<p>Only a small increase in the ticket price, the private tasting was money well spent. If the ticket price weren&rsquo;t so steep I would probably go both days just to have the opportunity to attend two salons. Read on for a look into our SAVOR experience.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>By the time we arrived to the event, the line had wrapped around the Altman Building twice. Some store owners were not pleased about us being there as we were so they erected a &ldquo;sturdy barricade&rdquo; to keep the unruly beer enthusiasts in check. During our wait I almost got a picture of Sam Calagione walking by but wasn&rsquo;t fast enough on the draw with the camera.</p>

<p>Each brewery had two beers for tasting, each paired with a small food dish. These dishes were not quite unique to each brewery so we started having repeats near the end of the night. However, the beers kept changing so we we&rsquo;re too concerned (that&rsquo;s why we were there after all) and any food was appreciated after missing dinner.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-1.jpg" alt="Line Outside">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-2.jpg" alt="Line Outside">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/barricade.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/barricade.jpg" alt="Sturdy Barricade">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/inside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/inside.jpg" alt="Just Inside the Entrance">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/floor-maps.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/floor-maps.jpg" alt="Floor Maps">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/linden-street.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/linden-street.jpg" alt="Linden Street Brewer">
            <div class="caption"><small>Linden Street Brewer</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Not all beer servers at the event were on the same playing field. Some were just hired help, there to serve the beer with no real knowledge of the beer or the brewery employing them. On the other hand, some servers intimately knew the beers they were serving and, more importantly, were passionate about them. There people were a real joy to talk to about the beers we were tasting and made the encounter with that brewery extra special.</p>

<p>If I had to choose one beer which stood out about the rest it was Biere de Tartine by Linden Street Brewery. Fermented with a trained sourdough yeast, this beer had a definitive bread taste and the result was amazing.</p>

<p>The highlight of the event for me was the tasting salon <em>Apocalypse Now and Again (and Again)</em>. The experience was a wonderfully intimate telling of Dick Cantwell&rsquo;s journey through Elysian Brewing&rsquo;s Twelve Beers of the Apocalypse project and what it means to use speciality ingredients on a commercial level. We were able to taste a few of the beer from that project with added commentary from the brewer. I can still taste the chocolate chili beer as I write this. Rather than attempt to summarize the experience in a watered-down paragraph, I recommend you instead listen to the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.ApocalypseNowAgainAgain.mp3">actual thing</a>. Bonus: At the 48 minute 13 second mark, I&rsquo;m the one who &ldquo;stumps&rdquo; Dick Cantwell with a question.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/dick-cantwell.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/dick-cantwell.jpg" alt="Dick Cantwell">
            <div class="caption"><small>Elysian&#8217;s Dick Cantwell</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-1.jpg" alt="Elysian Front">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-2.jpg" alt="Elysian Back">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/salon.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/salon.jpg" alt="Salon">
            <div class="caption"><small>Salon</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Three hours had gone by before we knew it and sadly it was time to leave. On the way each person received a bottle of the New York Limited collaboration beer from Brooklyn, Ommegang and Saranac. I&rsquo;ll post tasting notes after I get back and settled in.</p>

<p>Things to be aware of at future events:</p>

<ul>
<li>Make Time for Dinner &ndash; There was construction on our direct subway line so we didn&rsquo;t have time to eat dinner. Even though the beer had food pairings, not eating was rough, especially toward the end of the night.</li>
<li>Have a Game Plan &ndash; Even if you do not attend a Salon, there is no way to taste all of the beers available in only three hours. Look over the list of attending breweries beforehand and prioritize which ones you would like to see. Be aware there can be a line at some of the sponsoring breweries.</li>
</ul>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle-devil-horns.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle-devil-horns.jpg" alt="Devil Horns">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle.jpg" alt="Supporters Circle">
            <div class="caption"><small>Supporter&#8217;s Circle</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/boulevard.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/boulevard.jpg" alt="Boulevard Booth">
            <div class="caption"><small>Boulevard&#8217;s Booth</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release: BJCP Style Data]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/05/29/release-bjcp-style-data/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/05/29/release-bjcp-style-data</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I am launching the <a href="https://github.com/brewpuppy/bjcp-style-data">BJCP Style Data</a> repository, a collection of data files containing information from the official BJCP style guidelines. While the <a href="http://www.bjcp.org/stylecenter.php">BJCP website</a> contains a wealth of beer style information, none of the provided files are conducive to data processing. The goal of this project is to provide the official BJCP style guidelines in multiple data formats which can be easily used in software applications.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Release: BJCP Style Tree]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/05/19/release-bjcp-style-tree/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/05/19/release-bjcp-style-tree</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I am launching the Beer Kingdom, a group of visualizations to help us better understand the various beer styles. The first of these visualizations is the <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/beer-kingdom/bjcp-style-tree/">BJCP Style Tree</a>. Future visualizations will show the relationship between the different beer styles.</p>

<p>While I frequently find myself visiting the BJCP website for style information, I also frequently find myself wishing there was a better way to navigate the style data. The BJCP website is full of valuable information but the user interface is stuck in the 1990s. For this reason I have designed the BJCP Style Tree as a smoother, graphical way to access the style information. All the style information can be found here but in a way which takes advantage of today&rsquo;s web technology.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Samuel Adams - Tasman Red]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/04/21/samuel-adams-tasman-red/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/04/21/samuel-adams-tasman-red</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/samuel-adams-tasman-red/outside.jpg" width="300"> This wily red IPA gets its character from the Tasmanian hops that are full of grapefruit, pine, and earthy notes creating a bold flavor that threads throughout the taste.  The hops are balanced by a core of roasty malts that give this brew body and richness with hints of toffee.  This flavorful brew is rounded and smooth with a dry and citrusy hop finish.</p>

<ul>
<li>Batch Number: 1</li>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>Topaz</li>
<li>Galaxy</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Samuel Adams two-row pale malt blend</li>
<li>Special B</li>
<li>Caramel 60</li>
<li>Carafa III</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-fermenting Ale</li>
<li>Color: Rich garnet, 45 SRM</li>
<li>ABV: 6.5%</li>
<li>IBUs: 50</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<p>Brewer&rsquo;s Tasting Notes:</p>

<ul>
<li>While no grapefruit was used in this beer, the use of Topaz and Galaxy hops give this beer a bold hop character taste/aroma that can be compared to a grapefruit.</li>
<li>No caramel was used in this beer, though roasty caramel notes can be picked up through a blend of different malts.</li>
</ul>


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Jim Koch has a great <a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/tasman-red">tasting video</a> which I used to base my expectations. It&rsquo;s only a few minutes long but offers great insight into this particular beer.</p>

<blockquote><p>A big malt front to it and a big hop finish.</p><footer><strong>Jim Koch, Tasting Video</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/tasman-red'>Tasman Red</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>The use of IPA in the name immediately puts this in the style India Pale Ale. An ABV under 7.5% rules out 14C Imperial IPA. The special malts used in this beer push the SRM far above either the English IPA (14A) or American IPA (14B) styles. With all the malts in this beer it doesn&rsquo;t look like it will fit under any of the classic styles. If I had to pick one to judge it on though, it would be American IPA for the Aroma and Flavor described. I&rsquo;m a big fan of hops from Down Under (oh Nelson Sauvin, I want to go there) so I&rsquo;m excited these are the highlight of the beer.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Deep ruby red which really come across as a beer which takes malt seriously; the color should reflect this idea. Malt flavors are not joking matter folks.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; I&rsquo;m looking for the malts to make an appearance and not be overpowered by the hops. Specific smells I&rsquo;d like to see (smell?) are caramel and toffee as well as grapefruit and pine from the hops.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The flavor should be exactly what I smelled. sweet caramel toffee with some roasted notes balanced by lots of grapefruit and citrus along with spruce and pine for a resiny finish.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Deep red, a bit hazy. Pours beautifully with a full creamy head.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Definitely picking up on the citrus and pine of the hops but the malt was lost to me until the beer set for a few minutes, and only then did caramel flavors dominated the aroma.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Where the aroma failed, the taste certainly delivered. Roasty and caramel malt flavors which transitioned to the resinous hops which then transitioned into a grapefruit bitterness on the end. After the first few drinks when my palate was used to the bitterness the malt flavors really started to come and took a front seat.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Excellent (40 / 45)</h3>

<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/samuel-adams-tasman-red/inside.jpg" width="350" title="Inside Facing North" alt="Picture of beer in glass inside with northern light"></p>

<h4>Appearance: 2 / 3</h4>

<p>The color was exactly what I expected though the lack of clarity was a bit surprising coming from a professional such as Samuel Adams.</p>

<h4>Aroma: 10 / 12</h4>

<p>At first I was a bit disappointed with the aroma being hop-centric and out of the gate this beer smells like any other American IPA. However, when I smelled again after sitting a while, the malts were there for my enjoyment.</p>

<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>Two words: flavor delivers. This beer lives up to the promise of big malt front and a big hop finish; exactly what I expected. The caramel and resin flavors blend wonderfully. The lower IBU makes it very drinkable as only the malts linger on the palate. I would recommend this beer drank at a warmer temperature to fully appreciate the malt flavors. Maybe not as much grapefruit as what I was expecting so I docked it one point.</p>

<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>A complex beer which felt like a three-stage rocket to drink. This is something I would definitely buy again when I want a one-off IPA. I would recommend this beer to IPA drinkers who are looking for something different. I would <strong>not</strong> recommend this beer to Red Ale drinkers unless you&rsquo;re feeling particularly bold. While there are pleasant malt flavors the hops dominate this beer as any true IPA should and is nothing similar to the styles you may be used to drinking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi Received!]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/04/10/raspberry-pi-received/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-10T07:29:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/04/10/raspberry-pi-received</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finally received my Raspberry Pi Model B today and I must say it was an ordeal. After being on backorder for over a month, last week I began to see <a href="http://news.cnet.com/8301-1023_3-57577289-93/raspberry-pi-$25-model-sells-out-soon-after-u.s-debut/">news articles</a> discussing none other than Allied Electronics selling out of the Raspberry Pi in the United States. Surely if they had enough Raspberry Pis to sell to <em>new</em> customers there would enough inventory to fill backorders, right? So I emailed my account manager and was informed my order had not yet been filled. Huh, that&rsquo;s odd. Maybe they are just backed up with all the business and my order is about to be filled? Nope. I receive the same &ldquo;as soon as we get them in from the supplier but we don&rsquo;t know when that will be&rdquo; response to my query on a possible fill date. Meanwhile, over at <a href="http://www.newark.com/">Newark</a> I&rsquo;ve watched thousands of Raspberry Pis ship out each week.</p>

<p><img class="right" src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/logo.jpg" width="350"></p>

<p>Without any sort of time frame and another vendor able to ship today, I could no longer able to justify waiting and decided to cancel my order. Suddenly, upon request to have my order cancelled, I am told my order is being picked in the warehouse. Suspicious coincidence? Maybe, but I was willing to keep my order once I had seen the order was shipped. While I don&rsquo;t like to look a gift horse in the mouth, going forward I will be taking my business to Newark. I would like to point out that my account manager was very helpful, quick to respond to my queries, and spent quite a bit of time communicating with someone whose order was small. All of this despite being at the mercy of whoever was running the warehouse. Enough with that drama already; let&rsquo;s see what is in the box.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h4>Raspberry Pi Model B</h4>

<ul>
<li>512MB RAM</li>
<li>2 USB 2.0 sockets</li>
<li>10/100 BaseT Ethernet ports</li>
<li>Linux operating system</li>
<li>HDMI socket</li>
<li>SD card socket</li>
<li>3.5mm audio out socket</li>
<li>Raspberry Pi HD video camera connector</li>
<li>Size: 85.6 x 53.98 x 17mm</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/front.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Front of the Board">
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/back.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Back of the Board"></p>

<h4>Accessory Kit</h4>

<ul>
<li>4-port USB Hub</li>
<li>4GB SDCard</li>
<li>Enclosure</li>
<li>USB Power Adapter</li>
<li>Cable Micro USB Cable</li>
<li>6 foot HDMI cable</li>
</ul>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/kit.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/kit.jpg" alt="Accessory Kit">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/case-front.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/case-front.jpg" alt="Front of Case">
            <div class="caption"><small>Both front and back feature the &#928; symbol molded into the case.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/case-side.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/04/raspberry-pi-received/case-side.jpg" alt="Side of Case">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
