<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Racoon River Brewing Company | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/racoon-river-brewing-company/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:40:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raccoon River Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/raccoon-river-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T14:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/raccoon-river-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Raccoon River Brewery is located in downtown Des Moines, a bit difficult to find but that could have been the snow and just generally not knowing where I was in a new city. We also have a hard time not calling it <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raccoon_City">Raccoon City</a> Brewery which made for some interesting conversations.</p>

<p>A large upscale restaurant with a pub feel, Raccoon River has a second level which looks down onto the first. A two-story tower of brewing equipment becomes a centerpiece for both levels of the restaurant. The top level looks down on the bottom and has pool tables. We didn&rsquo;t see much else because we never went up. Next time I&rsquo;m make sure to get a real tour.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Raccoon River Brewing Co</strong><br>
200 10th St<br>
Des Moines, IA 50309-3609<br>
<a href="http://www.raccoonbrew.com/">www.raccoonbrew.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>Happy Hour Prices &ndash; Anytime.</li>
<li>Weekly Specials &ndash; Available Everyday.</li>
<li>Free Pool on Saturday&rsquo;s (11am-5pm).</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/raccoon-river-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" width="350"></p>

<h3>Tallgrass Light</h3>

<p><em><small>High-quality, lightest</small></em></p>

<p>Clear enough to see The Wife&rsquo;s face through. Light malty nose and what you&rsquo;d expect from a standard pilsner.</p>

<h3>Homestead Red</h3>

<p><em><small>A classic Red, rich and malty</small></em></p>

<p>Beautiful red color with a definite caramel nose and tastes of raisins. The bitterness was higher than I expected but balanced out nicely with the caramel malts.</p>

<h3>Bandit IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>Most assertive, highly hopped</small></em></p>

<p>Gold in color and full of hoppy aromatics. The bitterness is early and often which pairs well with the citrus hops used. This is not a beer I could drink all evening, but I would definitely have at least one before moving on to something else.</p>

<h3>Fatal Attraction (Seasonal)</h3>

<p><em><small>Strong golden Belgian ale, high gravity</small></em></p>

<p>Cloudy appearance with a sweet, crisp nose. The malty sweetness and the fruity esters of the yeast combine with effervescence mouth-feel which tingles on the tongue to make this beer quite the experience.</p>

<h3>MacCoy&rsquo;s Scotch Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Sweet, malty and complex dark ale, high gravity</small></em></p>

<p>Dark red in color, this beer has a dark, sweet raisin/chocolate taste which comes through in the nose. Caramel malts provided a balanced sweetness.</p>

<h3>Stonecutter Stout</h3>

<p><em><small>Big, dark and complex oatmeal stout</small></em></p>

<p>Black in color with a beautiful rich coffee nose (I want an air freshener that duplicates this smell). Light in body, this beer has a dark roasted front and a light bitter back.</p>

<h3>Stonecutter Imperial Stout</h3>

<p><em><small>Stonecutter Stout, times two</small></em></p>

<p>More subtle nose than the regular Stonecutter Stout. The extra alcohol overpowers other flavors which ruins the warming mouth-feel.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<ol>
<li>Fatal Attraction (Seasonal) &amp; MacCoy&rsquo;s Scotch Ale</li>
<li>Stonecutter Stout</li>
<li>Bandit IPA</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Fatal Attraction (Seasonal) &amp; MacCoy&rsquo;s Scotch Ale</li>
<li>Tallgrass Light</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Luke: Stonecutter Imperial Stout</li>
<li>The Wife: Stonecutter Imperial Stout</li>
</ul>


<div class="alert alert-info">
Two beers stood out from the others so much we could not decide which one we liked more so we just gave them both first place on our lists.
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The Wife and I both had burgers with sauteed vegetables. While the burgers were unique, they did not leave enough of an impression to remember what we had by the time we were home. I do remember they were good when we ate them though, so I wouldn&rsquo;t shy away from eating there in the future.</p>

<p>I may not be excited to eat here, but I will be excited about trying their beer and there are some excellent ones at Raccoon River. What is on tap changes regularly enough to always provide something new during your visit.</p>

<p>I will warn you if you visit in the early afternoon on a weekday, you may end up with a older waitress with a gruff demeanor. Do not be discouraged. If you can look past that and make conversation about the beer, she&rsquo;ll warm up to you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
