<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Wife | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/the-wife/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:38:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confluence Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/good-things.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Where Good Things Come Together&rdquo; &ldquo;Local Art&rdquo;" >
My schedule was terrible for my trip through Des Moines this year and the decision to visit Confluence was based more off their late tap room hours than anything else. Spoiler: It wasn&rsquo;t a bad decision.</p>

<p>Late in the evening we were driving through what appeared to be an industrial district filled with dark warehouses and wondering if our GPS was purposefully leading us to our doom. Just as we had given up hope, we round the bend and were greeted with the warm and bright Confluence store front. It was cold, late and being desperately in need of a beer we hustled inside.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Confluence Brewing Company</strong><br>
1235 Thomas Beck Rd., Suite A<br>
Des Moines, IA 50315<br>
<a href="http://confluencebrewing.com/">www.confluencebrewing.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Member Deals</h3>

<ul>
<li>$0.50 Off on Regular Pints</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> I am loath to post such a short write-up on this brewery&rsquo;s beers because they deserve better but I enjoyed the brewery so much I had the share the experience regardless. You&rsquo;ve been warned: these tasting notes are sub-standard.</p>

<h3>Des Moines IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>Mix of medium body, lighter color and plenty of malt flavor to balance the massive hop impact. Citrusy and piney hops from the Pacific Northwest offset the robust malt flavor of the two-row barley and medium crystal malts.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>75 IBU</li>
<li>7.1% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>High bitterness which does not linger and tastes of Centennial. The Wife: more hop smell than flavor; do not like.</p>

<h3>Capital Gold Golden Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Brewed with time-honored German brewing methods, its slightly sweet, bready, malty flavor is balanced perfectly by traditional German noble hops with medium-low hop bitterness. Domestic and imported German two-row barley malt and noble German hops as well as traditional lager yeast. Undergoes a lagering period of three to four weeks after initial fermentation.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>4.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Grainy nose but standard lager taste. The Wife: clean, light flavor reminiscent of most light beers.</p>

<h3>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>A refreshing, blonde ale, it features a base of two row American barley malt along with a large portion of wheat malt, a small dose of rye malt and un-malted oats, corn and wheat. Lightly hopped with English East Kent Goldings hops chosen for their subtle, earthy qualities and finished with Czech Saaz hops for their sweet, floral essence to create a beer that&rsquo;s light in body and color, with a velvety texture and an aroma as sweet as a freshly cut field of hay.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>21 IBU</li>
<li>5.6%</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite the complex grain flavor; there is a lot going on in this beer. The Wife: very interesting, complex light flavor.</p>

<h3>Thomas Beck Black IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>The dark color comes from black wheat, which is combined with two-row base malt and a good portion of caramel malt and some flaked rye to add a subtle dry, spiciness. We used a special blend of hops, including Nelson Sauvin from Australia, to give it a unique flavor and aroma profile completely distinct from its India Pale Ale cousin, Des Moines IPA.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>58 IBU</li>
<li>6.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Lots of citrus on top of roasted malt flavors. The Wife: burned, bitter flavor.</p>

<h3>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Features a massive bill of English Golden Promise, a little Special B and roasted barley for color to condense and create caramelized sugars that will survive the fermentation process. Adding English East Kent Golding balances the sweetness and cool fermenting with Scottish ale yeast.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>6.6% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>One of the more subtle Scotch Ales I&rsquo;ve tasted. A The Wife: smooth malty finish; very good.</p>

<h3>ChewBocka Winter Bock</h3>

<p><em><small>Made with plenty of Munich malt for a rich, chewy, full-body flavor as well as German Spalter Select, German Tettnanger and American Mt. Hood hops to balance out the malty sweetness. There are also some toasty notes as well as a slight hint of chocolate.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>28 IBU</li>
<li>6.2%</li>
</ul>


<p>Some fruity esters liven up this Bock. The Wife: &ldquo;oaty&rdquo; (I think she made this word up) flavor with a dry finish.</p>

<h3>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Lighter, crisper beer that still has some hop bite to it. Pilsen, Vienna and Caramel 10L malts create a lightly sweet malt profile that is beautifully balanced with Amarillo and Crystal hops.  The light citrus and subtle grass flavors from the hops remind us of the eagerly awaited spring.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>31 IBU</li>
<li>4.86% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Light, clean, and hoppy. I could drink gallons of this beer in the summer. The Wife: hoppy light beer; do not like.</p>

<h3>Wee Lassie Scottish Session Ale</h3>

<ul>
<li>25 IBU</li>
<li>4.8%</li>
</ul>


<p>Very light bodied. The Wife: smooth light ale flavor with a nice finish.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<p>While I quite enjoyed both IPAs offered, the ChewBocka Winter Bock and Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale beat them out but only because they were a bit more unique and stood out among the crowd.</p>

<ol>
<li>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</li>
<li>ChewBocka Winter Bock</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
<li>Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Luke: Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
<li>The Wife: Thomas Beck Black IPA</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>This will be short and sweet, just like our visit to Confluence. Because we arrived so late, I didn&rsquo;t have the time I would have wanted to spend. Hell, my notes were whatever I could fit on the back of a flier for local music. The only conclusion I can make is we enjoyed what little time we had and 100% plan on stopping there again the next time we&rsquo;re in Des Moines.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" alt="Tap Room">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" alt="Tap Board">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" alt="Beer">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" alt="Art">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" alt="casks">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard - Chocolate Ale]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/07/boulevard-chocolate-ale/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/07/boulevard-chocolate-ale</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2014/02/chocolate-ale/table-inside.jpg" width="200" title="&ldquo;On the Bier Garden&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of beer in glass inside with terribly lighting&rdquo;" > A collaboration between <a href="http://www.elbowchocolates.com/">Christopher Elbow</a> and Boulevard brewmaster Steven Pauwels, Chocolate Ale harmonizes the chocolate and malt, each supporting and enhancing, but not overwhelming, the other. Elbow recommended a rare variety of chocolate from the Dominican Republic, prized for its robust flavor and aroma. More than a mere flavoring, the crushed, roasted beans were incorporated into the brewing process itself.</p>

<p>Chocolate Ale is full of surprises, beginning with a glowing amber hue. The aroma is given over to earthy, fruity cocoa, with just a hint of hops. Smooth layers of dark chocolate intertwine with threads of caramel, vanilla, and nutty malt as the flavor warms and rounds to a bitter-sweet finish.</p>

<ul>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>Perle</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Pale Malt</li>
<li>Caracrystal Wheat</li>
<li>Simpsons Honey Naked Oats</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adjuncts:

<ul>
<li>Dextrose</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Cacao Nibs</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Color &ndash; 41 EBC / 21 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 24 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 20 Plato / 1.083 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 4 Plato / 1.016 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 9.1%</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p><a href="http://www.bjcp.org/2008styles/style23.php">Speciality Beer (23)</a>, base style unknown but my guess is a <a href="http://www.bjcp.org/2008styles/style10.php#1c">American Brown Ale (10C)</a>.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Clear, dark amber color. Moderate, light tan head with decent retention from the wheat.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Fruit notes mixed with a rich cocoa, with just a hint of green/minty hop aroma. The character of the cacao nibs should be evident.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; High caramel, vanilla, and nutty malt flavors. Medium bitter finish from the chocolate. Slightly sweet from the caramel malts. Medium body finishing with some alcohol warmth. The distinctive flavor character associated from the cacao nibs should be noticeable.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Copper color with medium-high clarity. The head is an ivory with low retention, possibly from being on draft. The CO2 bubbles rising from the sides of the glass from the higher level makes the beer quite the looker.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Exactly how a chocolate ale should smell. The cocoa is the dominant aroma with sweet caramel malt coming in a distant second. Possibly some fruit mixed in there but the cocoa has beaten the other aromas into submission.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Heavy malt, with grainy, caramel, and cocoa dominating. Reminds me of the flavors of a Tootsie Roll but with a rich vanilla backbone. The cacao gives the beer a different sort of bitterness which doesn&rsquo;t linger.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; Dry finish which evaporates off the tongue. Light bodied and effervescent with lingering alcohol warmth.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Excellent (43 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (47 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 2 / 3</h4>

<p>The practically non-existent head cost the beer one point.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 2 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Low Size and Retention, Cream Color</li>
<li>Medium Clarity</li>
<li>Amber/Brown Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 8 / 12</h4>

<p>I did not experience any earthy or hop aromas which were not overpowered by the cacao. There was perhaps a touch of fruitiness, but I could have been making that up in my head it was so slight. While I quite enjoyed the aroma, I had to dock the beer for not being as described.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 11 / 12

<ul>
<li>High Sweetness</li>
<li>Caramel malt</li>
<li>Chocolate Cherries</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>I was sceptical of how the dominating cocoa would work out, but the taste is almost exactly what I expected.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 19 / 20

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Caramel Malt</li>
<li>Medium-High Sweetness, Medium-Low Bitterness</li>
<li>Medium Earthy Hops</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Berry and Chocolate flavors (chocolate covered cherries)</li>
<li>Just enough bitterness to cut the sweetness at the end</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 5 / 5</h4>

<p>The light body prevents the beer from feeling too heavy from the sweetness and chocolate flavors.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Low-Medium Warmth and Creaminess</li>
<li>Dry Finish</li>
<li>Smooth with slight tingle on the back end with the hop flavor</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>Chocolate is usually associated with sweet, which this beer is not. As someone who likes drier beers, this beer makes for the perfect dessert pour. I really want to try making ice cream with this beer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
<li>Yes please, chocolate dessert.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard - Rye-On-Rye]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/boulevard-rye-on-rye/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/01/07/boulevard-rye-on-rye</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2014/01/rye-on-rye/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > Rye is an assertively flavorful grain more often associated with whiskey than with ales but has largely been eclipsed by corn and barley, the sources of bourbon and scotch. When Boulevard procured seasoned barrels from <a href="http://www.templetonrye.com">Templeton Rye</a>, they chose to brew a rich, tawny rye ale, then mellowed it in the warmth of charred oak rye whiskey casks. Two kinds of malted rye provide spicy sweetness, giving way to notes of caramelized wood and the citrusy tang of Citra and Ahtanum hops before easing into a dry, lingering finish.</p>

<div class="alert alert-info"><strong>Heads up!</strong> Despite what your bottle label may say, Boulevard Brewer Jeremy Danner has confirmed the hop schedule listed here is correct.</div>


<ul>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>Magnum &ndash; Bittering</li>
<li>Citra &ndash; Bittering/Flavor</li>
<li>Styrian Golding &ndash; Flavor/Aroma (in kettle)</li>
<li>Ahtanum &ndash; Flavor/Aroma (in whirlpool)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Pale Malt</li>
<li>Malted Rye</li>
<li>Munich</li>
<li>Cara 50</li>
<li>Crystal Rye</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adjuncts:

<ul>
<li>Dextrose</li>
<li>Brown Sugar</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Color &ndash; 44 EBC / 22 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 47 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 22.5 Plato / 1.094 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 2.8 Plato / 1.011 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 12%</li>
<li>CO2 &ndash; Bottles &ndash; 6.8 g/L</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>What first springs to mind for me is an imperial version of an <a href="http://www.bjcp.org/2008styles/style06.php#1d">American Rye Beer (6D)</a> but the color is far too dark to be true to the style, not to mention the oak aging. The extra bitterness should balance out the rich malts as long as the spice of the rye is not overpowering.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Dark amber more in line with a porter or stout and a nice solid head from the rye.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Oak, caramels, and maybe a touch of citrus or spicy notes.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Sweet caramels from the crystal malts and spiciness from the rye on the front. Warmth from the alcohol. Rich sweetness from the high OG balanced with the bitterness of the hops and rye. I&rsquo;m not sure how the citrus flavors of the hops will fit in but I&rsquo;m hoping they compliment the spiciness of the rye. Oak flavors always take me by surprise in their individual character so while I&rsquo;m expecting the oak flavors to be noticeable, I&rsquo;m not sure exactly how it will come through.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Beautiful amber, mostly clear with just a touch of turbidity. Average dark beige head which dissipates quickly.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Caramel and dark fruit notes with some rye spiciness pulling everything together. Brett sourness comes to mind, possibly from the combination of hops and barrel character.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Simple elegant flavors of rich caramel and a sourness/citrus of hops which I found extremely similar to Brett. Rye was mellow but in a good way. Pleasant warmth of alcohol complements the sweet bourbon twang from the barrels.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Excellent (44 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Excellent (44 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 2 / 3</h4>

<p>The low head retention cost the beer one point, but was otherwise spot on.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Smooth Texture, Medium Size, Medium-Low Retention, Cream Color</li>
<li>Low Clarity</li>
<li>Amber/Brown Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 10 / 12</h4>

<p>The caramels and rye spiciness were present, but the sour notes while pleasant, were definitely unexpected.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>High levels of Rich, Caramel, Roasty malt</li>
<li>Medium-Low Hops</li>
<li>Medium-High Sweetness</li>
<li>Slight Brett Smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>The complimentary flavors from the malts and the oak tie everything together. Even the citrus sourness which I was so sceptical about fit perfectly into the overall experience.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 18 / 20

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Hops</li>
<li>Citrusy Hops similar to the tang of Brett</li>
<li>Medium-High Rich, Caramel Malt</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Twang of brett or citrus hops</li>
<li>Sweet tingle at the front which mellows with a slight bittering of oak flavor at the end</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>A bit more carbonation than I would prefer in this style; rough on the mouth. However, I let mine breathe for a few minutes and by then it was perfect.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 4 / 5

<ul>
<li>Sweet Finish</li>
<li>Nice elevated amount of carbonation</li>
<li>Sweet beginning with smooth finish leaves mouth clean</li>
<li>Citrus tingling flavor once the drink is done</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>For a &ldquo;harsher&rdquo; rye beer, this is quite drinkable. The balance is spot on for what I enjoy drinking. The oak flavors, especially the bourbon, are great as the beer gets closer to 50F. However, I do not recommend drinking the beer about 55F because the balance goes totally off the wall.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 9 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard / Sierra Nevada - Terra Incognita]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/boulevard-sierra-nevada-terra-incognita/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/boulevard-sierra-nevada-terra-incognita</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/09/terra-incognita/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > First brewed in 2012 for SAVOR attendees, <a href="http://terraincognitabeer.com/">Terra Incognita</a> is a collaboration between the Sierra Nevada and Boulevard breweries which was released commercially in 2013. Terra Incognita is a blend of three different aging processes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Terra Incognita aged in Templeton Rye barrels (30%)</li>
<li>Terra Incognita aged in a 2,000-gallon foudre (45%)</li>
<li>Fresh Terra Incognita dry-hopped with East Kent Golding (25%)</li>
</ul>


<p>This blending creates a beer aimed at showcasing some predominant oak characteristics with a subtle hint of earthy hops and which celebrates the unique terroir of the two brewery locations. Then just prior to bottling a dose of the wild yeast Brettanomyces is added and the beer is aged for over three months.</p>

<ul>
<li>Color &ndash; 92.5 EBC / 47 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 38.5 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 16.9 Plato / 1.069 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 2.10 (after BC) Plato / 1.008 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 8.5%</li>
<li>CO2 &ndash; Bottles &ndash; 6 g/L</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>I did not have much to work with so this is nothing but guesswork. The vital statistics match that of a stout (category 13) with the ABV making my best approximation as an imperial stout.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Dark in color, almost black with a rich head to match.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Mild earthy hop flavors mixed with some oak notes from the barrel aging.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Earthy and spicy flavors from the hops with an rich oak back-end balanced by the warmth of the alcohol. Because the Brettanomyces is added late in the process I don&rsquo;t expect it to be a dominant flavor but rather something subtle in the background.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Huge tan colored head which was rock-solid and seemed to last <em>forever</em>. Beer was deep copper with good clarity.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Strong earthy hop aroma with a touch of rye spiciness and lactic sourness.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The rye and oak flavors blend well on the front of the taste. Some sweetness balanced with a dry bittering on the finish.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; Medium carbonation despite the huge head (which annoying kept getting on my nose). Dry finish.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Very Good (33 / 50)</h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/09/terra-incognita/outside-closeup.jpg" width="350" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Excellent (37 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 2 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: High Size, High Retention, Frothy Texture, Tan Color</li>
<li>Brown/Black color</li>
<li>Lace</li>
<li>Too much head</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 10 / 12</h4>

<p>While the hops flavors were present in the aroma I was missing the oak notes.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Caramel, Roasty, Medium-High Malt</li>
<li>Earthy, Medium Hops</li>
<li>Low-Medium Sweetness</li>
<li>Bittersweet oak background smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 10 / 20</h4>

<p>Why is the hop gone? Strangely, despite the bold hop aroma little to none of the earthy hop flavors which dominated the aroma remain.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 17 / 20

<ul>
<li>Rich, Toasty, Roasty, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Earthy, Spicy, Medium Hops</li>
<li>Low Sweetness</li>
<li>Low Acidic Back-end</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>Unfortunately, the Hulk Hogan head got in the way of drinking this beer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Medium Warmth</li>
<li>Low Creaminess</li>
<li>Medium, Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>This beer would be nice to have once in a while but not on a regular basis. I would be more willing to drink one on a crisp Autumn day as opposed to a hot Summer afternoon. Even then I would probably only drink one glass.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 3 / 10

<ul>
<li>High Stylistic Accuracy</li>
<li>High Technical Merit</li>
<li>Low Intangibles</li>
<li>I would finish this sample</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of New York Limited - Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, Saranac Brewery]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > Brewed and bottled at Brooklyn Brewery, Brookly, NY for SAVOR 2013 NYC this beer is a one-of-a-kind collaboration of Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, and Saranac Brewery. With a focus on local New York ingredients, these brewers combined matled barley, raw wheat, yeast, hops, spices, and ideas grown in New York State to bring you a unique take on wheat beer. This white lager, 100% re-fermented in this bottle, is a collaborative nod to the glorious past and brilliant future of New York State brewing. This special release was presented as an exit gift to SAVOR attendees in a 750 ml corked and caged bottle.</p>

<ul>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Coriander</li>
<li>Orange Peel</li>
<li>Lemon Verbena</li>
<li>Wildflower Honey</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Lager</li>
<li>ABV: 8.5%</li>
<li>IBU: 16.5 IBU</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Because this beer is unique, some research was involved in order to have any idea what to expect. My primary sources of information were the label on the bottle, the <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/news/savor-2013-collaboration-beer/">Media Spot</a>, and the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.SAVORCollaborationBeer.mp3">SAVOR 2013 Salon recording: SAVOR Collaboration Beer</a>. I also took into consideration the stylistic inspiration for this beer, the Witbier(16A).</p>

<ul>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Moderate sweetness with light, grainy, spicy wheat aromatics, often with a bit of tartness. Dominate coriander with a mix of complex herbal and floral aromas in the background. Moderate zesty, citrusy orangey fruitiness.</li>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Pale straw to light gold in color. Thick light-colored head with good retention from the wheat.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Pleasant sweetness with a honey character and a zesty, orange-citrusy fruitiness. The orange peel and lemon verbena should give this beer a different sort of bitterness alongside the low IBU value to help balance. The honey, coriander, and other herbs should give the beer a somewhat complex floral taste in the absence of a Belgian yeast strain. Coriander levels were higher than expected due to either 1) no masking esters or 2) less vigorous lager fermentation left more particulates to contribute to the flavor. Dry, with a low-amount of residual sugars and clean malt taste makes this beer smooth with the high alcohol levels going largely unnoticed. The use of a lager yeast puts the ingredients used to the main stage when it comes to flavor.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Golden straw colored with a touch of haze but otherwise clear. White, bubbly head can be quite tall and the retention is excellent considering its low density.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Coriander and orange dominates the aroma with a touch of floral notes. Spicy wheat characteristics are there if you&rsquo;re really looking for them. The CO2 tickles my nose.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; High carbonation levels makes for a bubbly but unexpectedly creamy texture. I had to pour this beer quickly because after opening the gas release caused the beer to escape the bottle much like a champagne.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Smooth and creamy while still light and refreshing. The orange bitterness lingers a bit on the tongue. Clean lager profile with a solid wheat backdrop for the spices. I think I was picking up on the honey flavors but without knowing the taste profiles of New York honey it is difficult to be certain.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Outstanding (45 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (46 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Smooth Texture, Medium-High Size, High Retention, White Color</li>
<li>Low Clarity</li>
<li>Yellow Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 9 / 12</h4>

<p>Any traces of sweetness or spicy wheat aromatics were masked by the coriander and other spices. Hopefully these will come through more once the beer has had some time to age.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Grainy, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Citrusy, Earthy, Spicy</li>
<li>Fruity</li>
<li>Soft nose with slight coriander smell</li>
<li>Smooth malt/wheat flavor balances with tingling spice aftertaste which lingers on tongue</li>
<li>Missing: Grainy, Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>The floral flavors were the only missing component here. I suspect the overly dominate coriander covered them up.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 19 / 20

<ul>
<li>Low Sweetness, Low Bitterness</li>
<li>Medium Hops, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Slight Toasty, Creamy Malt Flavors</li>
<li>Spicy, Citrusy, Herbal</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Missing: Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>The high level of carbonation was a bit much but the beer improved after several minutes of degassing.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Low Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 10 / 10</h4>

<p>A wonderful beer for drinking on a hot summer day (which we did), this easy to drink beer left me wishing I could have a keg of it every summer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 9 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/inside.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Picture of unopened bottle and SAVOR glasses"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
