<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Brewery Visit | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/brewery-visit/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-26T20:33:56-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confluence Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/good-things.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Where Good Things Come Together&rdquo; &ldquo;Local Art&rdquo;" >
My schedule was terrible for my trip through Des Moines this year and the decision to visit Confluence was based more off their late tap room hours than anything else. Spoiler: It wasn&rsquo;t a bad decision.</p>

<p>Late in the evening we were driving through what appeared to be an industrial district filled with dark warehouses and wondering if our GPS was purposefully leading us to our doom. Just as we had given up hope, we round the bend and were greeted with the warm and bright Confluence store front. It was cold, late and being desperately in need of a beer we hustled inside.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Confluence Brewing Company</strong><br>
1235 Thomas Beck Rd., Suite A<br>
Des Moines, IA 50315<br>
<a href="http://confluencebrewing.com/">www.confluencebrewing.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Member Deals</h3>

<ul>
<li>$0.50 Off on Regular Pints</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> I am loath to post such a short write-up on this brewery&rsquo;s beers because they deserve better but I enjoyed the brewery so much I had the share the experience regardless. You&rsquo;ve been warned: these tasting notes are sub-standard.</p>

<h3>Des Moines IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>Mix of medium body, lighter color and plenty of malt flavor to balance the massive hop impact. Citrusy and piney hops from the Pacific Northwest offset the robust malt flavor of the two-row barley and medium crystal malts.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>75 IBU</li>
<li>7.1% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>High bitterness which does not linger and tastes of Centennial. The Wife: more hop smell than flavor; do not like.</p>

<h3>Capital Gold Golden Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Brewed with time-honored German brewing methods, its slightly sweet, bready, malty flavor is balanced perfectly by traditional German noble hops with medium-low hop bitterness. Domestic and imported German two-row barley malt and noble German hops as well as traditional lager yeast. Undergoes a lagering period of three to four weeks after initial fermentation.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>4.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Grainy nose but standard lager taste. The Wife: clean, light flavor reminiscent of most light beers.</p>

<h3>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>A refreshing, blonde ale, it features a base of two row American barley malt along with a large portion of wheat malt, a small dose of rye malt and un-malted oats, corn and wheat. Lightly hopped with English East Kent Goldings hops chosen for their subtle, earthy qualities and finished with Czech Saaz hops for their sweet, floral essence to create a beer that&rsquo;s light in body and color, with a velvety texture and an aroma as sweet as a freshly cut field of hay.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>21 IBU</li>
<li>5.6%</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite the complex grain flavor; there is a lot going on in this beer. The Wife: very interesting, complex light flavor.</p>

<h3>Thomas Beck Black IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>The dark color comes from black wheat, which is combined with two-row base malt and a good portion of caramel malt and some flaked rye to add a subtle dry, spiciness. We used a special blend of hops, including Nelson Sauvin from Australia, to give it a unique flavor and aroma profile completely distinct from its India Pale Ale cousin, Des Moines IPA.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>58 IBU</li>
<li>6.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Lots of citrus on top of roasted malt flavors. The Wife: burned, bitter flavor.</p>

<h3>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Features a massive bill of English Golden Promise, a little Special B and roasted barley for color to condense and create caramelized sugars that will survive the fermentation process. Adding English East Kent Golding balances the sweetness and cool fermenting with Scottish ale yeast.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>6.6% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>One of the more subtle Scotch Ales I&rsquo;ve tasted. A The Wife: smooth malty finish; very good.</p>

<h3>ChewBocka Winter Bock</h3>

<p><em><small>Made with plenty of Munich malt for a rich, chewy, full-body flavor as well as German Spalter Select, German Tettnanger and American Mt. Hood hops to balance out the malty sweetness. There are also some toasty notes as well as a slight hint of chocolate.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>28 IBU</li>
<li>6.2%</li>
</ul>


<p>Some fruity esters liven up this Bock. The Wife: &ldquo;oaty&rdquo; (I think she made this word up) flavor with a dry finish.</p>

<h3>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Lighter, crisper beer that still has some hop bite to it. Pilsen, Vienna and Caramel 10L malts create a lightly sweet malt profile that is beautifully balanced with Amarillo and Crystal hops.  The light citrus and subtle grass flavors from the hops remind us of the eagerly awaited spring.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>31 IBU</li>
<li>4.86% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Light, clean, and hoppy. I could drink gallons of this beer in the summer. The Wife: hoppy light beer; do not like.</p>

<h3>Wee Lassie Scottish Session Ale</h3>

<ul>
<li>25 IBU</li>
<li>4.8%</li>
</ul>


<p>Very light bodied. The Wife: smooth light ale flavor with a nice finish.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<p>While I quite enjoyed both IPAs offered, the ChewBocka Winter Bock and Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale beat them out but only because they were a bit more unique and stood out among the crowd.</p>

<ol>
<li>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</li>
<li>ChewBocka Winter Bock</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
<li>Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Luke: Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
<li>The Wife: Thomas Beck Black IPA</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>This will be short and sweet, just like our visit to Confluence. Because we arrived so late, I didn&rsquo;t have the time I would have wanted to spend. Hell, my notes were whatever I could fit on the back of a flier for local music. The only conclusion I can make is we enjoyed what little time we had and 100% plan on stopping there again the next time we&rsquo;re in Des Moines.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" alt="Tap Room">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" alt="Tap Board">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" alt="Beer">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" alt="Art">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" alt="casks">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brooklyn Brewery - Brooklyn, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first I&rsquo;d heard about Brooklyn Brewery was from an article in a BYO issue. To be honest, I don&rsquo;t remember much from the article besides the fact they were an older brewery which I wanted to visit. I should probably go back and read that article. Anyway, since I was already in New York City it was a perfect opportunity for a visit. Let me tell you, I&rsquo;m glad that I did.</p>

<p>Brooklyn has a distinctly different feel than Manhattan island. When you emerge from the subway, you&rsquo;re immediately surrounded with by jobs, homes, and real people (not tourists). While I only experienced a few blocks of Brooklyn, it was enough to make an impression.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" alt="Factory Roots">
            <div class="caption"><small>The brewery's former life as a factory shows on the outside but the inside is 100% brewery.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" alt="Building">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/entrance.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Brewery Entrance">
        <div class="caption"><small>Standing guard just inside the main doors are four large fermentation vessels.</small></div>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Standing in the brewery entrance, to your right you&rsquo;ll catch a glimpse of the inner workings of the brewery. To your left is the tempting hubbub of the tap room. We went left.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Brooklyn Brewery</strong><br>
79 N 11th Street<br>
Brooklyn, New York 11249<br>
<a href="http://brooklynbrewery.com/">www.brooklynbrewery.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>10% off Merchandise &amp; Cases</li>
<li>1 Free Beer during Happy Hour &amp; Tours (Friday &amp; Saturday)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tap Room</h2>

<p>The tap room was the large generic room you would expect to see from a warehouse. While the room was filled with wooden tables and benches, finding an open seat was a challenge; the demand for this brewery has definitely outgrown its supply. Whenever a your ends, the line to the tokens to purchase tokens becomes a ten minute wait and the line for the beer becomes a fifteen to twenty minute wait. I would recommend grabbing two beers per person when you finally reach the bartenders. Speaking of bartenders, they all wear the Brooklyn Brewery shirts available for sale which is an excellent way to sneak a preview before you buy. Of course, I could not resist picking up another <a href="http://store.brooklynbrewery.com/brewhouse-t-shirt-180">shirt</a> for my collection.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/tap-room.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tap Room">
Even though the wait was long the beer was worth it. The ones we tried were a bit hoppy for The Wife which means they were right up my alley. The price of beer (five tokens for $20) is worth mentioning. One token will get you most beers with a few speciality beer costing two tokens. This is a killer price for any bar, let alone one in New York City which explains why the place was <em>packed</em> even on a Sunday.</p>

<h2>Tour</h2>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <p>The free tour starts in the main entryway with nowhere near enough seats for the large crowd gathered; no sign-up or reservations is required. We non-intentionally placed ourselves at the front of the tour, but unfortunately the tour consisted of a single room so it didn't make much of a difference. While the information given by the presenter was interesting and well delivered, I felt a bit disappointed at not seeing more of the brewery. Granted the room was quite large and packed with enough equipment to glimpse all aspects of the brewing process, it still felt like just a glimpse. That said, I do not regret going on the tour one bit or even a byte (hahaha, computer pun!) and I definitely recommend you do it at least once. Be sure to bring a beer with you on the tour though, as you'll be standing in one place for a while.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/presenter-bartender.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tour Guide">
    </div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The drink prices alone make the Brooklyn Brewery difficult to pass up; throw in the fact that the beer is <em>good</em> and it becomes a required stop. While there was music always playing it was not overly loud or obnoxious as you would find in most bars or clubs. I envy the group who snagged a large table early and brought a board game (Settlers of Catan I believe) for the evening. Others brought in pizza which is the encouraged food of choice for the tap room. Unfortunately I did not have a chance to try all the beers which means the I will definitely be returning to visit the Brooklyn Brewery the next time I&rsquo;m in New York City. Maybe I&rsquo;ll see you there next time.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" alt="Wall Logo">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" alt="Terminator">
            <div class="caption"><small>Under no circumstances should you visit this brewery if you are the future savior of mankind from intelligent killer robots.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" alt="Random Sword">
            <div class="caption"><small>Unfortunately, I did not witness any sword-fighting. Maybe next time?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" alt="Scorcher 1363">
            <div class="caption"><small>One of the beers on tap during our visit.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" alt="Log">
            <div class="caption"><small>Bonus points if you can figure out what they were brewing.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" alt="Grain Tubes">
            <div class="caption"><small>Those tubes carry grain, not liquids.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" alt="Chandelier">
            <div class="caption"><small>Did I mention this brewery was quite the classy establishment?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" alt="Casks">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" alt="Bottler">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raccoon River Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/raccoon-river-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T14:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/raccoon-river-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Raccoon River Brewery is located in downtown Des Moines, a bit difficult to find but that could have been the snow and just generally not knowing where I was in a new city. We also have a hard time not calling it <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raccoon_City">Raccoon City</a> Brewery which made for some interesting conversations.</p>

<p>A large upscale restaurant with a pub feel, Raccoon River has a second level which looks down onto the first. A two-story tower of brewing equipment becomes a centerpiece for both levels of the restaurant. The top level looks down on the bottom and has pool tables. We didn&rsquo;t see much else because we never went up. Next time I&rsquo;m make sure to get a real tour.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Raccoon River Brewing Co</strong><br>
200 10th St<br>
Des Moines, IA 50309-3609<br>
<a href="http://www.raccoonbrew.com/">www.raccoonbrew.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>Happy Hour Prices &ndash; Anytime.</li>
<li>Weekly Specials &ndash; Available Everyday.</li>
<li>Free Pool on Saturday&rsquo;s (11am-5pm).</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/raccoon-river-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" width="350"></p>

<h3>Tallgrass Light</h3>

<p><em><small>High-quality, lightest</small></em></p>

<p>Clear enough to see The Wife&rsquo;s face through. Light malty nose and what you&rsquo;d expect from a standard pilsner.</p>

<h3>Homestead Red</h3>

<p><em><small>A classic Red, rich and malty</small></em></p>

<p>Beautiful red color with a definite caramel nose and tastes of raisins. The bitterness was higher than I expected but balanced out nicely with the caramel malts.</p>

<h3>Bandit IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>Most assertive, highly hopped</small></em></p>

<p>Gold in color and full of hoppy aromatics. The bitterness is early and often which pairs well with the citrus hops used. This is not a beer I could drink all evening, but I would definitely have at least one before moving on to something else.</p>

<h3>Fatal Attraction (Seasonal)</h3>

<p><em><small>Strong golden Belgian ale, high gravity</small></em></p>

<p>Cloudy appearance with a sweet, crisp nose. The malty sweetness and the fruity esters of the yeast combine with effervescence mouth-feel which tingles on the tongue to make this beer quite the experience.</p>

<h3>MacCoy&rsquo;s Scotch Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Sweet, malty and complex dark ale, high gravity</small></em></p>

<p>Dark red in color, this beer has a dark, sweet raisin/chocolate taste which comes through in the nose. Caramel malts provided a balanced sweetness.</p>

<h3>Stonecutter Stout</h3>

<p><em><small>Big, dark and complex oatmeal stout</small></em></p>

<p>Black in color with a beautiful rich coffee nose (I want an air freshener that duplicates this smell). Light in body, this beer has a dark roasted front and a light bitter back.</p>

<h3>Stonecutter Imperial Stout</h3>

<p><em><small>Stonecutter Stout, times two</small></em></p>

<p>More subtle nose than the regular Stonecutter Stout. The extra alcohol overpowers other flavors which ruins the warming mouth-feel.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<ol>
<li>Fatal Attraction (Seasonal) &amp; MacCoy&rsquo;s Scotch Ale</li>
<li>Stonecutter Stout</li>
<li>Bandit IPA</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Fatal Attraction (Seasonal) &amp; MacCoy&rsquo;s Scotch Ale</li>
<li>Tallgrass Light</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Luke: Stonecutter Imperial Stout</li>
<li>The Wife: Stonecutter Imperial Stout</li>
</ul>


<div class="alert alert-info">
Two beers stood out from the others so much we could not decide which one we liked more so we just gave them both first place on our lists.
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The Wife and I both had burgers with sauteed vegetables. While the burgers were unique, they did not leave enough of an impression to remember what we had by the time we were home. I do remember they were good when we ate them though, so I wouldn&rsquo;t shy away from eating there in the future.</p>

<p>I may not be excited to eat here, but I will be excited about trying their beer and there are some excellent ones at Raccoon River. What is on tap changes regularly enough to always provide something new during your visit.</p>

<p>I will warn you if you visit in the early afternoon on a weekday, you may end up with a older waitress with a gruff demeanor. Do not be discouraged. If you can look past that and make conversation about the beer, she&rsquo;ll warm up to you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Olde Main Brewing Company - Ames, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/olde-main-brewing-company-ames-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T12:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/olde-main-brewing-company-ames-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/olde-main-brewing-company/sign.jpg" width="300"> Old Maine Brewery is located in the heart of downtown Ames' quaint Main Street district. Enter the restaurant and brewpub and you are immediately drawn in by the historic Main Street atmosphere and friendly brewpub feel. An abundance of wood gives the interior a warm, old-fashioned feeling making you right at home.</p>

<p>We ordered a plate of cheese fries at the time of the beer tasting so we would be able to continue driving afterwards. The cheese fries were about what you would expect at a bowling alley and easily something I could have made at home (frozen French fries + American cheese). Our waitress was very nice and quite helpful even though she was obviously busy preparing for the evening crowd. For this reason we forgive her for suggesting the cheese fries appetizer.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Olde Main Brewing Company &amp; Restaurant</strong><br>
316 Main Street<br>
Ames, Iowa 50010<br>
<a href="http://www.oldemainbrewing.com/">www.oldemainbrewing.com</a></p>

<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/olde-main-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" width="350"></p>

<h3>Long Face</h3>

<p><em><small>Amber Ale. A horse walks into a bar and the bartender says, &ldquo;Why the long face?&rdquo; An all around easy drinking, tasty beverage with malt and notable caramel flavors balanced by several American hop varieties.</small></em></p>

<p>Light malt flavor, less than what I expected out of an Amber Ale. Nice gold color. Pronounced bitterness which does not linger. Feels more like a German Pilsner than an Amber Ale.</p>

<h3>Off KILTer</h3>

<p><em><small>Scottish Ale. This traditional Scottish Ale has a subdued hop flavor and aroma with a high in malt flavor. Our brew master actually wears a kilt while brewing this ale to achieve maximum Scottish feel and tradition.</small></em></p>

<p>Amber in color with a noticeable malt aroma. Syrupy flavors almost conceal the peat which would have worked had it not been so out of balance.</p>

<h3>Clone</h3>

<p><em><small>American Pale Ale. Simply a &ldquo;Clone&rdquo; of an American classic, this American Pale Ale is crisp and clean with a noteworthy hoppy bite. The subtle malt background balances out the refreshing ale.</small></em></p>

<p>Light nose with a very pale yellow color; could easily pass as a pilsner. Moderate citrus hops balanced with bitterness. The dry finish is good for slow drinking during lasting conversations.</p>

<h3>Dinkey Wheat</h3>

<p><em><small>Belgian Style Wheat Ale. Named for the train that used to run from downtown Ames to the ISU Campus, the Dinkey Wheat has a flavor derived from coriander, chamomile, and orange peel, making for a unique drinking experience.</small></em></p>

<p>The aroma of this beer reminded me of a bag of chamomile tea before being brewed. Unfortunately, the beer tasted like someone steeped a bag of chamomile tea in an unfiltered wheat; not a good flavor.</p>

<h3>Sodbuster</h3>

<p><em><small>Stout Ale. Hearty ale with color and flavors derived from roast, chocolate, and caramel malts. This ale has a complex taste with a rich creamy mouth-feel. The pronounced hop presence balances the deep malt flavors.</small></em></p>

<p>Distinct aroma of roasted coffee. Light body with a drying finish. Dark roasted malts gives this beer a taste perfectly in tune with its aroma.</p>

<h3>Gryphonbrau</h3>

<p><em><small>Premium Lager. Germans brought lager beer to America in the 19th century. They brewed those early American lagers using a combination of local and traditional ingredients. In keeping with tradition we do the same. Local water and malted barley combine with traditional German hops and yeast means that Gryph is made the way that American lagers always should have been, with zero compromise on quality. It&rsquo;s an easy drinker with a slight malt sweetness and light hop flavor and aroma. This refreshing beer has a crisp and clean finish.</small></em></p>

<p>Clear and quite pale straw color. Floral nose and a slightly fruity taste but without esters. The light matliness brought the hops to the forefront of this beer. While too much for what I expect in a light lager, the taste intrigues me and makes me wish they had listed what hops where used.</p>

<h3>Elkman</h3>

<p><em><small>Milk Stout. The sweet character in this beer comes from lactose sugar added into the kettle and residual sugars left over after fermentation is complete.  Roasted grains with chocolate, caramel, and coffee flavors are the flagship tastes with the sweetness uniting these flavors together to give a full-bodied, creamy ale with a smooth finish.  This is a dark, deep, black colored ale with thick brown foam.</small></em></p>

<p>Creamy nose and a beautiful clear dark red color. Light body with a creamy mouth-feel.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<ol>
<li>Sodbuster</li>
<li>Elkman</li>
<li>Clone</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Off KILTer</li>
<li>&ldquo;Red Monkey&rdquo; Root Beer</li>
<li>Sodbuster</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Dinkey Wheat</li>
<li>The Wife: Dinkey Wheat</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Olde Maine is very generous with their beer sampler. We received eight 4 oz pours for a measly $6.00. This is a great deal for someone who needs a break from I-35 and worth the short detour. There are few places which can match the number of beers for the price.</p>

<p>For the most part I could tell where the brewer was headed with beer and there are some good beers hiding here. However, I do not think the recipes were quite finished and definitely need some tweaking. Balancing the flavors is all this brewery needs to become a great brewpub, instead of just an alright restaurant bar with hit-or-miss beers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summit Brewing Company - St Paul, Minnesota]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/16/summit-brewing-company-st-paul-minnesota/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-16T18:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/16/summit-brewing-company-st-paul-minnesota</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/sign-outside.jpg" width="300">Every Friday night, Summit invites a food truck and has a special beer on tap in addition to their full line-up of beers. The week we were there it was <a href="http://ramacsammys.com/">R.A. Mac Sammy&rsquo;s</a> which serves awesome mac-n-cheese dishes. Unfortunately I forgot my notebook in the rush to get to the brewery before the food truck left, so I don&rsquo;t have notes on the beer or any foods thoughts. What I can tell you is that I tried all of the available beers and enjoyed each one of them. Also, sauerkraut on mac-n-cheese is delicious (trust me on this one).</p>

<p>The tap room features a large area open area with many tables and benches. Music plays but not loud enough to be disruptive. You buy tokens from the cashier which are used to purchase beer from the bartender. I&rsquo;m not a huge fan of the system (the cashier is about ten feet from the bartender) but I can see how it would help keep people flowing when busy. There is also a gift shop right off the tap room where we picked up some <a href="http://store.summitbrewing.com/drinklocaltee.aspx">Summit swag</a>. Not shown in the pictures below are the double set of German copper brew kettles which are behind the large glass tap room wall (it was too dark to take better pictures with our old camera).</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/food-truck.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/food-truck.jpg" alt="Food Truck">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/food.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/food.jpg" alt="Food">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/tap-room.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/tap-room.jpg" alt="Tap Room">
            <div class="caption"><small>Tap Room</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/summit-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" alt="Full Glasses">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Summit Brewing Co</strong><br>
910 Montreal Cir<br>
Saint Paul, MN 55102-4246<br>
<a href="http://www.summitbrewing.com/">www.summitbrewing.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>10% Off Merchandise</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>I would probably end up coming to Summit every Friday if it were not several states away. The good beer coupled with new and different foods would be too much to resist. Hopefully I will have time to schedule a tour the next time I am in the area.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
