<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Horny Goat | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/horny-goat/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-05T11:34:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My favorite season of the year is almost upon us. Cooler weather, changing colors, all the best holidays, and of course, seasonal beer. One of the most iconic Autumn styles is the pumpkin beer. While pumpkin beers were produced in the early days of the American colonies, they were different from the pumpkin beers we know today.  Colonists used pumpkin and squash as the fermenting medium, since malted barley was scarce.  Once malt became more readily available, it replaced these alternatives to grain. In the 1990&rsquo;s, American craft brewers reintroduced the style to the delight of pumpkin beer drinkers.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/09/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-1.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 1 Beers">
Five pumpkin beers face off in a head-to-head challenge of seasonal carnage. Which brewery&rsquo;s Fall creation will emerge victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.newbelgium.com/beer/detail.aspx?id=4a0076ef-aa43-44bb-a1ff-1a20d33245b6">New Belgium &ndash; Pumpkick</a></h3>

<p><em><small>What&rsquo;s that bite of tartness doing in a pumpkin beer? Adding the unexpected kick of cranberry juice to brighten this traditionally spiced seasonal ale. Pumpkick is brewed with plenty of pumpkin juice, cinnamon, nutmeg, and allspice, but it&rsquo;s the cranberries and touch of lemongrass that send your taste buds sailing.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 6.0%</li>
<li>Hops: Target</li>
<li>Malts: Pale, Munich, Caramel</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Pumpkin juice, Cinnamon, Nutmeg, Allspice, Cranberries, Lemongrass</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 5 / 10</h4>

<p>Bold spice nose of nutmeg, allspice, and clove which comes through with a medium intensity in the flavor. There is a touch of fruity esters in the background which I would except from New Belgium. The vegetable/fruit flavor of the pumpkin and the dry finish leaves a gritty coating of spices on my tongue. The blend of spices is great but the finish leaves a residue which ruins the balance of the beer.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 5 / 10</h4>

<p>Spiced nose, strong of allspice and nutmeg. Weak flavor, pumpkin lacking. Lots of spices in the flavor.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.hornygoatbrewing.com/wordpress/meet-the-craft-beers/">Horny Goat &ndash; HornyCopia</a></h3>

<p><em><small>We mash in pumpkins with two-row, Vienna and Caramel malts for a hearty ale with just the right amount of body. Spices added to the boil create a complex yet deliciously harmonious flavor. We used pumpkin and spice to yield a brew we proudly describe as &ldquo;Pumpkin Pie in a Bottle&rdquo;.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 6.3%</li>
<li>IBU: 23</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 4 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet malty nose and good nutmeg aroma which comes through mild yet dominant in the flavor on top of a solid malt base. Finish is light and airy, but the nutmeg bitterness lingers, compounding with each drink and ruining the beer for me after only a few drinks.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft, sweet nose with little spice smell. Smooth malt flavor, dry finish. Good pumpkin up front.</p>

<h3><a href="http://schlafly.com/beers/styles/pumpkin-ale/">Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Our Pumpkin Ale blends the spices of the harvest with full-bodied sweetness for a beer that tastes like pumpkin pie. Pounds of pumpkin form a malty foundation that supports the fall flavors of cinnamon, nutmeg and clove.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 18.5 Plato</li>
<li>ABV: 8.0%</li>
<li>IBU: 16</li>
<li>SRM: 27 (Copper-colored, bright)</li>
<li>Malts: Pale, Crystal, Munich, Wheat, Chocolate</li>
<li>Hops: Marynka (PL)</li>
<li>Yeast: American Ale</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: pumpkin squash and a blend of spices</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Allspice comes through in the nose and is the dominant spice in the flavor with a medium intensity. Darker malts, possibly crystal, sweeten this beer up and ends with a pleasant, medium dry finish. While the sweetness sets this beer apart from the others, the extra flavors makes this beer a bit heavier and not as easy to drink.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft nose of nutmeg and allspice. Too much nutmeg and not enough malt flavor. Bitter back-end. Too much spice, not enough everything else.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.ofallonbrewery.com/products/">O'Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Like pumpkin pie in a bottle&hellip;we add 136 pounds of real pumpkin to the three-barley mash and then season the finished beer with cinnamon, nutmeg and cloves.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 5.6%</li>
<li>IBU: 11</li>
<li>SRM 8.7</li>
<li>Malts: Pale, White Wheat, Caramel 90L</li>
<li>Hops: Cluster</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>A sweet cinnamon nose with a good balance between the spices and hop bitterness. The spice flavors did not dominate but instead complimented the malts well; very well balanced.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet nose of cinnamon and nutmeg. Sweet pumpkin flavor with very little pumpkin back-end or bitterness. Slight malt flavor. Good body.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/harvest-pumpkin-ale">Samuel Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Smooth, rich, and roasty with over 17 lbs. of real pumpkin &amp; warming spices like ginger, cinnamon &amp; nutmeg give this brew a smooth inviting character.  This style, first brewed by American colonists, is hearty and spicy making it perfect for the crisper days of fall.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 5.7%</li>
<li>IBU: 14</li>
<li>SRM: 33 (Dark reddish amber)</li>
<li>Malts: Samuel Adams two-row pale malt blend, Caramel 60, Special B, smoked malt</li>
<li>Hops: East Kent Goldings, Fuggles</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-fermenting Ale</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Real pumpkin, cinnamon, ginger, nutmeg, allspice</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>The aroma is nutty with a hint of nutmeg. Vegetal pumpkin taste come through with a nice spice seasoning. Smooth, clean finish indicative of a lager beer. This beer is how I imagine the original pumpkin beers may have tasted.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Spiced nose of allspice and nutmeg. Sweet spice and malty flavor. No real hop bitterness noted; any bitterness is from pumpkin flavors. Tastes like it smells.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">8.5</div> O'Fallon &ndash; Pumpkin Beer</li>
<li><div class="badge">7.5</div> Samuel Adams &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">6.5</div> Schlafly &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">5.5</div> Horny Goat &ndash; HornyCopia</li>
<li><div class="badge">5</div> New Belgium &ndash; Pumpkick</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
