<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ommegang | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/ommegang/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-13T20:25:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of New York Limited - Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, Saranac Brewery]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > Brewed and bottled at Brooklyn Brewery, Brookly, NY for SAVOR 2013 NYC this beer is a one-of-a-kind collaboration of Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, and Saranac Brewery. With a focus on local New York ingredients, these brewers combined matled barley, raw wheat, yeast, hops, spices, and ideas grown in New York State to bring you a unique take on wheat beer. This white lager, 100% re-fermented in this bottle, is a collaborative nod to the glorious past and brilliant future of New York State brewing. This special release was presented as an exit gift to SAVOR attendees in a 750 ml corked and caged bottle.</p>

<ul>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Coriander</li>
<li>Orange Peel</li>
<li>Lemon Verbena</li>
<li>Wildflower Honey</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Lager</li>
<li>ABV: 8.5%</li>
<li>IBU: 16.5 IBU</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Because this beer is unique, some research was involved in order to have any idea what to expect. My primary sources of information were the label on the bottle, the <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/news/savor-2013-collaboration-beer/">Media Spot</a>, and the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.SAVORCollaborationBeer.mp3">SAVOR 2013 Salon recording: SAVOR Collaboration Beer</a>. I also took into consideration the stylistic inspiration for this beer, the Witbier(16A).</p>

<ul>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Moderate sweetness with light, grainy, spicy wheat aromatics, often with a bit of tartness. Dominate coriander with a mix of complex herbal and floral aromas in the background. Moderate zesty, citrusy orangey fruitiness.</li>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Pale straw to light gold in color. Thick light-colored head with good retention from the wheat.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Pleasant sweetness with a honey character and a zesty, orange-citrusy fruitiness. The orange peel and lemon verbena should give this beer a different sort of bitterness alongside the low IBU value to help balance. The honey, coriander, and other herbs should give the beer a somewhat complex floral taste in the absence of a Belgian yeast strain. Coriander levels were higher than expected due to either 1) no masking esters or 2) less vigorous lager fermentation left more particulates to contribute to the flavor. Dry, with a low-amount of residual sugars and clean malt taste makes this beer smooth with the high alcohol levels going largely unnoticed. The use of a lager yeast puts the ingredients used to the main stage when it comes to flavor.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Golden straw colored with a touch of haze but otherwise clear. White, bubbly head can be quite tall and the retention is excellent considering its low density.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Coriander and orange dominates the aroma with a touch of floral notes. Spicy wheat characteristics are there if you&rsquo;re really looking for them. The CO2 tickles my nose.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; High carbonation levels makes for a bubbly but unexpectedly creamy texture. I had to pour this beer quickly because after opening the gas release caused the beer to escape the bottle much like a champagne.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Smooth and creamy while still light and refreshing. The orange bitterness lingers a bit on the tongue. Clean lager profile with a solid wheat backdrop for the spices. I think I was picking up on the honey flavors but without knowing the taste profiles of New York honey it is difficult to be certain.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Outstanding (45 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (46 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Smooth Texture, Medium-High Size, High Retention, White Color</li>
<li>Low Clarity</li>
<li>Yellow Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 9 / 12</h4>

<p>Any traces of sweetness or spicy wheat aromatics were masked by the coriander and other spices. Hopefully these will come through more once the beer has had some time to age.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Grainy, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Citrusy, Earthy, Spicy</li>
<li>Fruity</li>
<li>Soft nose with slight coriander smell</li>
<li>Smooth malt/wheat flavor balances with tingling spice aftertaste which lingers on tongue</li>
<li>Missing: Grainy, Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>The floral flavors were the only missing component here. I suspect the overly dominate coriander covered them up.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 19 / 20

<ul>
<li>Low Sweetness, Low Bitterness</li>
<li>Medium Hops, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Slight Toasty, Creamy Malt Flavors</li>
<li>Spicy, Citrusy, Herbal</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Missing: Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>The high level of carbonation was a bit much but the beer improved after several minutes of degassing.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Low Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 10 / 10</h4>

<p>A wonderful beer for drinking on a hot summer day (which we did), this easy to drink beer left me wishing I could have a keg of it every summer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 9 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/inside.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Picture of unopened bottle and SAVOR glasses"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
