<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Olde Main | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/olde-main/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-13T20:25:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Olde Main Brewing Company - Ames, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/olde-main-brewing-company-ames-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-18T12:30:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/18/olde-main-brewing-company-ames-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/olde-main-brewing-company/sign.jpg" width="300"> Old Maine Brewery is located in the heart of downtown Ames' quaint Main Street district. Enter the restaurant and brewpub and you are immediately drawn in by the historic Main Street atmosphere and friendly brewpub feel. An abundance of wood gives the interior a warm, old-fashioned feeling making you right at home.</p>

<p>We ordered a plate of cheese fries at the time of the beer tasting so we would be able to continue driving afterwards. The cheese fries were about what you would expect at a bowling alley and easily something I could have made at home (frozen French fries + American cheese). Our waitress was very nice and quite helpful even though she was obviously busy preparing for the evening crowd. For this reason we forgive her for suggesting the cheese fries appetizer.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Olde Main Brewing Company &amp; Restaurant</strong><br>
316 Main Street<br>
Ames, Iowa 50010<br>
<a href="http://www.oldemainbrewing.com/">www.oldemainbrewing.com</a></p>

<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/olde-main-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" width="350"></p>

<h3>Long Face</h3>

<p><em><small>Amber Ale. A horse walks into a bar and the bartender says, &ldquo;Why the long face?&rdquo; An all around easy drinking, tasty beverage with malt and notable caramel flavors balanced by several American hop varieties.</small></em></p>

<p>Light malt flavor, less than what I expected out of an Amber Ale. Nice gold color. Pronounced bitterness which does not linger. Feels more like a German Pilsner than an Amber Ale.</p>

<h3>Off KILTer</h3>

<p><em><small>Scottish Ale. This traditional Scottish Ale has a subdued hop flavor and aroma with a high in malt flavor. Our brew master actually wears a kilt while brewing this ale to achieve maximum Scottish feel and tradition.</small></em></p>

<p>Amber in color with a noticeable malt aroma. Syrupy flavors almost conceal the peat which would have worked had it not been so out of balance.</p>

<h3>Clone</h3>

<p><em><small>American Pale Ale. Simply a &ldquo;Clone&rdquo; of an American classic, this American Pale Ale is crisp and clean with a noteworthy hoppy bite. The subtle malt background balances out the refreshing ale.</small></em></p>

<p>Light nose with a very pale yellow color; could easily pass as a pilsner. Moderate citrus hops balanced with bitterness. The dry finish is good for slow drinking during lasting conversations.</p>

<h3>Dinkey Wheat</h3>

<p><em><small>Belgian Style Wheat Ale. Named for the train that used to run from downtown Ames to the ISU Campus, the Dinkey Wheat has a flavor derived from coriander, chamomile, and orange peel, making for a unique drinking experience.</small></em></p>

<p>The aroma of this beer reminded me of a bag of chamomile tea before being brewed. Unfortunately, the beer tasted like someone steeped a bag of chamomile tea in an unfiltered wheat; not a good flavor.</p>

<h3>Sodbuster</h3>

<p><em><small>Stout Ale. Hearty ale with color and flavors derived from roast, chocolate, and caramel malts. This ale has a complex taste with a rich creamy mouth-feel. The pronounced hop presence balances the deep malt flavors.</small></em></p>

<p>Distinct aroma of roasted coffee. Light body with a drying finish. Dark roasted malts gives this beer a taste perfectly in tune with its aroma.</p>

<h3>Gryphonbrau</h3>

<p><em><small>Premium Lager. Germans brought lager beer to America in the 19th century. They brewed those early American lagers using a combination of local and traditional ingredients. In keeping with tradition we do the same. Local water and malted barley combine with traditional German hops and yeast means that Gryph is made the way that American lagers always should have been, with zero compromise on quality. It&rsquo;s an easy drinker with a slight malt sweetness and light hop flavor and aroma. This refreshing beer has a crisp and clean finish.</small></em></p>

<p>Clear and quite pale straw color. Floral nose and a slightly fruity taste but without esters. The light matliness brought the hops to the forefront of this beer. While too much for what I expect in a light lager, the taste intrigues me and makes me wish they had listed what hops where used.</p>

<h3>Elkman</h3>

<p><em><small>Milk Stout. The sweet character in this beer comes from lactose sugar added into the kettle and residual sugars left over after fermentation is complete.  Roasted grains with chocolate, caramel, and coffee flavors are the flagship tastes with the sweetness uniting these flavors together to give a full-bodied, creamy ale with a smooth finish.  This is a dark, deep, black colored ale with thick brown foam.</small></em></p>

<p>Creamy nose and a beautiful clear dark red color. Light body with a creamy mouth-feel.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<ol>
<li>Sodbuster</li>
<li>Elkman</li>
<li>Clone</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Off KILTer</li>
<li>&ldquo;Red Monkey&rdquo; Root Beer</li>
<li>Sodbuster</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Dinkey Wheat</li>
<li>The Wife: Dinkey Wheat</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>Olde Maine is very generous with their beer sampler. We received eight 4 oz pours for a measly $6.00. This is a great deal for someone who needs a break from I-35 and worth the short detour. There are few places which can match the number of beers for the price.</p>

<p>For the most part I could tell where the brewer was headed with beer and there are some good beers hiding here. However, I do not think the recipes were quite finished and definitely need some tweaking. Balancing the flavors is all this brewery needs to become a great brewpub, instead of just an alright restaurant bar with hit-or-miss beers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
