<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Buffalo Mill | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/buffalo-mill/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:38:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My favorite season of the year is upon us. Cool weather, changing colors, allergies, festivals, and of course, seasonal beer. Perhaps the the most iconic Autumn style is the pumpkin beer. While pumpkin beers were produced in the early days of the American colonies, they were different from the pumpkin beers we know today. Colonists used pumpkin and squash as the fermenting medium, since malted barley was scarce. Once malt became more readily available, it replaced these alternatives to grain.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/09/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-2.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 2 Beers">
Five more pumpkin beers face off in this head-to-head challenge of seasonal carnage. Which brewery&rsquo;s Fall creation will from Round 2 emerge victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.shocktopbeer.com/s/index.php/our-beers/pumpkin-wheat/">Shock Top &ndash; Pumpkin Wheat</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Our Pumpkin Wheat seasonal offering combines the smooth taste of Shock Top with the flavors of Fall. We start with a traditional Belgian-style wheat ale and then brew with ripe pumpkins and a variety of autumnal spices, including nutmeg, cinnamon and cloves, for a refreshingly smooth beer that fully captures all the flavors of fall.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Dominant allspice nose and flavor. The use of wheat makes a nice complement to the spices at the expense of smoothness but still resulting in a balanced beer. Wheat replaces any pumpkin characteristics which I am not a big fan of so this beer loses a few points for going off-style.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft spiced nose. Bitter front-end taste with a clean finish which doesn&rsquo;t linger. Allspice but no pumpkin taste. Tastes more like a wheat beer than a pumpkin beer.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.shipyard.com/images/pumpkinlyte.jpg">Shipyard &ndash; Pumpkinhead</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Shipyard Pumpkinhead Ale is a crisp and refreshing wheat ale with delightful aromatics and subtle spiced flavor.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 1048</li>
<li>Color: Golden</li>
<li>Malts: 2-Row British Pale Ale, Malted Wheat, Light Munich</li>
<li>Hops: Hallertau, Willamette</li>
<li>Yeast: Top-Fermenting English</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: pumpkin, cinnamon, nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 5 / 10</h4>

<p>Floral allspice aroma. Pale and straw-colored, this beer is the lightest in color we&rsquo;ve tasted so far. Floral front-end, light body, but not much spice flavor. Perhaps a touch of cinnamon and honey contributeS to the floral nature of the beer. While good, it is not much of a pumpkin beer so it loses some points for going off-style.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 2 / 10</h4>

<p>Cinnamon spice sweet nose with maybe some brown sugar as well. Huge cinnamon flavor with a slight bit of cloves on the front-end. Slight pumpkin flavor in mouth at the end. Really just tastes like cinnamon water to me.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.mendobrew.com/collections/seasonal.html">Mendocino &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>To honor Fall we offer our deep mahogany hued Pumpkin Ale, bursting with a robust roasted malt flavor. To this melange we add copious amounts of pumpkin and embellish that further with nutmeg, cinnamon and ginger. This would have been ideal, but perfection is our preference and so we diligently add cocoa nibs as the beer conditions and intensifies the depth of flavor. This melds magnificently with the pumpkin and spice. And as a fitting finale we gently introduce hops to compliment this complex potion and the result is a finish that is clean and brilliant. At 5% alc./vol., this is a Pumpkin perfect session ale &ndash; Perfect for Fall and the approaching holiday season.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 3 / 10</h4>

<p>Dark amber in color with a very mild spice aroma. Mild nutmeg and allspice flavors are ruined by the unexpected harsh bitterness from the cocoa nibs. I have no idea what would posses someone to add these flavors to a pumpkin beer but the gamble did not pay off.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 2 / 10</h4>

<p>Bitter and burned nutmeg flavor lingers in the mouth. Dry finish with maybe some cinnamon flavors.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.bluemoonbrewingcompany.com/ourbeers/product/harvest-pumpkin-ale">Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>In 1995, we crafted our first autumn seasonal-Pumpkin Ale. At the time, Oktoberfest beers were in high demand. For our version, we wanted to create a beer that was a little different than what was already out there and complemented the season by highlighting the flavors we&rsquo;ve all grown to love during this time. It was so popular that it became the first nationally available pumpkin ale. Harvest Pumpkin Ale, as it&rsquo;s called now, is crafted with pumpkin and spices of cinnamon, nutmeg, cloves, and allspice for a taste you&rsquo;ll want to fall right into.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>OG: 15 Plato</li>
<li>ABV: 5.7%</li>
<li>IBU: 16</li>
<li>Malts: Munich, Caramel</li>
<li>Hops: Hallertau</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Pumpkin, Cinnamon, Nutmeg, Clove, Allspice</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 7 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild spice aroma. Dominant nutmeg flavors are balanced out with some allspice and vegetable flavors. Dry finish with some bitterness from the nutmeg. While the spices have a strong presence they are not overpowering creating a nice balance.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet nose with a nutmeg/allspice flavor and a nice pumpkin bitterness.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.buffalobillsbrewery.com/">Buffalo Bill&rsquo;s &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</a></h3>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 8 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet pumpkin flesh nose and medium spice aroma. The spice takes a back seat and complements the good malt flavors. Light body with a dry finish, this beer is wonderfully balanced and easy to drink.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>Soft pumpkin nose and a smooth allspice flavor. Has a nice subtle pumpkin flavor.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">8.5</div> Buffalo Bill&rsquo;s &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">7.5</div> Blue Moon &ndash; Harvest Pumpkin Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">6.5</div> Shock Top &ndash; Pumpkin Wheat</li>
<li><div class="badge">3.5</div> Shipyard &ndash; Pumpkinhead</li>
<li><div class="badge">2.5</div> Mendocino &ndash; Pumpkin Ale</li>
</ol>


<p>In Case you Missed it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/">Round 1</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
