<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Court Avenue | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/court-avenue/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:38:25-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Court Avenue Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/14/court-avenue-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-14T15:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/02/14/court-avenue-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/pub-sign.jpg" width="300"> I had originally planned on my first stop through Des Moines to be the Raccoon River brewery, however we wandered the downtown streets without a map and eventually became lost. Luckily, we ended up going in the direction of the Court Avenue brewery which had a conveniently large sign to direct you out of the cold and into a warm restaurant. Fate had spoken, so we switched our agenda and made Court Avenue our first brewery stop of the trip.</p>

<p>I ordered the BBQ Pork sandwich which was shredded pork in BlackHawk Stout BBQ sauce on Texas toast and topped with coleslaw and a side of potato salad. The Wife ordered the BBQ Chicken pizza which has grilled chicken, red onion, fresh cilantro &amp; BlackHawk Stout BBQ sauce, with cheddar jack &amp; mozzarella cheese. For dessert we shared a huge piece of bread pudding. Needless to say we were stuffed by the end of the meal. All-in-all the food was absolutely amazing; the pictures cannot do them justice (especially with our old camera). In fact, I may have enjoyed the food more than the beer (gasp!).</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/pulled-pork.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/pulled-pork.jpg" alt="Pulled Pork Sandwich, Carolina Style">
            <div class="caption"><small>Pulled Pork Sandwich, Carolina Style</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/bbq-pizza.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/bbq-pizza.jpg" alt="BBQ Chicken Pizza">
            <div class="caption"><small>BBQ Chicken Pizza</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/bread-pudding.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/bread-pudding.jpg" alt="Bread Pudding">
            <div class="caption"><small>Bread Pudding</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>A good portion of the brewing equipment (kettles, fermenters, etc.) are behind glass in the dining room which makes for an interesting centerpiece during the dining experience. These are not only for show either, because we watched a brewer actively brewing something during our visit. He even stopped by our table and asked us how we were enjoying the beer when he saw me taking notes.</p>

<p>I was able to try most of the flagship beers as well as a few guest beers from <a href="http://21st-amendment.com/">21st Amendment</a>, a seasonal, and the special reserve stock in their standard sampler flight. My thoughts on the flagship beers below.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Court Avenue Brewing Co</strong><br>
309 Court Avenue<br>
Des Moines, Iowa, 50309<br>
<a href="http://www.courtavebrew.com/">www.courtavebrew.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>Happy Hour Prices &ndash; Anytime</li>
<li>VIP tour with Brewer</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/02/court-avenue-brewing-company/full-glasses.jpg" width="350"></p>

<h3>Two Rivers Light</h3>

<p><em><small>Our Two Rivers Light is the lightest brew we produce and is a great introduction to craft beer or alternative for the person who enjoys macro lagers.</small></em></p>

<p>Standard pilsner with a nice malt flavor. Reminds me of by favorite local pilsner, Boulevard Pilsner but less crisp. Court Avenue uses this beer as a gateway beer into the craft beer world.</p>

<h3>Belgian White</h3>

<p><em><small>An old Belgian farmhouse style, our white (or wit) is a wheat beer brewed with coriander and Curacao orange peel. A distinctive yeast strain, coupled with these spices, produces a cloudy, almost white beer, that&rsquo;s fruity, spicy and exceptionally refreshing.</small></em></p>

<p>Nice fruity nose. Spot on stylistically and exactly what I expect of a Belgian White. Dry clean finish but with a lingering coriander/citrus afternotes.</p>

<h3>Pointer Brown Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Southern English style of brown ale. Caramel, chocolate, slightly roasty flavors dominate the profile of this beer. Brewed to be flavorful and highly drinkable at the same time.</small></em></p>

<p>Light caramel nose with raisin notes. Nice balance between sweetness and bitterness. While I enjoyed the beer, it was not what I was expect from a Brown Ale.</p>

<h3>BlackHawk Stout</h3>

<p><em><small>A dry oatmeal stout. Coffee, roast and chocolate flavors throughout, very smooth body from the addition of flaked oats. The use of six different malts makes this a very complex beer.</small></em></p>

<p>Reminds me of a creamy, fuller-bodied Guinness. Perfect for nursing through a late evening with a gathering of friends. The Wife said it reminds her of a smoother, lighter bodies Oatmeal Stout from <a href="http://www.freestatebrewing.com/">Free State Brewery</a>.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<ol>
<li>Belgium White</li>
<li>Black Hawk Stout</li>
<li>Pointer Brown Ale</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Belgium White</li>
<li>Pointer Brown Ale</li>
<li>Black Hawk Stout</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Peach Tree IPA</li>
<li>The Wife: Peach Tree IPA</li>
</ul>


<p>In all fairness, the <a href="http://www.peacetreebrewing.com/">Peach Tree</a> IPA was not brewed at Court Avenue and was a stand-in for their Honest Lawyer IPA of which they had ran out (curses!). This beer was earthy on the hops and, in our opinion, had too much bitterness to balance out making this our least favorite beer.</p>

<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The available beers provided a wide range of tastes so everyone in your party should find something they can enjoy. For example, I overheard a couple sitting at a table next to us say <em>&ldquo;I don&rsquo;t like beer, but this is good!&rdquo;</em> about the Two Rivers Light. While the beer was good, I have to admit the food was amazing and stole the show during our visit. I may venture to say Court Avenue has the best food of any restaurant-brewery I have ever visited. I would recommend Court Avenue to anyone passing through Des Moines; the brewery has obtained a permanent spot on our &ldquo;To Visit&rdquo; list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
