<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Placebo Effect | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/placebo-effect/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-02T17:48:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Samuel Adams - Merry Mischief]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/07/07/samuel-adams-merry-mischief/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/07/07/samuel-adams-merry-mischief</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/07/merry-mischief/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > This rich dark gingerbread stout entices with the aromas of the holidays.  The flavor of gingerbread comes alive, beginning with the smooth sweetness and heartiness of dark roasted malts and a touch of wheat.  But it&rsquo;s the intensity and spices of cinnamon, clove, nutmeg, &amp; ginger that add a wicked kick for a jolly playful brew full of merry mischief.</p>

<ul>
<li>Batch Number: 1</li>
<li>Hops:

<ul>
<li>East Kent Goldings</li>
<li>Fuggles</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Malts:

<ul>
<li>Samuel Adams two row pale malt blend</li>
<li>Wheat</li>
<li>Special B</li>
<li>Paul&rsquo;s Roasted Barley</li>
<li>Flaked Oats</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Cinnamon</li>
<li>Clove</li>
<li>Nutmeg</li>
<li>Ginger</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Samuel Adams ale yeast</li>
<li>Color: 200 SRM</li>
<li>ABV: 9.0%</li>
<li>IBUs: 25</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://www.samueladams.com/craft-beers/merry-mischief">Brewer&rsquo;s Tasting Notes</a></h3>

<p>While no gingerbread went into this beer, the sweet roastiness with hints of cocoa and a slight nuttiness from the dark malts provide a similar comparison to gingerbread. A blend of nutmeg, cinnamon, cloves, and ginger were used to create a layer of complexity and lingering heat.</p>

<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Everything about this beer from description, the ingredients, the name, even the label screams Christmas/Winter Specialty Spiced Beer (21B) so I will use this style as a benchmark for my tasting. The inclusion of flaked oats and low IBUs has me guessing the base style is an Oatmeal Stout (13C).</p>

<ul>
<li>Aroma &ndash; A bold spice nose which will hopefully remind me of gingerbread cookies with the help of roasted grain aromas. I would guess the hops were used primarily for bittering and any hop aroma will be absent.</li>
<li>Appearance &ndash; If the reported IBU is correct, I would expect quite a dark, black beer impossible to see through with a thick, creamy, tan/brown-colored head.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The spices and higher alcohol content should contribute a warm, complex flavor set on top of a solid oats and roasted dark grain base balanced by a moderate bitterness from the hops.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Very black with a dark, tan head which was quite thick on the first poor. Opaque to the point of no visible light through the glass.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Clove and spices dominate the aroma, whether you&rsquo;re trying to smell the beer or not; no hop aroma.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The spices of the aroma come through first, followed by roasted grains and an alcohol warmth. Carbonation was a bit higher than I expected from a stout but works wells with the warmth of the alcohol.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Outstanding (41 / 45)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (42 / 45)</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): Excellent (34 / 45)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected it which deserves a perfect score. The reported SRM is more believable after you&rsquo;ve seen this beer first hand.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Dark Brown</li>
<li>Creamy Head</li>
<li>Defined Legs</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Black</li>
<li>Tan, Medium Head Size, Medium-Low Head Retention</li>
<li>Opaque</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 11 / 12</h4>

<p>Spices, particularly cloves, dominate the aroma and in my opinion overpower any grains that may have been present. Besides the lack of roasted grain notes this what I expected.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 11 / 12

<ul>
<li>Spiced Smell with Cookie Bread</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 9 / 12

<ul>
<li>Bready, Medium-High Malt</li>
<li>Piney</li>
<li>Spice</li>
<li>Smells Similar to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wassail">Wassail</a></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 18 / 20</h4>

<p>Spices, check. Alcohol warmth, check. Roasted grains, um&hellip;maybe. Just short of perfect, the overpowering spices have masked any significant grain flavors I hoped to find but not in a bad way, hence the high but not perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 18 / 20

<ul>
<li>Smooth</li>
<li>Creamy</li>
<li>Spiced</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 15 / 20

<ul>
<li>Toasty</li>
<li>Piney, Spicy</li>
<li>Banana</li>
<li>Spice</li>
<li>Malty Balance</li>
<li>Tastes Similar to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wassail">Wassail</a></li>
<li>For something with this much flavor, it should have been heavier</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 9 / 10</h4>

<p>I would probably only drink one (large) glass of this beer in a night but oh man would I enjoy that one beer. It is important to note that there is a small window of opportunity in which this beer can be fully appreciated and July is not one of those times. However, this beer sets the bar for all Christmas beers to follow.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 10

<ul>
<li>Front-end acidic but balances with spices</li>
<li>I really like it; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Adam (Placebo Effect): 7 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would drink a pint of this beer, however I wouldn&rsquo;t fathom drinking this beer in a non-holiday context</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
