<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sierra Nevada | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/sierra-nevada/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-02T17:48:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of Boulevard / Sierra Nevada - Terra Incognita]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/boulevard-sierra-nevada-terra-incognita/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/09/08/boulevard-sierra-nevada-terra-incognita</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/09/terra-incognita/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > First brewed in 2012 for SAVOR attendees, <a href="http://terraincognitabeer.com/">Terra Incognita</a> is a collaboration between the Sierra Nevada and Boulevard breweries which was released commercially in 2013. Terra Incognita is a blend of three different aging processes:</p>

<ul>
<li>Terra Incognita aged in Templeton Rye barrels (30%)</li>
<li>Terra Incognita aged in a 2,000-gallon foudre (45%)</li>
<li>Fresh Terra Incognita dry-hopped with East Kent Golding (25%)</li>
</ul>


<p>This blending creates a beer aimed at showcasing some predominant oak characteristics with a subtle hint of earthy hops and which celebrates the unique terroir of the two brewery locations. Then just prior to bottling a dose of the wild yeast Brettanomyces is added and the beer is aged for over three months.</p>

<ul>
<li>Color &ndash; 92.5 EBC / 47 SRM</li>
<li>Bitterness &ndash; 38.5 IBU</li>
<li>Original Gravity &ndash; 16.9 Plato / 1.069 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Terminal Gravity &ndash; 2.10 (after BC) Plato / 1.008 Specific Gravity</li>
<li>Alcohol (ABV) &ndash; 8.5%</li>
<li>CO2 &ndash; Bottles &ndash; 6 g/L</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>I did not have much to work with so this is nothing but guesswork. The vital statistics match that of a stout (category 13) with the ABV making my best approximation as an imperial stout.</p>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Dark in color, almost black with a rich head to match.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Mild earthy hop flavors mixed with some oak notes from the barrel aging.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Earthy and spicy flavors from the hops with an rich oak back-end balanced by the warmth of the alcohol. Because the Brettanomyces is added late in the process I don&rsquo;t expect it to be a dominant flavor but rather something subtle in the background.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Huge tan colored head which was rock-solid and seemed to last <em>forever</em>. Beer was deep copper with good clarity.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Strong earthy hop aroma with a touch of rye spiciness and lactic sourness.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; The rye and oak flavors blend well on the front of the taste. Some sweetness balanced with a dry bittering on the finish.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; Medium carbonation despite the huge head (which annoying kept getting on my nose). Dry finish.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Very Good (33 / 50)</h3>

<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/09/terra-incognita/outside-closeup.jpg" width="350" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" ></p>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Excellent (37 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 2 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: High Size, High Retention, Frothy Texture, Tan Color</li>
<li>Brown/Black color</li>
<li>Lace</li>
<li>Too much head</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 10 / 12</h4>

<p>While the hops flavors were present in the aroma I was missing the oak notes.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Caramel, Roasty, Medium-High Malt</li>
<li>Earthy, Medium Hops</li>
<li>Low-Medium Sweetness</li>
<li>Bittersweet oak background smell</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 10 / 20</h4>

<p>Why is the hop gone? Strangely, despite the bold hop aroma little to none of the earthy hop flavors which dominated the aroma remain.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 17 / 20

<ul>
<li>Rich, Toasty, Roasty, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Earthy, Spicy, Medium Hops</li>
<li>Low Sweetness</li>
<li>Low Acidic Back-end</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>Unfortunately, the Hulk Hogan head got in the way of drinking this beer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Medium-High Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Medium Warmth</li>
<li>Low Creaminess</li>
<li>Medium, Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>This beer would be nice to have once in a while but not on a regular basis. I would be more willing to drink one on a crisp Autumn day as opposed to a hot Summer afternoon. Even then I would probably only drink one glass.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 3 / 10

<ul>
<li>High Stylistic Accuracy</li>
<li>High Technical Merit</li>
<li>Low Intangibles</li>
<li>I would finish this sample</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
