<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Woodchuck | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/woodchuck/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-05T11:34:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pumpkin Beer Showdown: Round 4]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r4/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-21T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/10/21/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s an Autumn miracle! Just when I had given up hope, these latecomers had shown up to join the showdown. Even after tasting over a dozen different pumpkin beers I&rsquo;m still excited to see how this batch turns out.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/10/pumpkin-beer-showdown/round-4.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Round 4 Beers">
Which brewery&rsquo;s late-to-the-party beverage will emerge from Round 4 victorious? Let&rsquo;s find out.</p>

<!-- More -->


<h3><a href="http://rogue.com/beers/chatoe-pumpkin.php">Rogue Farms &ndash; Pumpkin Patch Ale</a></h3>

<p><em><small>The newest addition to the Chatoe Rogue series is Pumpkin Patch Ale, a beer made using fresh pumpkins grown in a patch that borders Rogue&rsquo;s 42 acre hop yard. The pumpkins are picked, loaded into Rogue&rsquo;s farm truck, driven immediately 77 miles to our brewery in Newport, quickly roasted, and pitched into the brew kettle to create a batch of Pumpkin Patch Ale.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>14 PLATO</li>
<li>25 Lovibond</li>
<li>75 AA</li>
<li>IBU: 25</li>
<li>Hops: Rogue Micro Hopyard Rebel Hops</li>
<li>Malts: Great Western 2-Row, Carawheat, Weyermann Carafe Malts</li>
<li>Yeast: Pacman Yeast</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: Rogue Farms Pumpkins, Ginger, Cloves, Vanilla bean, Cinnamon, Cardamom, Nutmeg</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Mild nutmeg aroma. Complex flavors of allspice and clove make this beer difficult to decipher but in a good way. However, there is a bit too much astringency on the back-end (maybe the orange peel?) which overstays its welcome. Unfortunately, the extra bitterness at the end kept this from being one of my favorites.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Sweet pumpkin nose and a soft spice smell. Smooth malt front flowing easily into spice bitterness. Slight lingering flavor of cinnamon and cloves.</p>

<h3><a href="http://mothersbrewing.com/craft-beers/our-beers/mr-pumpkin/">Mother&rsquo;s &ndash; Mr. Pumpkin</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Our first release from Mother&rsquo;s Cupboard, Mr. Pumpkin is a medium bodied, copper color ale. With just the right blend of 2 Row, Caramel, and Crystal malts, pumpkin and spices, Mother&rsquo;s has created one yummy pint of love. Perfect after dinner in lieu of dessert, or for a night out on the town. Enjoy out doors on cool fall nights, or when slaving over the stove making that holiday dinner for the in-laws. If pie can be for breakfast, well it certainly should work as beer.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>ABV: 5.0%</li>
<li>IBU: 10</li>
<li>Color: Copper colored medium to medium-light bodied</li>
<li>Malts: Pale ale, Crystal 35</li>
<li>Hops: Very little hops</li>
<li>Special Ingredients: touch of Roast pumpkin before addition for some carmelization and pie spice in kettle and post fermentation</li>
</ul>


<h4>Brew Puppy: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Good spice nose of ginger and allspice. Dry finish and pleasant amount of allspice/cinnamon/nutmeg which balances with the malts. Not quite enough body in this beer which lost it points for me.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Cinnamon and allspice nose. Lingering cinnamon front-end flavor with mild to modest front-end bitterness and only a small malt flavor.</p>

<h3><a href="http://www.woodchuck.com/cider/private-reserves.html">Woodchuck &ndash; Pumpkin Cider</a></h3>

<p><em><small>Every once in a while you know you stumble upon something glorious. That something just so happens to be our Private Reserve Pumpkin. We have combined our signature taste with a refreshing pumpkin finish. Limited to just two and half hours on the production line this is a true connoisseur&rsquo;s cider.</small></em></p>

<h4>Brew Puppy: 2 / 10</h4>

<p>Aroma is an icepick of sweetness straight into the sinuses. The combination of cider and spices tastes like cheap flavoured gum. Couldn&rsquo;t bring myself to take more than one drink so that&rsquo;s all the analysis I&rsquo;ll be providing.</p>

<h4>The Wife: 6 / 10</h4>

<p>Strong apple cider nose. Beautiful dark color. Bubble gum sweet, candy apple flavor with no bitterness. Not sure where the pumpkin flavor fits in.</p>

<h2>Results</h2>

<ol>
<li><div class="badge">6</div> Rogue Farms &ndash; Pumpkin Patch Ale</li>
<li><div class="badge">6</div> Mother&rsquo;s &ndash; Mr. Pumpkin</li>
<li><div class="badge">4</div> Woodchuck &ndash; Pumpkin Cider</li>
</ol>


<p>In Case you Missed it:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="/blog/2013/09/23/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r1/">Round 1</a></li>
<li><a href="/blog/2013/09/30/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r2/">Round 2</a></li>
<li><a href="/blog/2013/10/07/pumpkin-beer-showdown-r3/">Round 3</a></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
