<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Brooklyn Brewery | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/brooklyn-brewery/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-26T20:41:37-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tasting of New York Limited - Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, Saranac Brewery]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/08/27/new-york-limited-brooklyn-ommegang-saranac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/outside.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Outside Facing North&rdquo; &ldquo;Picture of bottle and beer in glass outside with northern light&rdquo;" > Brewed and bottled at Brooklyn Brewery, Brookly, NY for SAVOR 2013 NYC this beer is a one-of-a-kind collaboration of Brooklyn Brewery, Brewery Ommegang, and Saranac Brewery. With a focus on local New York ingredients, these brewers combined matled barley, raw wheat, yeast, hops, spices, and ideas grown in New York State to bring you a unique take on wheat beer. This white lager, 100% re-fermented in this bottle, is a collaborative nod to the glorious past and brilliant future of New York State brewing. This special release was presented as an exit gift to SAVOR attendees in a 750 ml corked and caged bottle.</p>

<ul>
<li>Special Ingredients:

<ul>
<li>Coriander</li>
<li>Orange Peel</li>
<li>Lemon Verbena</li>
<li>Wildflower Honey</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Yeast: Lager</li>
<li>ABV: 8.5%</li>
<li>IBU: 16.5 IBU</li>
</ul>


<!-- More -->


<h3>What I Expected</h3>

<p>Because this beer is unique, some research was involved in order to have any idea what to expect. My primary sources of information were the label on the bottle, the <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/news/savor-2013-collaboration-beer/">Media Spot</a>, and the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.SAVORCollaborationBeer.mp3">SAVOR 2013 Salon recording: SAVOR Collaboration Beer</a>. I also took into consideration the stylistic inspiration for this beer, the Witbier(16A).</p>

<ul>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Moderate sweetness with light, grainy, spicy wheat aromatics, often with a bit of tartness. Dominate coriander with a mix of complex herbal and floral aromas in the background. Moderate zesty, citrusy orangey fruitiness.</li>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Pale straw to light gold in color. Thick light-colored head with good retention from the wheat.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Pleasant sweetness with a honey character and a zesty, orange-citrusy fruitiness. The orange peel and lemon verbena should give this beer a different sort of bitterness alongside the low IBU value to help balance. The honey, coriander, and other herbs should give the beer a somewhat complex floral taste in the absence of a Belgian yeast strain. Coriander levels were higher than expected due to either 1) no masking esters or 2) less vigorous lager fermentation left more particulates to contribute to the flavor. Dry, with a low-amount of residual sugars and clean malt taste makes this beer smooth with the high alcohol levels going largely unnoticed. The use of a lager yeast puts the ingredients used to the main stage when it comes to flavor.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Tasting Notes</h3>

<ul>
<li>Appearance &ndash; Golden straw colored with a touch of haze but otherwise clear. White, bubbly head can be quite tall and the retention is excellent considering its low density.</li>
<li>Aroma &ndash; Coriander and orange dominates the aroma with a touch of floral notes. Spicy wheat characteristics are there if you&rsquo;re really looking for them. The CO2 tickles my nose.</li>
<li>Mouthfeel &ndash; High carbonation levels makes for a bubbly but unexpectedly creamy texture. I had to pour this beer quickly because after opening the gas release caused the beer to escape the bottle much like a champagne.</li>
<li>Flavor &ndash; Smooth and creamy while still light and refreshing. The orange bitterness lingers a bit on the tongue. Clean lager profile with a solid wheat backdrop for the spices. I think I was picking up on the honey flavors but without knowing the taste profiles of New York honey it is difficult to be certain.</li>
</ul>


<h3>Conclusion: Outstanding (45 / 50)</h3>

<p><strong>Guest Tasters:</strong></p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: Outstanding (46 / 50)</li>
</ul>


<h4>Appearance: 3 / 3</h4>

<p>The color and head of this beer was exactly what I expected which deserves a perfect score.</p>

<ul>
<li>Second Opinion &ndash; The Wife: 3 / 3

<ul>
<li>Head: Smooth Texture, Medium-High Size, High Retention, White Color</li>
<li>Low Clarity</li>
<li>Yellow Color</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Aroma: 9 / 12</h4>

<p>Any traces of sweetness or spicy wheat aromatics were masked by the coriander and other spices. Hopefully these will come through more once the beer has had some time to age.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 10 / 12

<ul>
<li>Grainy, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Citrusy, Earthy, Spicy</li>
<li>Fruity</li>
<li>Soft nose with slight coriander smell</li>
<li>Smooth malt/wheat flavor balances with tingling spice aftertaste which lingers on tongue</li>
<li>Missing: Grainy, Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Flavor: 19 / 20</h4>

<p>The floral flavors were the only missing component here. I suspect the overly dominate coriander covered them up.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 19 / 20

<ul>
<li>Low Sweetness, Low Bitterness</li>
<li>Medium Hops, Medium Malt</li>
<li>Slight Toasty, Creamy Malt Flavors</li>
<li>Spicy, Citrusy, Herbal</li>
<li>Even Balance</li>
<li>Missing: Floral</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Mouthfeel: 4 / 5</h4>

<p>The high level of carbonation was a bit much but the beer improved after several minutes of degassing.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 5 / 5

<ul>
<li>Low Body</li>
<li>Medium Carbonation</li>
<li>Dry Finish</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Overall Impression: 10 / 10</h4>

<p>A wonderful beer for drinking on a hot summer day (which we did), this easy to drink beer left me wishing I could have a keg of it every summer.</p>

<ul>
<li>The Wife: 9 / 10

<ul>
<li>I would pay money for this beer; please send me the recipe!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/08/new-york-limited/inside.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Picture of unopened bottle and SAVOR glasses"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Brooklyn Brewery - Brooklyn, New York]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/16/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first I&rsquo;d heard about Brooklyn Brewery was from an article in a BYO issue. To be honest, I don&rsquo;t remember much from the article besides the fact they were an older brewery which I wanted to visit. I should probably go back and read that article. Anyway, since I was already in New York City it was a perfect opportunity for a visit. Let me tell you, I&rsquo;m glad that I did.</p>

<p>Brooklyn has a distinctly different feel than Manhattan island. When you emerge from the subway, you&rsquo;re immediately surrounded with by jobs, homes, and real people (not tourists). While I only experienced a few blocks of Brooklyn, it was enough to make an impression.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/factory.jpg" alt="Factory Roots">
            <div class="caption"><small>The brewery's former life as a factory shows on the outside but the inside is 100% brewery.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/outside.jpg" alt="Building">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/entrance.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Brewery Entrance">
        <div class="caption"><small>Standing guard just inside the main doors are four large fermentation vessels.</small></div>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Standing in the brewery entrance, to your right you&rsquo;ll catch a glimpse of the inner workings of the brewery. To your left is the tempting hubbub of the tap room. We went left.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Brooklyn Brewery</strong><br>
79 N 11th Street<br>
Brooklyn, New York 11249<br>
<a href="http://brooklynbrewery.com/">www.brooklynbrewery.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Perks</h3>

<ul>
<li>10% off Merchandise &amp; Cases</li>
<li>1 Free Beer during Happy Hour &amp; Tours (Friday &amp; Saturday)</li>
</ul>


<h2>Tap Room</h2>

<p>The tap room was the large generic room you would expect to see from a warehouse. While the room was filled with wooden tables and benches, finding an open seat was a challenge; the demand for this brewery has definitely outgrown its supply. Whenever a your ends, the line to the tokens to purchase tokens becomes a ten minute wait and the line for the beer becomes a fifteen to twenty minute wait. I would recommend grabbing two beers per person when you finally reach the bartenders. Speaking of bartenders, they all wear the Brooklyn Brewery shirts available for sale which is an excellent way to sneak a preview before you buy. Of course, I could not resist picking up another <a href="http://store.brooklynbrewery.com/brewhouse-t-shirt-180">shirt</a> for my collection.
<img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/tap-room.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tap Room">
Even though the wait was long the beer was worth it. The ones we tried were a bit hoppy for The Wife which means they were right up my alley. The price of beer (five tokens for $20) is worth mentioning. One token will get you most beers with a few speciality beer costing two tokens. This is a killer price for any bar, let alone one in New York City which explains why the place was <em>packed</em> even on a Sunday.</p>

<h2>Tour</h2>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <p>The free tour starts in the main entryway with nowhere near enough seats for the large crowd gathered; no sign-up or reservations is required. We non-intentionally placed ourselves at the front of the tour, but unfortunately the tour consisted of a single room so it didn't make much of a difference. While the information given by the presenter was interesting and well delivered, I felt a bit disappointed at not seeing more of the brewery. Granted the room was quite large and packed with enough equipment to glimpse all aspects of the brewing process, it still felt like just a glimpse. That said, I do not regret going on the tour one bit or even a byte (hahaha, computer pun!) and I definitely recommend you do it at least once. Be sure to bring a beer with you on the tour though, as you'll be standing in one place for a while.</p>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-6">
        <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/presenter-bartender.jpg" class="img-responsive" alt="Tour Guide">
    </div>
</div>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>The drink prices alone make the Brooklyn Brewery difficult to pass up; throw in the fact that the beer is <em>good</em> and it becomes a required stop. While there was music always playing it was not overly loud or obnoxious as you would find in most bars or clubs. I envy the group who snagged a large table early and brought a board game (Settlers of Catan I believe) for the evening. Others brought in pizza which is the encouraged food of choice for the tap room. Unfortunately I did not have a chance to try all the beers which means the I will definitely be returning to visit the Brooklyn Brewery the next time I&rsquo;m in New York City. Maybe I&rsquo;ll see you there next time.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/wall-logo.jpg" alt="Wall Logo">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/terminator.jpg" alt="Terminator">
            <div class="caption"><small>Under no circumstances should you visit this brewery if you are the future savior of mankind from intelligent killer robots.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/sword.jpg" alt="Random Sword">
            <div class="caption"><small>Unfortunately, I did not witness any sword-fighting. Maybe next time?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/scorcher-1363.jpg" alt="Scorcher 1363">
            <div class="caption"><small>One of the beers on tap during our visit.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/log.jpg" alt="Log">
            <div class="caption"><small>Bonus points if you can figure out what they were brewing.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/grain-tubes.jpg" alt="Grain Tubes">
            <div class="caption"><small>Those tubes carry grain, not liquids.</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/chandelier.jpg" alt="Chandelier">
            <div class="caption"><small>Did I mention this brewery was quite the classy establishment?</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/casks.jpg" alt="Casks">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-3.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/brewery-4.jpg" alt="Random Brewery Picture">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/brooklyn-brewery-brooklyn-new-york/bottler.jpg" alt="Bottler">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
