<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Events | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-20T19:40:27-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SAVOR: An American Craft Beer & Food Experience]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/savor-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2013/06/15/savor-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Held in Washington D.C. for the last five years, <a href="http://www.savorcraftbeer.com/">SAVOR</a> took place this year at the Altman Building and adjoining Metropolitan Pavilion in Manhattan, New York. Attendees enjoy a reception-style sampling of sweet and savoury appetizers and craft beers from over seventy small and independent craft breweries.</p>

<p>If I had to describe my SAVOR experience in one word it would be <em>overwhelming</em>. I say this in the best possible way but I was entirely unprepared for the event. Not that I did not plan ahead (I remembered to wear pants and everything!) and this wasn&rsquo;t the first beer/wine tasting events I had attended. Maybe it was just the product of a Midwesterner&rsquo;s first time in the Big Apple but this event was broad in a scope to a degree I had not imagined.</p>

<p>SAVOR offers the opportunity to participate in directed tasting salons featuring stars from the craft beer and food scene. Very few events offer the opportunity to have a one-on-one conversation with the rock stars of the craft beer world. My frantic Ticketmaster antics during the pre-sale managed to secure myself tickets to one of the salon&rsquo;s:</p>

<p><strong>Apocalypse Now and Again (and Again)</strong></p>

<blockquote><p>If the world were coming to end, what beer would you brew? In 2012, <a href="http://www.elysianbrewing.com">Elysian Brewing Company</a> answered that question with their 12 Beers of the Apocalypse series. While the world may not have come to an end, the Apocalypse series did, leaving behind a dozen unique beers, each brewed with unusual ingredients. Join Elysian founder Dick Cantwell as he shares samples of four beers from the series and talks about the trials and tribulations of the project.</p></blockquote>

<p>Only a small increase in the ticket price, the private tasting was money well spent. If the ticket price weren&rsquo;t so steep I would probably go both days just to have the opportunity to attend two salons. Read on for a look into our SAVOR experience.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>By the time we arrived to the event, the line had wrapped around the Altman Building twice. Some store owners were not pleased about us being there as we were so they erected a &ldquo;sturdy barricade&rdquo; to keep the unruly beer enthusiasts in check. During our wait I almost got a picture of Sam Calagione walking by but wasn&rsquo;t fast enough on the draw with the camera.</p>

<p>Each brewery had two beers for tasting, each paired with a small food dish. These dishes were not quite unique to each brewery so we started having repeats near the end of the night. However, the beers kept changing so we we&rsquo;re too concerned (that&rsquo;s why we were there after all) and any food was appreciated after missing dinner.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-1.jpg" alt="Line Outside">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/line-2.jpg" alt="Line Outside">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/barricade.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/barricade.jpg" alt="Sturdy Barricade">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/inside.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/inside.jpg" alt="Just Inside the Entrance">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/floor-maps.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/floor-maps.jpg" alt="Floor Maps">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/linden-street.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/linden-street.jpg" alt="Linden Street Brewer">
            <div class="caption"><small>Linden Street Brewer</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Not all beer servers at the event were on the same playing field. Some were just hired help, there to serve the beer with no real knowledge of the beer or the brewery employing them. On the other hand, some servers intimately knew the beers they were serving and, more importantly, were passionate about them. There people were a real joy to talk to about the beers we were tasting and made the encounter with that brewery extra special.</p>

<p>If I had to choose one beer which stood out about the rest it was Biere de Tartine by Linden Street Brewery. Fermented with a trained sourdough yeast, this beer had a definitive bread taste and the result was amazing.</p>

<p>The highlight of the event for me was the tasting salon <em>Apocalypse Now and Again (and Again)</em>. The experience was a wonderfully intimate telling of Dick Cantwell&rsquo;s journey through Elysian Brewing&rsquo;s Twelve Beers of the Apocalypse project and what it means to use speciality ingredients on a commercial level. We were able to taste a few of the beer from that project with added commentary from the brewer. I can still taste the chocolate chili beer as I write this. Rather than attempt to summarize the experience in a watered-down paragraph, I recommend you instead listen to the <a href="http://www.craftbeerradio.com/cbr-savor/SAVOR.2013.061513.ApocalypseNowAgainAgain.mp3">actual thing</a>. Bonus: At the 48 minute 13 second mark, I&rsquo;m the one who &ldquo;stumps&rdquo; Dick Cantwell with a question.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/dick-cantwell.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/dick-cantwell.jpg" alt="Dick Cantwell">
            <div class="caption"><small>Elysian's Dick Cantwell</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-1.jpg" alt="Elysian Front">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/elysian-2.jpg" alt="Elysian Back">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-3">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/salon.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/salon.jpg" alt="Salon">
            <div class="caption"><small>Salon</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<p>Three hours had gone by before we knew it and sadly it was time to leave. On the way each person received a bottle of the New York Limited collaboration beer from Brooklyn, Ommegang and Saranac. I&rsquo;ll post tasting notes after I get back and settled in.</p>

<p>Things to be aware of at future events:</p>

<ul>
<li>Make Time for Dinner &ndash; There was construction on our direct subway line so we didn&rsquo;t have time to eat dinner. Even though the beer had food pairings, not eating was rough, especially toward the end of the night.</li>
<li>Have a Game Plan &ndash; Even if you do not attend a Salon, there is no way to taste all of the beers available in only three hours. Look over the list of attending breweries beforehand and prioritize which ones you would like to see. Be aware there can be a line at some of the sponsoring breweries.</li>
</ul>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle-devil-horns.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle-devil-horns.jpg" alt="Devil Horns">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/supporters-circle.jpg" alt="Supporters Circle">
            <div class="caption"><small>Supporter's Circle</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/boulevard.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2013/06/savor/boulevard.jpg" alt="Boulevard Booth">
            <div class="caption"><small>Boulevard's Booth</small></div>
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
