<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Confluence Brewing Company | BREW PUPPY dot NET]]></title>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/categories/confluence-brewing-company/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-13T20:25:21-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luke Dodge]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Confluence Brewing Company - Des Moines, Iowa]]></title>
    <link href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://brewpuppy.github.io/blog/2014/02/24/confluence-brewing-company-des-moines-iowa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="right" src="/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/good-things.jpg" width="300" title="&ldquo;Where Good Things Come Together&rdquo; &ldquo;Local Art&rdquo;" >
My schedule was terrible for my trip through Des Moines this year and the decision to visit Confluence was based more off their late tap room hours than anything else. Spoiler: It wasn&rsquo;t a bad decision.</p>

<p>Late in the evening we were driving through what appeared to be an industrial district filled with dark warehouses and wondering if our GPS was purposefully leading us to our doom. Just as we had given up hope, we round the bend and were greeted with the warm and bright Confluence store front. It was cold, late and being desperately in need of a beer we hustled inside.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Address</h3>

<p><strong>Confluence Brewing Company</strong><br>
1235 Thomas Beck Rd., Suite A<br>
Des Moines, IA 50315<br>
<a href="http://confluencebrewing.com/">www.confluencebrewing.com</a></p>

<h3>AHA Member Deals</h3>

<ul>
<li>$0.50 Off on Regular Pints</li>
</ul>


<h2>Beers</h2>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> I am loath to post such a short write-up on this brewery&rsquo;s beers because they deserve better but I enjoyed the brewery so much I had the share the experience regardless. You&rsquo;ve been warned: these tasting notes are sub-standard.</p>

<h3>Des Moines IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>Mix of medium body, lighter color and plenty of malt flavor to balance the massive hop impact. Citrusy and piney hops from the Pacific Northwest offset the robust malt flavor of the two-row barley and medium crystal malts.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>75 IBU</li>
<li>7.1% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>High bitterness which does not linger and tastes of Centennial. The Wife: more hop smell than flavor; do not like.</p>

<h3>Capital Gold Golden Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Brewed with time-honored German brewing methods, its slightly sweet, bready, malty flavor is balanced perfectly by traditional German noble hops with medium-low hop bitterness. Domestic and imported German two-row barley malt and noble German hops as well as traditional lager yeast. Undergoes a lagering period of three to four weeks after initial fermentation.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>4.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Grainy nose but standard lager taste. The Wife: clean, light flavor reminiscent of most light beers.</p>

<h3>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>A refreshing, blonde ale, it features a base of two row American barley malt along with a large portion of wheat malt, a small dose of rye malt and un-malted oats, corn and wheat. Lightly hopped with English East Kent Goldings hops chosen for their subtle, earthy qualities and finished with Czech Saaz hops for their sweet, floral essence to create a beer that&rsquo;s light in body and color, with a velvety texture and an aroma as sweet as a freshly cut field of hay.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>21 IBU</li>
<li>5.6%</li>
</ul>


<p>Quite the complex grain flavor; there is a lot going on in this beer. The Wife: very interesting, complex light flavor.</p>

<h3>Thomas Beck Black IPA</h3>

<p><em><small>The dark color comes from black wheat, which is combined with two-row base malt and a good portion of caramel malt and some flaked rye to add a subtle dry, spiciness. We used a special blend of hops, including Nelson Sauvin from Australia, to give it a unique flavor and aroma profile completely distinct from its India Pale Ale cousin, Des Moines IPA.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>58 IBU</li>
<li>6.8% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Lots of citrus on top of roasted malt flavors. The Wife: burned, bitter flavor.</p>

<h3>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</h3>

<p><em><small>Features a massive bill of English Golden Promise, a little Special B and roasted barley for color to condense and create caramelized sugars that will survive the fermentation process. Adding English East Kent Golding balances the sweetness and cool fermenting with Scottish ale yeast.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>22 IBU</li>
<li>6.6% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>One of the more subtle Scotch Ales I&rsquo;ve tasted. A The Wife: smooth malty finish; very good.</p>

<h3>ChewBocka Winter Bock</h3>

<p><em><small>Made with plenty of Munich malt for a rich, chewy, full-body flavor as well as German Spalter Select, German Tettnanger and American Mt. Hood hops to balance out the malty sweetness. There are also some toasty notes as well as a slight hint of chocolate.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>28 IBU</li>
<li>6.2%</li>
</ul>


<p>Some fruity esters liven up this Bock. The Wife: &ldquo;oaty&rdquo; (I think she made this word up) flavor with a dry finish.</p>

<h3>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</h3>

<p><em><small>Lighter, crisper beer that still has some hop bite to it. Pilsen, Vienna and Caramel 10L malts create a lightly sweet malt profile that is beautifully balanced with Amarillo and Crystal hops.  The light citrus and subtle grass flavors from the hops remind us of the eagerly awaited spring.</small></em></p>

<ul>
<li>31 IBU</li>
<li>4.86% ABV</li>
</ul>


<p>Light, clean, and hoppy. I could drink gallons of this beer in the summer. The Wife: hoppy light beer; do not like.</p>

<h3>Wee Lassie Scottish Session Ale</h3>

<ul>
<li>25 IBU</li>
<li>4.8%</li>
</ul>


<p>Very light bodied. The Wife: smooth light ale flavor with a nice finish.</p>

<h2>Favorites</h2>

<p>While I quite enjoyed both IPAs offered, the ChewBocka Winter Bock and Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale beat them out but only because they were a bit more unique and stood out among the crowd.</p>

<ol>
<li>Fresh Start Hoppy Pale Lager</li>
<li>ChewBocka Winter Bock</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
</ol>


<h3>The Wife</h3>

<ol>
<li>Gray&rsquo;s Lake Nessie Scottish Ale</li>
<li>Farmer John&rsquo;s Multi-Grain Ale</li>
<li>Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
</ol>


<h3>Least Favorite</h3>

<ul>
<li>Luke: Capital Gold Golden Lager</li>
<li>The Wife: Thomas Beck Black IPA</li>
</ul>


<h2>Conclusion</h2>

<p>This will be short and sweet, just like our visit to Confluence. Because we arrived so late, I didn&rsquo;t have the time I would have wanted to spend. Hell, my notes were whatever I could fit on the back of a flier for local music. The only conclusion I can make is we enjoyed what little time we had and 100% plan on stopping there again the next time we&rsquo;re in Des Moines.</p>

<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-room.jpg" alt="Tap Room">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/tap-board.jpg" alt="Tap Board">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-1.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/brewery-2.jpg" alt="Brewery">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/beer.jpg" alt="Beer">
        </a>
    </div>
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/art.jpg" alt="Art">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>


<div class="row">
    <div class="col-md-4">
        <a href="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" class="thumbnail">
            <img src="http://brewpuppy.github.io/images/blog/2014/02/confluence/casks.jpg" alt="casks">
        </a>
    </div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
